<Version>
  <xmlSource>This XML content was developed by AHRQ's contractor ECRI Institute for the National Quality Measures Clearinghouse (NQMC).</xmlSource>
  <Section SecID="560" OrdBy="10" Name="General">
    <Field FieldID="11" OrdBy="20" ID="561" Name="Title" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_title&quot;&gt;Maternal and newborn care: proportion of women who delivered at term and had group B streptococcus (GBS) screening at 35 to 37 weeks' gestation.&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="1" OrdBy="30" ID="562" Name="Source(s)" Type="citation">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Maternal newborn dashboard - key performance indicator criterion reference guide, version 1.3. Ontario (Canada): Better Outcomes Registry and Network (BORN) Ontario; 2014 Jul 2. 12 p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="563" OrdBy="40" Name="Measure Domain">
    <Field FieldID="3025" OrdBy="50" ID="564" Name="Primary Measure Domain" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Clinical Quality Measures: Process" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3026" OrdBy="60" ID="565" Name="Secondary Measure Domain" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Does not apply to this measure" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="566" OrdBy="70" Name="Brief Abstract">
    <Field FieldID="34" OrdBy="80" ID="567" Name="Description" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This measure is used to assess the proportion of women who delivered at term and had group B streptococcus (GBS) screening at 35 to 37 weeks' gestation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="21" OrdBy="90" ID="568" Name="Rationale" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Group B streptococcus (GBS) is a bacterium which commonly infects pregnant women and poses the risk of being transmitted to infants during the perinatal period (Phares et al., 2008). GBS transmission from mother to infant carries serious health risks to the newborn including sepsis, pneumonia, or meningitis (Baker &amp;amp; Edwards, 1995; Davies et al., 2001; Verani et al., 2010). In both Canada and the United States, GBS disease is a leading cause of infant morbidity and mortality (Verani et al., 2010; Darling &amp;amp; Saurette, 2010; Money et al., 2004). &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In Canada, almost one-fifth of pregnant women are colonized with GBS at 36 weeks' gestation (Darling &amp;amp; Saurette, 2010). If left untreated, approximately 50% of babies born to GBS positive mothers become colonized and 1% to 2% of colonized infants develop GBS disease (Darling &amp;amp; Saurette, 2010). Infections occurring within the first week of an infant's life are considered early-onset GBS and are acquired through vertical transmission from a GBS colonized mother to the infant. Infections occurring after the first week of life are considered late-onset and can be acquired through both vertical transmission from the mother to the infant and horizontal transmission from the hospital or community to the infant (Canadian Task Force on Preventive Health Care [CTFPHC], 2002).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When maternal GBS infections are identified prenatally, early-onset GBS disease in the newborn can be prevented by administration of intrapartum antibiotic prophylaxis (IAP) to the mother (CTFPHC, 2002; Verani et al., 2010). The screening method that identifies the greatest number of GBS infected mothers should, therefore, result in the fewest number of infants with early-onset GBS disease. In 1996, the Centre for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) issued recommendations for two screening strategies to prevent perinatal GBS transmission: &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Universal screening&lt;/span&gt;: All pregnant women are screened for GBS infection by culture testing at 35 to 37 weeks' gestation and decisions to administer IAP are based on a positive GBS culture. &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Risk-based screening&lt;/span&gt;: IAP is administered based on risk factors that increase likelihood of early-onset GBS infection (e.g., previous delivery of GBS-infected baby, premature delivery, maternal fever greater than 38&amp;ordm;C, rupture of membranes greater than 18 hours [Verani et al., 2010]). &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A large population-based study conducted in the late 90s found that universal screening identified a greater proportion of women at risk of transmitting GBS to their babies than risk-based screening. Based on this study, CDC's 2002 revised guidelines recommended universal screening exclusively (Verani et al., 2010). Despite these recommendations, the issue of whether to employ a universal vs. risk-based approach to screening remains contentious. While universal screening is recommended in the United States, Canada, and Belgium, it is not currently recommended in the United Kingdom or New Zealand (Colbourn et al., 2007; CTFPHC, 2002; Melin et al., 2004; Campbell et al., 2004). Concerns remain about clinical effectiveness, cost-effectiveness, overuse of antibiotics, and medicalization of labour (Gilbert, 2004; Cromwell et al., 2007).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3500" OrdBy="100" ID="569" Name="Evidence for Rationale" Type="citation">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Baker CJ, Edwards MS. Group B streptococcal infections. In: Remington J, Klein JO, editor(s). Infectious disease of the fetus and newborn infant. 4th ed. Philadelphia (PA): WB Saunders; 1995. p. 980-1054.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Campbell N, Eddy A, Darlow B, Stone P, Grimwood K, New Zealand GBS Consensus Working Party. The prevention of early-onset neonatal group B streptococcus infection: technical report from the New Zealand GBS Consensus Working Party. N Z Med J. 2004 Aug 20;117(1200):U1023. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=15475993&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Canadian Task Force on Preventive Health Care. Prevention of group B streptococcal infection in newborns. Recommendation statement from the Canadian Task Force on Preventive Health Care. Can Fam Physician. 2002 May;48:934-5, 944-6. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=12053638&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Colbourn T, Asseburg C, Bojke L, Philips Z, Claxton K, Ades AE, Gilbert RE. Prenatal screening and treatment strategies to prevent group B streptococcal and other bacterial infections in early infancy: cost-effectiveness and expected value of information analyses. Health Technol Assess. 2007 Aug;11(29):1-226, iii. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=17651659&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Cromwell D, Joffey T, van der Meulen J, Dhillon C, Hughes R, Murphy D. The prevention of early-onset neonatal group B streptococcal disease in UK obstetric units: an audit of reported practice in England, Scotland, Wales and Northern Ireland. London (England): Royal College of Obstetricians and Gynaecologists (RCOG); 2007. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Darling E, Saurette K. Group B streptococcus: prevention and management in labour. Ontario (Canada): Association of Ontario Midwives (AOM); 2010 Jan. 23 p.&amp;nbsp;(Clinical practice guideline; no. 11).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Davies HD, Raj S, Adair C, Robinson J, McGeer A, Alberta GBS Study Group. Population-based active surveillance for neonatal group B streptococcal infections in Alberta, Canada: implications for vaccine formulation. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2001 Sep;20(9):879-84. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=11734768&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Gilbert R. Prenatal screening for group B streptococcal infection: gaps in the evidence. Int J Epidemiol. 2004 Feb;33(1):2-8. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=15075135&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Melin P, Verschraegen G, Mahieu L, Claeys G, Mol PD. Towards a Belgian consensus for prevention of perinatal group B streptococcal disease. Indian J Med Res. 2004 May;119 Suppl:197-200. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=15232194&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Money DM, Dobson S, Canadian Paediatric Society, Infectious Diseases Commitee. The prevention of early-onset neonatal group B streptococcal disease. J Obstet Gynaecol Can. 2004 Sep;26(9):826-40. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=15361281&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Phares CR, Lynfield R, Farley MM, MohleBoetani J, Harrison LH, Petit S, Craig AS, Schaffner W, Zansky SM, Gershman K, Stefonek KR, Albanese BA, Zell ER, Schuchat A, Schrag SJ, Active Bacterial Core Surveillance/Emerging Infections Program Network. Epidemiology of invasive group B streptococcal disease in the United States, 1999-2005. JAMA. 2008 May 7;299(17):2056-65. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=18460666&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Thielman J, Konnyu K, Grimshaw J, Moher D. What is the evidence supporting universal versus risk-based maternal screening to prevent group B streptococcal infection in newborns?. Ottawa (Canada): Ottawa Hospital Research Institute; 2011 Oct. 11 p.&amp;nbsp;(KTA Evidence Summary; no. 14).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Verani JR, McGee L, Schrag SJ, Division of Bacterial Diseases, National Center for Immunization and Respiratory Diseases, Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC). Prevention of perinatal group B streptococcal disease--revised guidelines from CDC, 2010. MMWR Recomm Rep. 2010 Nov 19;59(RR-10):1-36. [264 references] &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=21088663&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3022" OrdBy="110" ID="570" Name="Primary Health Components" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pregnancy; group B &lt;em&gt;Streptococcus&lt;/em&gt; (GBS) screening &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="23" OrdBy="120" ID="571" Name="Denominator Description" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Total number of women who delivered at term (greater than or equal to 37 weeks' gestation) and did not decline group B streptococcus (GBS) screening (see the related &quot;Denominator Inclusions/Exclusions&quot; field)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="24" OrdBy="130" ID="572" Name="Numerator Description" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Number of women who delivered at term and had group B streptococcus (GBS) screening at 35 to 37 weeks' gestation (see the related &quot;Numerator Inclusions/Exclusions&quot; field)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="573" OrdBy="140" Name="Evidence Supporting the Measure">
    <Field FieldID="3027" OrdBy="150" ID="574" Name="Type of Evidence Supporting the Criterion of Quality for the Measure" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="A clinical practice guideline or other peer-reviewed synthesis of the clinical research evidence" />
      <FieldValue Value="A formal consensus procedure, involving experts in relevant clinical, methodological,  public health and organizational sciences" />
      <FieldValue Value="A systematic review of the clinical research literature (e.g., Cochrane Review)" />
      <FieldValue Value="One or more research studies published in a National Library of Medicine (NLM) indexed, peer-reviewed journal" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3501" OrdBy="160" ID="575" Name="Additional Information Supporting Need for the Measure" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Group B streptococcus (GBS) disease is a leading cause of infant mortality in Canada. Screening pregnant women for GBS colonization has been shown to greatly reduce early-onset GBS disease in infants. Screening can be done by universal culture testing or by assessing maternal risk factors. &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Universal, culture-based GBS screening of women at 35 to 37 weeks' gestation is recommended as best practice by a range of North American bodies, including the Canadian Task Force on Preventive Health Care, Society of Obstetrician and Gynaecologists of Canada, Association of Ontario Midwives, British Columbia Reproductive Care Program, Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, Institute for Clinical Systems Improvement, American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists, American Academy of Pediatrics, American College of Nurse-Midwives, American Academy of Family Physicians, and American Society for Microbiology. &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;In contrast, risk-based GBS screening is recommended by several non-North American agencies including the National Institute for Health and Care Excellence, Royal College of Obstetricians and Gynaecologists, New Zealand GBS Consensus Working Party, and New Zealand College of Midwives. &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;According to a 2007 health technology assessment, until a GBS vaccine is developed, universal, culture-based GBS screening followed by intrapartum antibiotic prophylaxis for GBS positive women is considered to be the most cost effective strategy for women at low risk of GBS infection (i.e., membrane rupture greater than 18 hours or no risk factors). &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;While many guidelines have made recommendations on GBS screening, there is a dearth of scientific evidence on this subject (e.g., randomized controlled trials, systematic reviews). As of 2010, there were no randomized controlled trials comparing the two strategies. &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Refer to &lt;em&gt;What is Known About Universal versus Risk-based Maternal Screening to Prevent Group B Streptococcal Infection in Newborns?&lt;/em&gt; for a summary of the evidence on the recommended prenatal screening strategy for group B streptococcal infection. The report's intention is to support efforts that seek to increase rates of universal GBS screening among pregnant women across Ontario.&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3502" OrdBy="170" ID="576" Name="Evidence for Additional Information Supporting Need for the Measure" Type="citation">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Thielman J, Konnyu K, Grimshaw J, Moher D. What is the evidence supporting universal versus risk-based maternal screening to prevent group B streptococcal infection in newborns?. Ottawa (Canada): Ottawa Hospital Research Institute; 2011 Oct. 11 p.&amp;nbsp;(KTA Evidence Summary; no. 14).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3072" OrdBy="180" ID="577" Name="Extent of Measure Testing" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;To validate the seven potential indicators as being appropriate for use throughout the province, the authors first extracted data from the BORN Information System (BIS) for fiscal year 2009 to 2010 to assess historical and current performance on these indicators across Ontario's 14 health regions (Local Health Integration Networks). Simultaneously, evidence summaries on each of the potential indicators were developed in collaboration with the Knowledge to Action Research Centre at the Ottawa Hospital Research Institute (Thielman et al., 2011; Konnyu, Grimshaw, &amp;amp; Moher, &quot;What are the drivers,&quot; 2010; Konnyu, Grimshaw, &amp;amp; Moher, &quot;What are the maternal,&quot; 2011; Konnyu, Grimshaw, &amp;amp; Moher, &quot;What is known,&quot; 2011; Khangura, Grimshaw, &amp;amp; Moher, 2010). This group, which has expertise in the review and synthesis of literature to support evidence-informed health care decision-making, assisted with determining the level of scientific evidence to support each indicator. For example, the evidence summary on early term repeat Caesarean section (i.e., before 39 weeks' gestation) in a defined population determined that as a result of this practice there were indeed objective risks to babies that could be reduced by delaying delivery.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Following review of the data and evidence summaries, the committee removed one indicator and refined some of the others, leaving six. In five of the six, the potential for improvement in rates was obvious. The remaining indicator (rate of screening for group B streptococcus) is currently satisfactory throughout all health regions of the province; however, the committee felt it was important at the outset to have the dashboard reflect not only performance areas requiring improvement, but also areas in which performance was good.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3007" OrdBy="190" ID="578" Name="Evidence for Extent of Measure Testing" Type="citation">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Khangura S, Grimshaw J, Moher D. What is known about the timing of elective repeat cesarean section?. Ottawa (Canada): Ottawa Hospital Research Institute; 2010 May. 11 p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Konnyu K, Grimshaw J, Moher D. What are the drivers of in-hospital formula supplementation in healthy term neonates and what is the effectiveness of hospital-based interventions designed to reduce formula supplementation?. Ottawa (Canada): Ottawa Hospital Research Institute; 2010 Oct. 13 p.&amp;nbsp;(KTA Evidence Summary; no. 8).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Konnyu K, Grimshaw J, Moher D. What are the maternal and newborn outcomes associated with episiotomy during spontaneous vaginal delivery?. Ottawa (Canada): Ottawa Hospital Research Institute; 2011 Jul. 11 p.&amp;nbsp;(KTA Evidence Summary; no. 13).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Konnyu K, Grimshaw J, Moher D. What is known about the maternal and newborn risks of elective induction of women at term?. Ottawa (Canada): Ottawa Hospital Research Institute; 2011 Mar. 13 p.&amp;nbsp;(KTA Evidence Summary; no. 10).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Sprague AE, Dunn SI, Fell DB, Harrold J, Walker MC, Kelly S, Smith GN. Measuring quality in maternal-newborn care: developing a clinical dashboard. J Obstet Gynaecol Can. 2013 Jan;35(1):29-38. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=23343794&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Thielman J, Konnyu K, Grimshaw J, Moher D. What is the evidence supporting universal versus risk-based maternal screening to prevent group B streptococcal infection in newborns?. Ottawa (Canada): Ottawa Hospital Research Institute; 2011 Oct. 11 p.&amp;nbsp;(KTA Evidence Summary; no. 14).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="580" OrdBy="210" Name="State of Use of the Measure">
    <Field FieldID="3029" OrdBy="220" ID="581" Name="State of Use" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Current routine use" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3030" OrdBy="230" ID="582" Name="Current Use" Type="picklist-choice-3">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="583" OrdBy="240" Name="Application of the Measure in its Current Use">
    <Field FieldID="3031" OrdBy="250" ID="584" Name="Measurement Setting" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="Hospital Inpatient" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3032" OrdBy="260" ID="585" Name="Professionals Involved in Delivery of Health Services" Type="picklist-choice-3">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3033" OrdBy="270" ID="586" Name="Least Aggregated Level of Services Delivery Addressed" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Single Health Care Delivery or Public Health Organizations" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3505" OrdBy="280" ID="587" Name="Statement of Acceptable Minimum Sample Size" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Unspecified" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="41" OrdBy="290" ID="588" Name="Target Population Age" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="42" OrdBy="300" ID="589" Name="Target Population Gender" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Female (only)" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="660" OrdBy="310" Name="National Strategy for Quality Improvement in Health Care">
    <Field FieldID="3522" OrdBy="320" ID="661" Name="National Quality Strategy Aim" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Better Care&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3525" OrdBy="330" ID="662" Name="National Quality Strategy Priority" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Health and Well-being of Communities&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Prevention and Treatment of Leading Causes of Mortality&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="590" OrdBy="340" Name="Institute of Medicine (IOM) National Health Care Quality Report Categories">
    <Field FieldID="3163" OrdBy="350" ID="591" Name="IOM Care Need" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="Staying Healthy" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3164" OrdBy="360" ID="592" Name="IOM Domain" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="Effectiveness" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="593" OrdBy="370" Name="Data Collection for the Measure">
    <Field FieldID="3506" OrdBy="380" ID="594" Name="Case Finding Period" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Three-month reporting period&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3054" OrdBy="390" ID="595" Name="Denominator Sampling Frame" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Patients associated with provider" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3057" OrdBy="400" ID="598" Name="Denominator (Index) Event or Characteristic" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="Institutionalization" />
      <FieldValue Value="Therapeutic Intervention" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3058" OrdBy="410" ID="599" Name="Denominator Time Window" Type="picklist-choice-3">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="55" OrdBy="420" ID="596" Name="Denominator Inclusions/Exclusions" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xA;Total number of women who delivered at term (greater than or equal to 37 weeks' gestation) did not decline group B streptococcus (GBS) screening&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: The key performance indicators (KPIs) criteria are defined by the pertinent BORN Information System (BIS) data elements that are used to calculate the rates and proportion values for the respective Maternal Newborn Dashboard KPI. As well, pick-list values for each data element, when selected, will result in a patient record to be either included or excluded for a given KPI based on the KPI criterion definition.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;Refer to the original measure documentation for a complete list of KPI criteria.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xA;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3507" OrdBy="430" ID="597" Name="Exclusions/Exceptions" Type="picklist-choice-4">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="59" OrdBy="440" ID="600" Name="Numerator Inclusions/Exclusions" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xA;Number of women who delivered at term and had group B streptococcus (GBS) screening at 35 to 37 weeks' gestation (35 weeks + 0 days to 37 weeks + 0 days gestation)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: Refer to the original measure documentation for a complete list of key performance indicator (KPI) criteria.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xA;Refer to the original measure documentation for exclusions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3061" OrdBy="450" ID="601" Name="Numerator Search Strategy" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Institutionalization" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3062" OrdBy="460" ID="602" Name="Data Source" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Registry data" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3065" OrdBy="470" ID="603" Name="Type of Health State" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Does not apply to this measure" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3066" OrdBy="480" ID="604" Name="Instruments Used and/or Associated with the Measure" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;BORN Information System (BIS) Maternal Newborn Dashboard (MND)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="605" OrdBy="490" Name="Computation of the Measure">
    <Field FieldID="3508" OrdBy="500" ID="606" Name="Measure Specifies Disaggregation" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Does not apply to this measure" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3067" OrdBy="520" ID="608" Name="Scoring" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Rate/Proportion" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3068" OrdBy="530" ID="609" Name="Interpretation of Score" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Desired value is a higher score" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3090" OrdBy="540" ID="610" Name="Allowance for Patient or Population Factors" Type="picklist-choice-3">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3070" OrdBy="560" ID="612" Name="Standard of Comparison" Type="picklist-choice-3">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="71" OrdBy="570" ID="613" Name="Prescriptive Standard" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;1&quot; cellpadding=&quot;1&quot; summary=&quot;Prescriptive Standard&quot;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;tbody&gt;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;Target:&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;Greater than 94%&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;Warning: &lt;/td&gt;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;90% to 94%&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;Alert:&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;Less than 90%&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/tbody&gt;&#xA;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="9" OrdBy="580" ID="614" Name="Evidence for Prescriptive Standard" Type="citation">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Sprague AE, Dunn SI, Fell DB, Harrold J, Walker MC, Kelly S, Smith GN. Measuring quality in maternal-newborn care: developing a clinical dashboard. J Obstet Gynaecol Can. 2013 Jan;35(1):29-38. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=23343794&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="615" OrdBy="590" Name="Identifying Information">
    <Field FieldID="73" OrdBy="600" ID="616" Name="Original Title" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;KPI 5 - Proportion of women who delivered at term and had Group B Streptococcus (GBS) screening at 35-37 weeks' gestation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="74" OrdBy="610" ID="617" Name="Measure Collection Name" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="Maternal-Newborn Care Performance Indicators" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="16" OrdBy="650" ID="621" Name="Submitter" Type="orglist">
      <FieldValue Value="Better Outcomes Registry and Network (BORN) Ontario - State/Local Government Agency [Non-U.S.]" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="17" OrdBy="660" ID="622" Name="Developer" Type="orglist-p">
      <FieldValue Value="Better Outcomes Registry and Network (BORN) Ontario - State/Local Government Agency [Non-U.S.]" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="79" OrdBy="670" ID="623" Name="Funding Source(s)" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Better Outcomes Registry and Network (BORN) Ontario is funded by the Ontario Ministry of Health and Long Term Care.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="80" OrdBy="680" ID="624" Name="Composition of the Group that Developed the Measure" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ann E. Sprague, RN, PhD (Better Outcomes Registry &amp;amp; Network [BORN] Ontario, Ottawa ON); Sandra I. Dunn, RN, PhD (BORN Ontario, Ottawa ON); Deshayne B. Fell, MSc (BORN Ontario, Ottawa ON); JoAnn Harrold, MD, FRCPC (Department of Pediatrics, Children's Hospital of Eastern Ontario, Ottawa ON); Mark C. Walker, MD, FRCSC (BORN Ontario, Ottawa ON; Departments of Obstetrics and Gynecology, and Epidemiology, University of Ottawa, Ottawa ON; Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, The Ottawa Hospital and the Ottawa Hospital Research Institute, Ottawa ON); Sherrie Kelly, MSc (BORN Ontario, Ottawa ON); Graeme N. Smith, MD, PhD, FRCSC (Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, Kingston General Hospital, Queen's University, Kingston ON), and clinical experts from the BORN Maternal Newborn Outcomes Committee &amp;ndash; Dashboard Subcommittee&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="81" OrdBy="690" ID="625" Name="Financial Disclosures/Other Potential Conflicts of Interest" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;None declared.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="19" OrdBy="730" ID="629" Name="Adaptation" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This measure was not adapted from another source.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3086" OrdBy="740" ID="630" Name="Date of Most Current Version in NQMC" Type="date">
      <FieldValue Value="2014 Jul" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3511" OrdBy="750" ID="631" Name="Measure Maintenance" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3512" OrdBy="760" ID="632" Name="Date of Next Anticipated Revision" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="20" OrdBy="770" ID="633" Name="Measure Status" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the current release of the measure.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The measure developer reaffirmed the currency of this measure in April 2016. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="14" OrdBy="780" ID="634" Name="Measure Availability" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Source not available electronically.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For more information, contact BORN Ontario at 401 Smyth Road, Ottawa, ON, K1H 8L1; Phone: 613-737-7600 x 6022; Web site: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bornontario.ca/en/&quot; title=&quot;BORN Ontario Web site&quot;&gt;www.bornontario.ca/en/&lt;/a&gt;; E-mail: &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:info@bornontario.ca&quot;&gt;info@bornontario.ca&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="87" OrdBy="800" ID="636" Name="NQMC Status" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This NQMC summary was completed by ECRI Institute on January 26, 2015. The information was verified by the measure developer on April 21, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The information was reaffirmed by the measure developer on April 4, 2016. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="88" OrdBy="810" ID="637" Name="Copyright Statement" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;No copyright restrictions apply.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="641" OrdBy="850" Name="Production">
    <Field FieldID="1" OrdBy="1366" ID="562" Name="Source(s)" Type="citation">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Maternal newborn dashboard - key performance indicator criterion reference guide, version 1.3. Ontario (Canada): Better Outcomes Registry and Network (BORN) Ontario; 2014 Jul 2. 12 p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="99999" OrdBy="99999" Name="Disclaimer">
    <Field FieldID="99999" OrdBy="99999" ID="99999" Name="NQMC Disclaimer" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;p&gt;The National Quality Measures Clearinghouse™ (NQMC) does not develop, produce, approve, or endorse the measures represented on this site.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;All measures summarized by NQMC and hosted on our site are produced under the auspices of medical specialty societies, relevant professional associations, public and private organizations, other government agencies, health care organizations or plans, individuals, and similar entities.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Measures represented on the NQMC Web site are submitted by measure developers, and are screened solely to determine that they meet the &lt;a href=&quot;/help-and-about/summaries/inclusion-criteria&quot;&gt;NQMC Inclusion Criteria&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;NQMC, AHRQ, and its contractor ECRI Institute make no warranties concerning the content or its reliability and/or validity of the quality measures and related materials represented on this site. Moreover, the views and opinions of developers or authors of measures represented on this site do not necessarily state or reflect those of NQMC, AHRQ, or its contractor, ECRI Institute, and inclusion or hosting of measures in NQMC may not be used for advertising or commercial endorsement purposes.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Readers with questions regarding measure content are directed to contact the measure developer.&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
</Version>