<Version>
  <xmlSource>This XML content was developed by AHRQ's contractor ECRI Institute for the National Quality Measures Clearinghouse (NQMC).</xmlSource>
  <Section SecID="560" OrdBy="10" Name="General">
    <Field FieldID="11" OrdBy="20" ID="561" Name="Title" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_title&quot;&gt;Diagnostic imaging: percentage of final reports for patients aged 18 years and older undergoing CT with documentation that one or more of the specified dose optimization techniques were used.&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="1" OrdBy="30" ID="562" Name="Source(s)" Type="citation">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;American College of Radiology (ACR), American Medical Association-convened Physician Consortium for Performance Improvement® (PCPI®), National Committee for Quality Assurance (NCQA). Diagnostic imaging performance measurement set. Reston (VA): American College of Radiology (ACR); 2015 Feb. 58 p.  [89 references]&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="563" OrdBy="40" Name="Measure Domain">
    <Field FieldID="3025" OrdBy="50" ID="564" Name="Primary Measure Domain" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Clinical Quality Measures: Process" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3026" OrdBy="60" ID="565" Name="Secondary Measure Domain" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Does not apply to this measure" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="566" OrdBy="70" Name="Brief Abstract">
    <Field FieldID="34" OrdBy="80" ID="567" Name="Description" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This measure is used to assess the percentage of final reports for patients aged 18 years and older undergoing computed tomography (CT) with documentation that one or more of the following dose optimization techniques were used:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Automated exposure control &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Adjustment of the milli-amps (mA) and/or kilo-voltage (kV) according to patient size &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Use of iterative reconstruction technique &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="21" OrdBy="90" ID="568" Name="Rationale" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mettler et al. (2009) estimate that computed tomography (CT) scans account for 17% of total imaging procedures performed in the United States each year and 49% of the collective radiation dose from imaging procedures. Current advances in technology have resulted in several methods to reduce radiation dose for patients undergoing CT. Studies show that the use of CT dose optimization techniques can reduce radiation dose by 40% to 50% without sacrificing image quality or diagnostic ability (Ozdoba et al., 2014; May et al., 2014; Kalra et al., 2002). &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The following evidence statements are quoted &lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;verbatim&lt;/span&gt; from the referenced clinical guidelines and other references&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;CT examinations should be performed only for a valid medical reason and with the minimum exposure that provides the image quality necessary for adequate diagnostic information (American College of Radiology [ACR], 2014).&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Radiologists, medical physicists, registered radiologist assistants, radiologic technologists, and all supervising physicians have a responsibility for safety in the workplace by keeping radiation exposure to staff, and to society as a whole, &quot;as low as reasonably achievable&quot; (ALARA) and to assure that radiation doses to individual patients are appropriate, taking into account the possible risk from radiation exposure and the diagnostic image quality necessary to achieve the clinical objective (ACR, 2014).&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Facilities, in consultation with the medical physicist, should have in place and should adhere to policies and procedures, in accordance with ALARA, to vary examination protocols to take into account patient body habitus, such as height and/or weight, body mass index or lateral width. The dose reduction devices that are available on imaging equipment should be active; if not, manual techniques should be used to moderate the exposure while maintaining the necessary diagnostic image quality. Periodically, radiation exposures should be measured and patient radiation doses estimated by a medical physicist in accordance with the appropriate ACR Technical Standard (ACR, 2014).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3500" OrdBy="100" ID="569" Name="Evidence for Rationale" Type="citation">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;American College of Radiology (ACR), American Medical Association-convened Physician Consortium for Performance Improvement® (PCPI®), National Committee for Quality Assurance (NCQA). Diagnostic imaging performance measurement set. Reston (VA): American College of Radiology (ACR); 2015 Feb. 58 p.  [89 references]&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;American College of Radiology (ACR). ACR practice guideline for performing and interpreting diagnostic computed tomography (CT). Reston (VA): American College of Radiology (ACR); 2014. 8 p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Kalra MK, Prasad S, Saini S, Blake MA, Varghese J, Halpern EF, Thrall JH, Rhea JT. Clinical comparison of standard-dose and 50% reduced-dose abdominal CT: effect on image quality. AJR Am J Roentgenol. 2002 Nov;179(5):1101-6. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=12388481&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;May MS, Eller A, Stahl C, Wuest W, Scharf M, Hammon M, Dankerl P, Schlechtweg PM, Allmendinger T, Sedlmair M, Schmidt B, Uder M, Lell MM. Dose reduction in computed tomography of the chest: image quality of iterative reconstructions at a 50% radiation dose compared to filtered back projection at a 100% radiation dose. ROFO Fortschr Geb Rontgenstr Nuklearmed. 2014 Jun;186(6):576-84. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=24477504&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Mettler FA, Bhargavan M, Faulkner K, Gilley DB, Gray JE, Ibbott GS, Lipoti JA, Mahesh M, McCrohan JL, Stabin MG, Thomadsen BR, Yoshizumi TT. Radiologic and nuclear medicine studies in the United States and worldwide: frequency, radiation dose, and comparison with other radiation sources--1950-2007. Radiology. 2009 Nov;253(2):520-31. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=19789227&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Ozdoba C, Slotboom J, Schroth G, Ulzheimer S, Kottke R, Watzal H, Weisstanner C. Dose reduction in standard head CT: first results from a new scanner using iterative reconstruction and a new detector type in comparison with two previous generations of multi-slice CT. Clin Neuroradiol. 2014 Mar;24(1):23-8. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=24482000&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3022" OrdBy="110" ID="570" Name="Primary Health Components" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Computed tomography (CT); dose optimization techniques&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="23" OrdBy="120" ID="571" Name="Denominator Description" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;All final reports for patients aged 18 years and older undergoing computed tomography (CT)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="24" OrdBy="130" ID="572" Name="Numerator Description" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Final reports with documentation that one or more of the following dose optimization techniques were used:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Automated exposure control &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Adjustment of the milli-amps (mA) and/or kilo-voltage (kV) according to patient size &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Use of iterative reconstruction technique &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="573" OrdBy="140" Name="Evidence Supporting the Measure">
    <Field FieldID="3027" OrdBy="150" ID="574" Name="Type of Evidence Supporting the Criterion of Quality for the Measure" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="A clinical practice guideline or other peer-reviewed synthesis of the clinical research evidence" />
      <FieldValue Value="A formal consensus procedure, involving experts in relevant clinical, methodological,  public health and organizational sciences" />
      <FieldValue Value="One or more research studies published in a National Library of Medicine (NLM) indexed, peer-reviewed journal" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3501" OrdBy="160" ID="575" Name="Additional Information Supporting Need for the Measure" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Importance of Topic&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;As imaging technology continues to advance, the United States healthcare system has seen an increase in both the type and frequency of imaging studies being performed. The increase in utilization of imaging studies is accompanied by a corresponding increase in cost and exposure to radiation for both patients and healthcare professionals. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;From 1980 to 2006, the number of radiologic procedures performed in the United States showed a ten-fold increase while the annual per-capita effective dose from radiologic and nuclear medicine procedures increased by 600% (Mettler et al., 2009). &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;From 1996 to 2010, the number of computerized tomographic (CT) examinations tripled, while the number of ultrasounds nearly doubled (Smith-Bindman et al., 2012). &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;From 1996 to 2010, advanced diagnostic imaging (i.e., CT, magnetic resonance imaging [MRI], nuclear medicine, and ultrasound) accounted for approximately 35% of all imaging studies (Smith-Bindman et al., 2012). &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;From 1980 to 2006, the proportion of radiation exposure that is attributable to medical sources increased from 17% to 53% (Mettler et al., 2009). &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;In 2006, while CT scans only accounted for approximately 17% of all radiologic procedures performed in the United States, they accounted for over 65% of the total effective radiation dose from radiologic procedures (Mettler et al., 2009). &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;In 2006, the estimated per-capita effective radiation dose for radiologic procedures in the United States was nearly 20% higher than the average for other well-developed countries (Mettler et al., 2009). &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Diagnostic imaging was prioritized as a topic area for measure development due to a high level of utilization, rising costs, and the need for measures to help promote appropriate use of imaging and improve outcomes. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Opportunity for Improvement&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;More than 67 million CT scans are performed in the U.S. each year (Mettler et al., 2009). With the increasing number of CT scans being performed, the use of dose optimization techniques becomes more important than ever. As these techniques are relatively new, there is paucity of data related to their current implementation and use. However, one 2013 study by Vance et al. showed significant variability in the use of CT scans based on patient characteristics (e.g., age, sex, race, insurance status) and geographic location. These variations may result in disproportionate radiation exposure for some patient populations. With variability in the use of CT, care must be taken to ensure that dose optimization techniques are applied uniformly across patient populations to minimize excess exposure.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3502" OrdBy="170" ID="576" Name="Evidence for Additional Information Supporting Need for the Measure" Type="citation">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;American College of Radiology (ACR), American Medical Association-convened Physician Consortium for Performance Improvement® (PCPI®), National Committee for Quality Assurance (NCQA). Diagnostic imaging performance measurement set. Reston (VA): American College of Radiology (ACR); 2015 Feb. 58 p.  [89 references]&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Mettler FA, Bhargavan M, Faulkner K, Gilley DB, Gray JE, Ibbott GS, Lipoti JA, Mahesh M, McCrohan JL, Stabin MG, Thomadsen BR, Yoshizumi TT. Radiologic and nuclear medicine studies in the United States and worldwide: frequency, radiation dose, and comparison with other radiation sources--1950-2007. Radiology. 2009 Nov;253(2):520-31. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=19789227&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Smith-Bindman R, Miglioretti DL, Johnson E, Lee C, Feigelson HS, Flynn M, Greenlee RT, Kruger RL, Hornbrook MC, Roblin D, Solberg LI, Vanneman N, Weinmann S, Williams AE. Use of diagnostic imaging studies and associated radiation exposure for patients enrolled in large integrated health care systems, 1996-2010. JAMA. 2012 Jun 13;307(22):2400-9. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=22692172&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Vance EA, Xie X, Henry A, Wernz C, Slonim AD. Computed tomography scan use variation: patient, hospital, and geographic factors. Am J Manag Care. 2013;19(3):e93-9. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=23534948&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3072" OrdBy="180" ID="577" Name="Extent of Measure Testing" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some of the measures in this set are being made available without any prior testing. The Physician Consortium for Performance Improvement (PCPI) recognizes the importance of testing all of its measures and encourages testing of the diagnostic imaging measurement set for feasibility and reliability by organizations or individuals positioned to do so. The &lt;em&gt;Measure Testing Protocol for PCPI Measures&lt;/em&gt; was approved by the PCPI in 2010 and is available on the PCPI Web site (see Position Papers at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.physicianconsortium.org&quot; title=&quot;PCPI Web site&quot;&gt;www.physicianconsortium.org&lt;/a&gt;); interested parties are encouraged to review this document and to contact PCPI staff. The PCPI will welcome any opportunity to promote the initial testing of these measures and to ensure that any results available from testing are used to refine the measures before implementation. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3007" OrdBy="190" ID="578" Name="Evidence for Extent of Measure Testing" Type="citation">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;American College of Radiology (ACR), American Medical Association-convened Physician Consortium for Performance Improvement® (PCPI®), National Committee for Quality Assurance (NCQA). Diagnostic imaging performance measurement set. Reston (VA): American College of Radiology (ACR); 2015 Feb. 58 p.  [89 references]&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="580" OrdBy="210" Name="State of Use of the Measure">
    <Field FieldID="3029" OrdBy="220" ID="581" Name="State of Use" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Current routine use" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3030" OrdBy="230" ID="582" Name="Current Use" Type="picklist-choice-3">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="583" OrdBy="240" Name="Application of the Measure in its Current Use">
    <Field FieldID="3031" OrdBy="250" ID="584" Name="Measurement Setting" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="Ambulatory/Office-based Care" />
      <FieldValue Value="Ambulatory Procedure/Imaging Center" />
      <FieldValue Value="Hospital Inpatient" />
      <FieldValue Value="Hospital Outpatient" />
      <FieldValue Value="Long-term Care Facilities - Other" />
      <FieldValue Value="Skilled Nursing Facilities/Nursing Homes" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3032" OrdBy="260" ID="585" Name="Professionals Involved in Delivery of Health Services" Type="picklist-choice-3">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3033" OrdBy="270" ID="586" Name="Least Aggregated Level of Services Delivery Addressed" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Single Health Care Delivery or Public Health Organizations" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3505" OrdBy="280" ID="587" Name="Statement of Acceptable Minimum Sample Size" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Does not apply to this measure" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="41" OrdBy="290" ID="588" Name="Target Population Age" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Age greater than or equal to 18 years&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="42" OrdBy="300" ID="589" Name="Target Population Gender" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Either male or female" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="660" OrdBy="310" Name="National Strategy for Quality Improvement in Health Care">
    <Field FieldID="3522" OrdBy="320" ID="661" Name="National Quality Strategy Aim" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Better Care&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3525" OrdBy="330" ID="662" Name="National Quality Strategy Priority" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Health and Well-being of Communities&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Making Care Safer&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Prevention and Treatment of Leading Causes of Mortality&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="590" OrdBy="340" Name="Institute of Medicine (IOM) National Health Care Quality Report Categories">
    <Field FieldID="3163" OrdBy="350" ID="591" Name="IOM Care Need" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="Staying Healthy" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3164" OrdBy="360" ID="592" Name="IOM Domain" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="Effectiveness" />
      <FieldValue Value="Equity" />
      <FieldValue Value="Safety" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="593" OrdBy="370" Name="Data Collection for the Measure">
    <Field FieldID="3506" OrdBy="380" ID="594" Name="Case Finding Period" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3054" OrdBy="390" ID="595" Name="Denominator Sampling Frame" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Patients associated with provider" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3057" OrdBy="400" ID="598" Name="Denominator (Index) Event or Characteristic" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="Diagnostic Evaluation" />
      <FieldValue Value="Patient/Individual (Consumer) Characteristic" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3058" OrdBy="410" ID="599" Name="Denominator Time Window" Type="picklist-choice-3">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="55" OrdBy="420" ID="596" Name="Denominator Inclusions/Exclusions" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;All final reports for patients aged 18 years or older undergoing computed tomography (CT) &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exceptions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;None&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3507" OrdBy="430" ID="597" Name="Exclusions/Exceptions" Type="picklist-choice-4">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="59" OrdBy="440" ID="600" Name="Numerator Inclusions/Exclusions" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Final reports with documentation that one or more of the following dose optimization techniques were used:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Automated exposure control &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Adjustment of the milli-amps (mA) and/or kilo-voltage (kV) according to patient size &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Use of iterative reconstruction technique &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3061" OrdBy="450" ID="601" Name="Numerator Search Strategy" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Fixed time period or point in time" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3062" OrdBy="460" ID="602" Name="Data Source" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Electronic health/medical record" />
      <FieldValue Value="Imaging data" />
      <FieldValue Value="Paper medical record" />
      <FieldValue Value="Registry data" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3065" OrdBy="470" ID="603" Name="Type of Health State" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Does not apply to this measure" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3066" OrdBy="480" ID="604" Name="Instruments Used and/or Associated with the Measure" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="605" OrdBy="490" Name="Computation of the Measure">
    <Field FieldID="3508" OrdBy="500" ID="606" Name="Measure Specifies Disaggregation" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Does not apply to this measure" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3067" OrdBy="520" ID="608" Name="Scoring" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Rate/Proportion" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3068" OrdBy="530" ID="609" Name="Interpretation of Score" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Desired value is a higher score" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3090" OrdBy="540" ID="610" Name="Allowance for Patient or Population Factors" Type="picklist-choice-3">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3070" OrdBy="560" ID="612" Name="Standard of Comparison" Type="picklist-choice-3">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="615" OrdBy="590" Name="Identifying Information">
    <Field FieldID="73" OrdBy="600" ID="616" Name="Original Title" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Measure #6: radiation consideration for adult computed tomography (CT): utilization of dose optimization techniques.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="74" OrdBy="610" ID="617" Name="Measure Collection Name" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="Diagnostic Imaging Performance Measurement Set" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="16" OrdBy="650" ID="621" Name="Submitter" Type="orglist">
      <FieldValue Value="American College of Radiology - Medical Specialty Society" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="17" OrdBy="660" ID="622" Name="Developer" Type="orglist-p">
      <FieldValue Value="American College of Radiology - Medical Specialty Society" />
      <FieldValue Value="National Committee for Quality Assurance - Health Care Accreditation Organization" />
      <FieldValue Value="Physician Consortium for Performance Improvement® - Clinical Specialty Collaboration" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="79" OrdBy="670" ID="623" Name="Funding Source(s)" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="80" OrdBy="680" ID="624" Name="Composition of the Group that Developed the Measure" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Diagnostic Imaging Measure Development Work Group Members&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;William Golden, MD (&lt;em&gt;Co-chair&lt;/em&gt;) (internal medicine) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;David Seidenwurm (&lt;em&gt;Co-chair&lt;/em&gt;) (diagnostic radiology) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Michael Bettmann, MD &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Dorothy Bulas, MD (pediatric radiology) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Rubin I. Cohen, MD, FACP, FCCP, FCCM &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Richard T. Griffey, MD, MPH (emergency medicine) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Eric J. Hohenwalter, MD (vascular interventional radiology) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Deborah Levine, MD, FACR (radiology/ultrasound) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Mark Morasch, MD (vascular surgery) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Paul Nagy, MD, PhD (radiology) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Mark R. Needham, MD, MBA (family medicine) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Hoang D. Nguyen (diagnostic radiology/payer representative) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Charles J. Prestigiacomo, MD, FACS (neurosurgery) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;William G. Preston, MD, FAAN (neurology) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Robert Pyatt, Jr., MD (diagnostic radiology) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Robert Rosenberg, MD (diagnostic radiology) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;David A. Rubin, MD (diagnostic radiology) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;B Winfred (B.W.) Ruffner, MD, FACP (medical oncology) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Frank Rybicki, MD, PhD, FAHA (diagnostic radiology) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Cheryl A. Sadow, MD (radiology) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;John Schneider, MD, PhD (internal medicine) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Gary Schultz, DC, DACR (chiropractic) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Paul R. Sierzenski, MD, RDMS (emergency medicine) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Michael Wasylik, MD (orthopedic surgery) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Diagnostic Imaging Measure Development Work Group Staff&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;American College of Radiology&lt;/em&gt;: Judy Burleson, MHSA; Alicia Blakey, MS &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;American Medical Association-convened Physician Consortium for Performance Improvement&lt;/em&gt;: Mark Antman, DDS, MBA; Kathleen Blake, MD, MPH; Kendra Hanley, MS; Toni Kaye, MPH; Marjorie Rallins, DPM; Kimberly Smuk, RHIA; Samantha Tierney, MPH; Stavros Tsipas, MA &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;National Committee for Quality Assurance&lt;/em&gt;: Mary Barton, MD &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="81" OrdBy="690" ID="625" Name="Financial Disclosures/Other Potential Conflicts of Interest" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;None of the members of the Diagnostic Imaging Work Group had any disqualifying material interest under the Physician Consortium for Performance Improvement (PCPI) Conflict of Interest Policy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3083" OrdBy="720" ID="628" Name="Measure Initiative(s)" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Physician Quality Reporting System" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="19" OrdBy="730" ID="629" Name="Adaptation" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This measure was not adapted from another source.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3086" OrdBy="740" ID="630" Name="Date of Most Current Version in NQMC" Type="date">
      <FieldValue Value="2015 Feb" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3511" OrdBy="750" ID="631" Name="Measure Maintenance" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This measure is reviewed and updated every 3 years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3512" OrdBy="760" ID="632" Name="Date of Next Anticipated Revision" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;2018&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="20" OrdBy="770" ID="633" Name="Measure Status" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the current release of the measure.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="14" OrdBy="780" ID="634" Name="Measure Availability" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Source available from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.acr.org/~/media/ACR/Documents/PDF/QualitySafety/Quality%20Measurement/Performance%20Measures/DiagnosticImagingMeasureSet2015.pdf&quot; title=&quot;ACR Web site&quot;&gt;American College of Radiology (ACR) Web site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For more information, contact ACR at 1891 Preston White Drive, Reston, VA 20191; Phone: 703-648-8900; E-mail: &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:info@acr.org&quot;&gt;info@acr.org&lt;/a&gt;; Web site: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.acr.org/&quot; title=&quot;ACR Web site&quot;&gt;www.acr.org&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="87" OrdBy="800" ID="636" Name="NQMC Status" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This NQMC summary was completed by ECRI Institute on October 13, 2015. The information was verified by the measure developer on November 19, 2015. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="88" OrdBy="810" ID="637" Name="Copyright Statement" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This NQMC summary is based on the original measure, which is subject to the measure developer's copyright restrictions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;copy;2014 American Medical Association (AMA) and American College of Radiology (ACR). All Rights Reserved. CPT&amp;reg; Copyright 2004 to 2013 American Medical Association.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="641" OrdBy="850" Name="Production">
    <Field FieldID="1" OrdBy="1366" ID="562" Name="Source(s)" Type="citation">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;American College of Radiology (ACR), American Medical Association-convened Physician Consortium for Performance Improvement® (PCPI®), National Committee for Quality Assurance (NCQA). Diagnostic imaging performance measurement set. Reston (VA): American College of Radiology (ACR); 2015 Feb. 58 p.  [89 references]&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="99999" OrdBy="99999" Name="Disclaimer">
    <Field FieldID="99999" OrdBy="99999" ID="99999" Name="NQMC Disclaimer" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;p&gt;The National Quality Measures Clearinghouse™ (NQMC) does not develop, produce, approve, or endorse the measures represented on this site.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;All measures summarized by NQMC and hosted on our site are produced under the auspices of medical specialty societies, relevant professional associations, public and private organizations, other government agencies, health care organizations or plans, individuals, and similar entities.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Measures represented on the NQMC Web site are submitted by measure developers, and are screened solely to determine that they meet the &lt;a href=&quot;/help-and-about/summaries/inclusion-criteria&quot;&gt;NQMC Inclusion Criteria&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;NQMC, AHRQ, and its contractor ECRI Institute make no warranties concerning the content or its reliability and/or validity of the quality measures and related materials represented on this site. Moreover, the views and opinions of developers or authors of measures represented on this site do not necessarily state or reflect those of NQMC, AHRQ, or its contractor, ECRI Institute, and inclusion or hosting of measures in NQMC may not be used for advertising or commercial endorsement purposes.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Readers with questions regarding measure content are directed to contact the measure developer.&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
</Version>