<Version>
  <xmlSource>This XML content was developed by AHRQ's contractor ECRI Institute for the National Quality Measures Clearinghouse (NQMC).</xmlSource>
  <Section SecID="560" OrdBy="10" Name="General">
    <Field FieldID="11" OrdBy="20" ID="561" Name="Title" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_title&quot;&gt;Inflammatory bowel disease (IBD): percentage of patients aged 18 years and older with an IBD encounter who were prescribed prednisone equivalents greater than or equal to 10 mg/day for 60 or greater consecutive days or a single prescription equating to 600 mg prednisone or greater for all fills and were documented for risk of bone loss once during the reporting year or the previous calendar year.&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="1" OrdBy="30" ID="562" Name="Source(s)" Type="citation">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;American Gastroenterological Association (AGA). Inflammatory bowel disease (IBD): preventive care: corticosteroid related iatrogenic injury - bone loss assessment. Bethesda (MD): American Gastroenterological Association (AGA); 2015 Dec 18. 7 p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="563" OrdBy="40" Name="Measure Domain">
    <Field FieldID="3025" OrdBy="50" ID="564" Name="Primary Measure Domain" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Clinical Quality Measures: Process" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3026" OrdBy="60" ID="565" Name="Secondary Measure Domain" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Does not apply to this measure" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="566" OrdBy="70" Name="Brief Abstract">
    <Field FieldID="34" OrdBy="80" ID="567" Name="Description" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This measure is used to assess the percentage of patients aged 18 years and older with an inflammatory bowel disease (IBD) encounter who were prescribed prednisone equivalents greater than or equal to 10 mg/day for 60 or greater consecutive days or a single prescription equating to 600 mg prednisone or greater for all fills and were documented for risk of bone loss once during the reporting year or the previous calendar year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="21" OrdBy="90" ID="568" Name="Rationale" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Patients with inflammatory bowel disease (IBD) often rely on their gastroenterologist for healthcare maintenance. In addition, the gastroenterologist also provides guidance to the patient's primary care physician on a broad range of issues such as vaccinations, osteoporosis screening, and cancer/dysplasia surveillance. Screening for osteoporosis is based on a combination of individual risk factors, but a history of prolonged (greater than 3 months) steroid use over 10 mg is reason enough to obtain dual-energy x-ray absorptiometry scanning (Moscandrew, Mahadevan, &amp;amp; Kane, 2009). &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Markers of greater osteoporosis and fracture risk include older age, hypogonadism, corticosteroid therapy, and established cirrhosis (American Gastroenterological Association [AGA], &quot;Osteoporosis in hepatic disorders,&quot; 2003). &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The decision to measure bone density should follow an individualized approach. It should be considered when it will help the patient decide whether to institute treatment to prevent osteoporotic fracture. It should also be considered in patients receiving glucocorticoid therapy for two months or more and patients with other conditions that place them at high risk for osteoporotic fracture (&quot;Osteoporosis prevention,&quot; 2000). &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The most commonly used measurement to diagnose osteoporosis and predict fracture risk is based on assessment of bone mineral density (BMD) by dual energy X-ray absorptiometry (DXA) (&quot;Osteoporosis prevention,&quot; 2000). &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Measurements of BMD made at the hip predict hip fracture better than measurements made at other sites while BMD measurement at the spine predicts spine fracture better than measures at other sites (&quot;Osteoporosis prevention,&quot; 2000). &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clinical Recommendation Statements&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;IBD has only a modest effect on BMD, with a pooled Z score of -0.5 (AGA, &quot;Guidelines on osteoporosis,&quot; 2003). &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Corticosteroid use is the variable most strongly associated with osteoporosis. However, it is difficult to distinguish corticosteroid use from disease activity in terms of causal impact on bone density, because the two are closely linked (AGA, &quot;Guidelines on osteoporosis,&quot; 2003). &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However there is strong evidence that those on long-term steroids of greater than three months have a significant increase risk of fracture (Papaioannou, Ferko, &amp;amp; Adachi, 2001). DXA screening is recommended in inflammatory bowel disease patients with one or more risk factors: history of vertebral fractures, postmenopausal, male greater than 50 years of age, chronic corticosteroid therapy, or hypogonadism. If the initial DXA is normal, the AGA recommends repeat testing in 2 to 3 years. If the patient has osteoporosis, or has a history of a low trauma fracture, evaluation for secondary causes should be completed. Suggested studies include a complete blood count, serum concentrations of alkaline phosphatase level, calcium, creatinine, and 25-OH vitamin D, serum protein electrophoresis, serum calcium, and a testosterone level in males (Bernstein, Leslie, &amp;amp; Leboff, 2003).&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Data on the treatment of osteoporosis in Crohn's disease depend on studies that are not specific to IBD. The evidence levels and recommendation grades are accordingly marked down. Weight bearing, isotonic exercise, stopping smoking, avoiding alcohol excess, and maintaining adequate dietary calcium (greater than 1 g/day) are beneficial. Hormone replacement treatment is no longer generally advised in post-menopausal women with osteoporosis, but regular use of bisphosphonates, calcitonin and its derivatives, and raloxifene may reduce or prevent further bone loss. Data in men with osteoporosis are less secure but bisphosphonates are probably of value. Newer data also support the use of strontium salts. Patients receiving systemic steroid therapy should receive calcium and vitamin D for prophylaxis (Van Assche et al., 2013).&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Diagnosis of osteoporosis in adults is best made from a T score of less than -2.5 on radiographic bone densitometry, all other diagnosis methods having current limitations. The presence of osteoporosis identifies patients at above average risk for fracture and who should receive treatment. Osteopenia may be a prognostic marker for future osteoporosis, but presents little direct risk. However if the T score is less than -1.5, treatment with calcium and vitamin D should be recommended. Pre-existing history of fracture is of substantial adverse prognostic significance and patients should be treated for osteoporosis even if the T score is normal (Van Assche et al., 2013). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3500" OrdBy="100" ID="569" Name="Evidence for Rationale" Type="citation">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;American Gastroenterological Association (AGA). American Gastroenterological Association medical position statement: guidelines on osteoporosis in gastrointestinal diseases. Gastroenterology. 2003 Mar;124(3):791-4. [15 references] &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=12612916&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;American Gastroenterological Association (AGA). American Gastroenterological Association medical position statement: osteoporosis in hepatic disorders. Gastroenterology. 2003 Sep;125(3):937-40. [1 reference] &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=12949737&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;American Gastroenterological Association (AGA). Inflammatory bowel disease (IBD): preventive care: corticosteroid related iatrogenic injury - bone loss assessment. Bethesda (MD): American Gastroenterological Association (AGA); 2015 Dec 18. 7 p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Bernstein CN, Leslie WD, Leboff MS. AGA technical review on osteoporosis in gastrointestinal diseases. Gastroenterology. 2003 Mar;124(3):795-841. [298 references] &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=12612917&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Moscandrew M, Mahadevan U, Kane S. General health maintenance in IBD. Inflamm Bowel Dis. 2009 Sep;15(9):1399-409. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=19591135&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Osteoporosis prevention, diagnosis, and therapy. NIH Consens Statement Online. 2000 Mar 27-29;17(1):1-45. [111 references] &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=11525451&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Papaioannou A, Ferko NC, Adachi JD. All patients with inflammatory bowel disease should have bone density assessment: pro. Inflamm Bowel Dis. 2001 May;7(2):158-62; discussion 168-9. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=11383589&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Van Assche G, Dignass A, Bokemeyer B, Danese S, Gionchetti P, Moser G, Beaugerie L, Gomollón F, Häuser W, Herrlinger K, Oldenburg B, Panes J, Portela F, Rogler G, Stein J, Tilg H, Travis S, Lindsay JO, European Crohn's and Colitis Organisation. Second European evidence-based consensus on the diagnosis and management of ulcerative colitis part 3: special situations. J Crohns Colitis. 2013 Feb;7(1):1-33. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=23040453&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3022" OrdBy="110" ID="570" Name="Primary Health Components" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Inflammatory bowel disease (IBD); corticosteroid-related iatrogenic injury; bone loss assessment; prednisone&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="23" OrdBy="120" ID="571" Name="Denominator Description" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;All patients aged 18 years and older with a diagnosis of inflammatory bowel disease (IBD) (see the related &quot;Denominator Inclusions/Exclusions&quot; field)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="24" OrdBy="130" ID="572" Name="Numerator Description" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Patients who have received dose of corticosteroids greater than or equal to 10 mg/day of prednisone equivalents for 60 or greater consecutive days or a single prescription equating to 600 mg prednisone or greater for all fills and who were documented for risk of bone loss during the reporting year or the previous calendar year (see the related &quot;Numerator Inclusions/Exclusions&quot; field)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="573" OrdBy="140" Name="Evidence Supporting the Measure">
    <Field FieldID="3027" OrdBy="150" ID="574" Name="Type of Evidence Supporting the Criterion of Quality for the Measure" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="A clinical practice guideline or other peer-reviewed synthesis of the clinical research evidence" />
      <FieldValue Value="A formal consensus procedure, involving experts in relevant clinical, methodological,  public health and organizational sciences" />
      <FieldValue Value="One or more research studies published in a National Library of Medicine (NLM) indexed, peer-reviewed journal" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3501" OrdBy="160" ID="575" Name="Additional Information Supporting Need for the Measure" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3072" OrdBy="180" ID="577" Name="Extent of Measure Testing" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="580" OrdBy="210" Name="State of Use of the Measure">
    <Field FieldID="3029" OrdBy="220" ID="581" Name="State of Use" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Current routine use" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3030" OrdBy="230" ID="582" Name="Current Use" Type="picklist-choice-3">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="583" OrdBy="240" Name="Application of the Measure in its Current Use">
    <Field FieldID="3031" OrdBy="250" ID="584" Name="Measurement Setting" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="Ambulatory/Office-based Care" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3032" OrdBy="260" ID="585" Name="Professionals Involved in Delivery of Health Services" Type="picklist-choice-3">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3033" OrdBy="270" ID="586" Name="Least Aggregated Level of Services Delivery Addressed" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Individual Clinicians or Public Health Professionals" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3505" OrdBy="280" ID="587" Name="Statement of Acceptable Minimum Sample Size" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Specified" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="41" OrdBy="290" ID="588" Name="Target Population Age" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Age greater than or equal to 18 years&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="42" OrdBy="300" ID="589" Name="Target Population Gender" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Either male or female" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="660" OrdBy="310" Name="National Strategy for Quality Improvement in Health Care">
    <Field FieldID="3522" OrdBy="320" ID="661" Name="National Quality Strategy Aim" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Better Care&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3525" OrdBy="330" ID="662" Name="National Quality Strategy Priority" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Prevention and Treatment of Leading Causes of Mortality&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="590" OrdBy="340" Name="Institute of Medicine (IOM) National Health Care Quality Report Categories">
    <Field FieldID="3163" OrdBy="350" ID="591" Name="IOM Care Need" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="Living with Illness" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3164" OrdBy="360" ID="592" Name="IOM Domain" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="Effectiveness" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="593" OrdBy="370" Name="Data Collection for the Measure">
    <Field FieldID="3506" OrdBy="380" ID="594" Name="Case Finding Period" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The reporting period (January 1 through December 31)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3054" OrdBy="390" ID="595" Name="Denominator Sampling Frame" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Patients associated with provider" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3057" OrdBy="400" ID="598" Name="Denominator (Index) Event or Characteristic" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="Clinical Condition" />
      <FieldValue Value="Encounter" />
      <FieldValue Value="Patient/Individual (Consumer) Characteristic" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3058" OrdBy="410" ID="599" Name="Denominator Time Window" Type="picklist-choice-3">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="55" OrdBy="420" ID="596" Name="Denominator Inclusions/Exclusions" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xA;All patients aged 18 years and older with a diagnosis of inflammatory bowel disease (IBD) &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Denominator Criteria (Eligible Cases)&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Patients aged greater than or equal to 18 years on date of encounter &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AND&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Diagnosis for IBD (International Classification of Diseases, Tenth Revision, Clinical Modification [ICD-10-CM] codes): K50.00, K50.011, K50.012, K50.013, K50.014, K50.018, K50.019, K50.10, K50.111, K50.112, K50.113, K50.114, K50.118, K50.119, K50.80, K50.811, K50.812, K50.813, K50.814, K50.818, K50.819, K50.90, K50.911, K50.912, K50.913, K50.914, K50.918, K50.919, K51.00, K51.011, K51.012, K51.013, K51.014, K51.018, K51.019, K51.20, K51.211, K51.212, K51.213, K51.214, K51.218, K51.219, K51.30, K51.311, K51.312, K51.313, K51.314, K51.318, K51.319, K51.40, K51.411, K51.412, K51.413, K51.414, K51.418, K51.419, K51.50, K51.511, K51.512, K51.513, K51.514, K51.518, K51.519, K51.80, K51.811, K51.812, K51.813, K51.814, K51.818, K51.819, K51.90, K51.911, K51.912, K51.913, K51.914, K51.918, K51.919&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AND&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Patient encounter during the reporting period (refer to the original measure documentation for specific Current Procedural Terminology [CPT] codes)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AND&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Patients who have received or are receiving corticosteroids* greater than or equal to 10 mg/day of prednisone equivalents for 60 or greater consecutive days or a single prescription equating to 600 mg prednisone or greater for all fills: G9469&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;*&lt;em&gt;Corticosteroids&lt;/em&gt;: Prednisone equivalents used expressly for the treatment of IBD and not for other indications (including premedication before anti-TNF [tumor necrosis factor] therapy, non-IBD indications) can be determined using the following: 1 mg of prednisone = 1 mg of prednisolone; 5 mg of cortisone; 4 mg of hydrocortisone; 0.8 mg of triamcinolone; 0.8 mg of methylprednisolone; 0.15 mg of dexamethasone; 0.15 mg of betamethasone. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xA;None&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3507" OrdBy="430" ID="597" Name="Exclusions/Exceptions" Type="picklist-choice-4">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="59" OrdBy="440" ID="600" Name="Numerator Inclusions/Exclusions" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Patients who have received dose of corticosteroids greater than or equal to 10 mg/day of prednisone equivalents for 60 or greater consecutive days or a single prescription equating to 600 mg prednisone or greater for all fills and who were documented* for risk of bone loss during the reporting year or the previous calendar year&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;*&lt;em&gt;Documented&lt;/em&gt;: Documentation that an assessment for risk of bone loss has been performed or ordered. This includes, but is not limited to, review of systems and medication history, and ordering of central dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry (DXA) scan. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3061" OrdBy="450" ID="601" Name="Numerator Search Strategy" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Fixed time period or point in time" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3062" OrdBy="460" ID="602" Name="Data Source" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Administrative clinical data" />
      <FieldValue Value="Registry data" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3065" OrdBy="470" ID="603" Name="Type of Health State" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Does not apply to this measure" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3066" OrdBy="480" ID="604" Name="Instruments Used and/or Associated with the Measure" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="605" OrdBy="490" Name="Computation of the Measure">
    <Field FieldID="3508" OrdBy="500" ID="606" Name="Measure Specifies Disaggregation" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Does not apply to this measure" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3067" OrdBy="520" ID="608" Name="Scoring" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Rate/Proportion" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3068" OrdBy="530" ID="609" Name="Interpretation of Score" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Desired value is a higher score" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3090" OrdBy="540" ID="610" Name="Allowance for Patient or Population Factors" Type="picklist-choice-3">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3070" OrdBy="560" ID="612" Name="Standard of Comparison" Type="picklist-choice-3">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="615" OrdBy="590" Name="Identifying Information">
    <Field FieldID="73" OrdBy="600" ID="616" Name="Original Title" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Measure #271: inflammatory bowel disease (IBD): preventive care: corticosteroid related iatrogenic injury &amp;ndash; bone loss assessment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="74" OrdBy="610" ID="617" Name="Measure Collection Name" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="Inflammatory Bowel Disease" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="16" OrdBy="650" ID="621" Name="Submitter" Type="orglist">
      <FieldValue Value="American Gastroenterological Association - Medical Specialty Society" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="17" OrdBy="660" ID="622" Name="Developer" Type="orglist-p">
      <FieldValue Value="American Gastroenterological Association - Medical Specialty Society" />
      <FieldValue Value="Physician Consortium for Performance Improvement® - Clinical Specialty Collaboration" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="79" OrdBy="670" ID="623" Name="Funding Source(s)" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="80" OrdBy="680" ID="624" Name="Composition of the Group that Developed the Measure" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="81" OrdBy="690" ID="625" Name="Financial Disclosures/Other Potential Conflicts of Interest" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3640" OrdBy="715" ID="702" Name="Core Quality Measures" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="Gastroenterology" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3083" OrdBy="720" ID="628" Name="Measure Initiative(s)" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Physician Quality Reporting System" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="19" OrdBy="730" ID="629" Name="Adaptation" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This measure was not adapted from another source.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3086" OrdBy="740" ID="630" Name="Date of Most Current Version in NQMC" Type="date">
      <FieldValue Value="2015 Dec" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3511" OrdBy="750" ID="631" Name="Measure Maintenance" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3512" OrdBy="760" ID="632" Name="Date of Next Anticipated Revision" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;2017&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="20" OrdBy="770" ID="633" Name="Measure Status" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the current release of the measure.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="14" OrdBy="780" ID="634" Name="Measure Availability" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Source not available electronically.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For more information, contact the American Gastroenterological Association (AGA) at 4930 Del Ray Avenue, Bethesda, MD 20814; Phone: 301-654-2055; Fax: 301-654-5920; E-mail: &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:measures@gastro.org&quot;&gt;measures@gastro.org&lt;/a&gt;; Web site: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gastro.org/&quot; title=&quot;AGA Web site&quot;&gt;www.gastro.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="87" OrdBy="800" ID="636" Name="NQMC Status" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This NQMC measure summary was completed by ECRI Institute on March 14, 2016. The information was verified by the measure developer on March 29, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="88" OrdBy="810" ID="637" Name="Copyright Statement" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This NQMC summary is based on the original measure, which is subject to the measure developer's copyright restrictions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Measures are not clinical guidelines, do not establish a standard of medical care, and have not been tested for all potential applications. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Measures, while copyrighted, can be reproduced and distributed, without modification, for noncommercial purposes, e.g., use by health care providers in connection with their practices. Commercial use is defined as the sale, license, or distribution of the Measures for commercial gain, or incorporation of the Measures into a product or service that is sold, licensed or distributed for commercial gain. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Commercial uses of the Measures require a license agreement between the user and the American Medical Association (AMA), (on behalf of the Physician Consortium for Performance Improvement&amp;reg; [PCPI&amp;reg;]) or American Gastroenterological Association (AGA). Neither the AMA, AGA, PCPI, nor its members shall be responsible for any use of the Measures. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The AMA's and PCPI's significant past efforts and contributions to the development and updating of the Measures is acknowledged. AGA is solely responsible for the review and enhancement (&quot;Maintenance&quot;) of the Measures as of June 30, 2014&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;AGA encourages use of the Measures by other health care professionals, where appropriate. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;THE MEASURES AND SPECIFICATIONS ARE PROVIDED &quot;AS IS&quot; WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;copy;2015 American Medical Association and American Gastroenterological Association. All Rights Reserved. Applicable FARS/DFARS Restrictions Apply to Government Use. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Limited proprietary coding is contained in the Measure specifications for convenience. Users of the proprietary code sets should obtain all necessary licenses from the owners of these code sets. The AMA, AGA, the PCPI and its members disclaim all liability for use or accuracy of any Current Procedural Terminology (CPT&amp;reg;) or other coding contained in the specifications. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;CPT&amp;reg; contained in the Measures specifications is copyright 2004-2014 American Medical Association. LOINC&amp;reg; copyright 2004-2013 Regenstrief Institute, Inc. SNOMED CLINICAL TERMS (SNOMED CT&amp;reg;) copyright 2004-2013 College of American Pathologists. All Rights Reserved.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="641" OrdBy="850" Name="Production">
    <Field FieldID="1" OrdBy="1366" ID="562" Name="Source(s)" Type="citation">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;American Gastroenterological Association (AGA). Inflammatory bowel disease (IBD): preventive care: corticosteroid related iatrogenic injury - bone loss assessment. Bethesda (MD): American Gastroenterological Association (AGA); 2015 Dec 18. 7 p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="99999" OrdBy="99999" Name="Disclaimer">
    <Field FieldID="99999" OrdBy="99999" ID="99999" Name="NQMC Disclaimer" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;p&gt;The National Quality Measures Clearinghouse™ (NQMC) does not develop, produce, approve, or endorse the measures represented on this site.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;All measures summarized by NQMC and hosted on our site are produced under the auspices of medical specialty societies, relevant professional associations, public and private organizations, other government agencies, health care organizations or plans, individuals, and similar entities.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Measures represented on the NQMC Web site are submitted by measure developers, and are screened solely to determine that they meet the &lt;a href=&quot;/help-and-about/summaries/inclusion-criteria&quot;&gt;NQMC Inclusion Criteria&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;NQMC, AHRQ, and its contractor ECRI Institute make no warranties concerning the content or its reliability and/or validity of the quality measures and related materials represented on this site. Moreover, the views and opinions of developers or authors of measures represented on this site do not necessarily state or reflect those of NQMC, AHRQ, or its contractor, ECRI Institute, and inclusion or hosting of measures in NQMC may not be used for advertising or commercial endorsement purposes.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Readers with questions regarding measure content are directed to contact the measure developer.&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
</Version>