<Version>
  <xmlSource>This XML content was developed by AHRQ's contractor ECRI Institute for the National Quality Measures Clearinghouse (NQMC).</xmlSource>
  <Section SecID="560" OrdBy="10" Name="General">
    <Field FieldID="11" OrdBy="20" ID="561" Name="Title" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_title&quot;&gt;Eye care: percentage of patients aged 18 years and older with a diagnosis of uncomplicated cataract who had cataract surgery and no significant ocular conditions impacting the visual outcome of surgery and had best-corrected visual acuity of 20/40 or better (distance or near) achieved within 90 days following the cataract surgery.&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="1" OrdBy="30" ID="562" Name="Source(s)" Type="citation">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;American Medical Association-convened Physician Consortium for Performance Improvement® (PCPI®), American Academy of Ophthalmology. Eye care I and II performance measurement sets. Chicago (IL): American Medical Association (AMA); 2015 Aug. 55 p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="563" OrdBy="40" Name="Measure Domain">
    <Field FieldID="3025" OrdBy="50" ID="564" Name="Primary Measure Domain" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Clinical Quality Measures: Outcome" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3026" OrdBy="60" ID="565" Name="Secondary Measure Domain" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Does not apply to this measure" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="566" OrdBy="70" Name="Brief Abstract">
    <Field FieldID="34" OrdBy="80" ID="567" Name="Description" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This measure is used to assess the percentage of patients aged 18 years and older with a diagnosis of uncomplicated cataract who had cataract surgery and no significant ocular conditions impacting the visual outcome of surgery and had best-corrected visual acuity of 20/40 or better (distance or near) achieved within 90 days following the cataract surgery.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="21" OrdBy="90" ID="568" Name="Rationale" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The only reason to perform cataract surgery (other than for a limited set of medical indications) is to improve a patient's vision and associated functioning. The use of a 20/40 visual acuity threshold is based on several considerations. First, it is the level for unrestricted operation of a motor vehicle in the United States (U.S). Second, it has been consistently used by the U.S. Food and Drug Administration (FDA) in its assessment for approval of intraocular lens (IOL) and other vision devices. Third, it is the literature standard to denote success in cataract surgery. Fourth, work by West et al. (1997) in the Salisbury Eye Study, suggests that 20/40 is a useful threshold for 50th percentile functioning for several vision-related tasks.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Most patients achieve excellent visual acuity after cataract surgery (20/40 or better). This outcome is achieved consistently through careful attention through the accurate measurement of axial length and corneal power and the appropriate selection of an IOL power calculation formula. As such, it reflects the care and diligence with which the surgery is assessed, planned and executed. Failure to achieve this after surgery in eyes without comorbid ocular conditions that would impact the success of the surgery would reflect care that should be assessed for opportunities for improvement.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The exclusion of patients with other ocular and systemic conditions known to increase the risk of an adverse outcome reflects the findings of the two published prediction rule papers for cataract surgery outcomes, by Mangione et al. (1995) and Steinberg et al. (1994). In both papers, the presence of comorbid glaucoma and macular degeneration negatively impacted the likelihood of successful outcomes of surgery. Further, exclusion of eyes with ocular conditions that could impact the success of the surgery would NOT eliminate the large majority of eyes undergoing surgery while also minimizing the potential adverse selection that might otherwise occur relative to those patients with the most complex situations who might benefit the most from having surgery to maximize their remaining vision.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The following clinical recommendation statements are quoted &lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;verbatim&lt;/span&gt; from the referenced clinical guidelines and represent the evidence base for the measure&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is an outcome measure. As such, there are no statements in the guideline specific to this measurement topic.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3500" OrdBy="100" ID="569" Name="Evidence for Rationale" Type="citation">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;American Medical Association-convened Physician Consortium for Performance Improvement® (PCPI®), American Academy of Ophthalmology. Eye care I and II performance measurement sets. Chicago (IL): American Medical Association (AMA); 2015 Aug. 55 p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Mangione CM, Orav EJ, Lawrence MG, Phillips RS, Seddon JM, Goldman L. Prediction of visual function after cataract surgery. A prospectively validated model. Arch Ophthalmol. 1995 Oct;113(10):1305-11. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=7575265&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Steinberg EP, Tielsch JM, Schein OD, Javitt JC, Sharkey P, Cassard SD, Legro MW, Diener-West M, Bass EB, Damiano AM. National study of cataract surgery outcomes. Variation in 4-month postoperative outcomes as reflected in multiple outcome measures. Ophthalmology. 1994 Jun;101(6):1131-40; discussion 1140-1. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=8008355&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;West SK, Munoz B, Rubin GS, Schein OD, Bandeen-Roche K, Zeger S, German S, Fried LP. Function and visual impairment in a population-based study of older adults. The SEE project. Salisbury Eye Evaluation. Invest Ophthalmol Vis Sci. 1997 Jan;38(1):72-82. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=9008632&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3022" OrdBy="110" ID="570" Name="Primary Health Components" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cataract surgery; best-corrected visual acuity of 20/40&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="23" OrdBy="120" ID="571" Name="Denominator Description" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;All patients aged 18 years and older who had cataract surgery (see the related &quot;Denominator Inclusions/Exclusions&quot; field)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="24" OrdBy="130" ID="572" Name="Numerator Description" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Patients who had best-corrected visual acuity of 20/40 or better (distance or near) achieved within 90 days following cataract surgery&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="573" OrdBy="140" Name="Evidence Supporting the Measure">
    <Field FieldID="3027" OrdBy="150" ID="574" Name="Type of Evidence Supporting the Criterion of Quality for the Measure" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="A clinical practice guideline or other peer-reviewed synthesis of the clinical research evidence" />
      <FieldValue Value="One or more research studies published in a National Library of Medicine (NLM) indexed, peer-reviewed journal" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3501" OrdBy="160" ID="575" Name="Additional Information Supporting Need for the Measure" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Opportunity for Improvement&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is an outcome of surgery indicator of direct relevance to patients and referring providers. The available evidence suggests that cataract surgery achieves this in between 86% and 98% of surgeries in eyes without comorbid ocular conditions. While small, the volume of cataract surgery in the United States (U.S.) of over 2.8 million surgeries suggests that the impact could affect more than 100,000 patients per year. Because of the exclusion of comorbid ocular conditions, one would expect performance on this indicator to be as high as possible, with significantly lower rates suggestive of opportunities for improvement. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cataract surgery successfully restores vision in the majority of people who have the procedure. The ASCRS National Cataract Database reported that at 3 months postoperatively, 85.5% of all patients had a 20/40 or better best-corrected visual acuity, 57.2% of patients had 20/25 or better postoperative best-corrected visual acuity, and 74.6% of patients were within +/- 1.0 D of target spherical equivalent. Based on 5,788 responses, the mean visual function index score at 3 months postoperatively was 70.3% compared with 55.0% preoperatively (American Academy of Ophthalmology [AAO], 2011).&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Additionally, data from a UK multi-center Cataract National Dataset found a postoperative visual acuity of 6/12 (20/40) or better was achieved for 94.7% of eyes with no co-pathologies and in 79.9% of eyes with one or more copathologies (Jaycock et al., 2009).&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A rate of 85.5% to 94.7% of patients achieving a 20/40 or better visual acuity in the context of approximately 3 million cataract surgeries in the U.S. annually would mean that between 160,000 to 435,000 individuals would not achieve a 20/40 or better visual acuity which suggests an opportunity for improvement. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3502" OrdBy="170" ID="576" Name="Evidence for Additional Information Supporting Need for the Measure" Type="citation">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;American Academy of Ophthalmology Cataract and Anterior Segment Panel. Cataract in the adult eye. San Francisco (CA): American Academy of Ophthalmology (AAO); 2011. 89 p.  [855 references]&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;American Medical Association-convened Physician Consortium for Performance Improvement® (PCPI®), American Academy of Ophthalmology. Eye care I and II performance measurement sets. Chicago (IL): American Medical Association (AMA); 2015 Aug. 55 p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Jaycock P, Johnston RL, Taylor H, Adams M, Tole DM, Galloway P, Canning C, Sparrow JM, UK EPR user group. The Cataract National Dataset electronic multi-centre audit of 55,567 operations: updating benchmark standards of care in the United Kingdom and internationally. Eye (Lond). 2009 Jan;23(1):38-49. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=18034196&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3072" OrdBy="180" ID="577" Name="Extent of Measure Testing" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The American Medical Association (AMA)-convened Physician Consortium for Performance Improvement (PCPI) collaborated on several measure testing projects in 2012 and 2015 to ensure the Cataracts &amp;ndash; Complications within 30 Days Following Cataracts Surgery measure and Cataracts &amp;ndash; 20/40 or Better Visual Acuity within 90 Days Following Cataracts Surgery measures are reliable and evaluated for accuracy of the measure numerator, denominator and exception case identification. The testing projects were conducted utilizing electronic health record data and registry data. Parallel forms reliability and signal-to-noise reliability were tested. One site participated in the parallel forms testing of the measures. Site A was a physician-owned multi-location suburban practice in a large Midwestern city with four physicians. Signal-to-noise reliability was assessed using 2013 data acquired from the Centers for Medicare &amp;amp; Medicaid Services Physician Quality Reporting System Group Practice Reporting Option (GPRO) database. An analysis of the measure exclusions was conducted using 2013 Medicare 5% Beneficiary claims data.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cataracts &amp;ndash; 20/40 or Better Visual Acuity within 90 Days Following Cataracts Surgery&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Parallel Forms Reliability Testing (Site A)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There were 149 observations from one site used for the denominator analysis. The kappa statistic value was found to be non-calculable resulting from the inability to divide by zero in the statistic formula when only one response was used. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Of the 149 observations that were initially selected, 149 observations met the criteria for inclusion in the numerator analysis. The kappa statistic value of 0.85 demonstrates almost perfect agreement between the automated report and reviewer. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Reliability: N, % Agreement, Kappa (95% Confidence Interval)&lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Denominator: 149, 100.0%, Non-Calculable* (Non-Calculable, Non-Calculable)* &lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Numerator: 149, 92.6%, 0.85 (0.76, 0.93)&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;*Cannot calculate kappa statistics when only one response (Yes/Yes) was used, as this causes a divide-by-zero error in the statistic formula.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Signal-to-Noise Reliability Testing&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For this measure, the reliability at the minimum level of quality reporting events (10) was 0.47. The average number of quality reporting events for physicians included is 55.3. The reliability at the average number of quality reporting events was 0.83. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This measure has poor reliability when evaluated at the minimum level of quality reporting events and high reliability at the average number of quality events. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Exclusions Analysis&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Medicare 5% Beneficiary claims data sample, there were 46,715 unique individuals who had a cataract procedure in the first nine months of 2013 with a total of 70,773 procedures. Using the criteria for the measure, 17,735 (25.1%) procedures had a cataract measure exclusion associated with the procedure. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3007" OrdBy="190" ID="578" Name="Evidence for Extent of Measure Testing" Type="citation">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;American Medical Association-convened Physician Consortium for Performance Improvement® (PCPI®), American Academy of Ophthalmology. Eye care I and II performance measurement sets. Chicago (IL): American Medical Association (AMA); 2015 Aug. 55 p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="580" OrdBy="210" Name="State of Use of the Measure">
    <Field FieldID="3029" OrdBy="220" ID="581" Name="State of Use" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Current routine use" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3030" OrdBy="230" ID="582" Name="Current Use" Type="picklist-choice-3">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="583" OrdBy="240" Name="Application of the Measure in its Current Use">
    <Field FieldID="3031" OrdBy="250" ID="584" Name="Measurement Setting" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="Ambulatory/Office-based Care" />
      <FieldValue Value="Ambulatory Procedure/Imaging Center" />
      <FieldValue Value="Hospital Outpatient" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3032" OrdBy="260" ID="585" Name="Professionals Involved in Delivery of Health Services" Type="picklist-choice-3">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3033" OrdBy="270" ID="586" Name="Least Aggregated Level of Services Delivery Addressed" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Individual Clinicians or Public Health Professionals" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3505" OrdBy="280" ID="587" Name="Statement of Acceptable Minimum Sample Size" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Does not apply to this measure" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="41" OrdBy="290" ID="588" Name="Target Population Age" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Age greater than or equal to 18 years&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="42" OrdBy="300" ID="589" Name="Target Population Gender" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Either male or female" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="660" OrdBy="310" Name="National Strategy for Quality Improvement in Health Care">
    <Field FieldID="3522" OrdBy="320" ID="661" Name="National Quality Strategy Aim" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Better Care&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3525" OrdBy="330" ID="662" Name="National Quality Strategy Priority" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Prevention and Treatment of Leading Causes of Mortality&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="590" OrdBy="340" Name="Institute of Medicine (IOM) National Health Care Quality Report Categories">
    <Field FieldID="3163" OrdBy="350" ID="591" Name="IOM Care Need" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="Getting Better" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3164" OrdBy="360" ID="592" Name="IOM Domain" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="Effectiveness" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="593" OrdBy="370" Name="Data Collection for the Measure">
    <Field FieldID="3506" OrdBy="380" ID="594" Name="Case Finding Period" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3054" OrdBy="390" ID="595" Name="Denominator Sampling Frame" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Patients associated with provider" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3057" OrdBy="400" ID="598" Name="Denominator (Index) Event or Characteristic" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="Clinical Condition" />
      <FieldValue Value="Patient/Individual (Consumer) Characteristic" />
      <FieldValue Value="Therapeutic Intervention" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3058" OrdBy="410" ID="599" Name="Denominator Time Window" Type="picklist-choice-3">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="55" OrdBy="420" ID="596" Name="Denominator Inclusions/Exclusions" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;All patients aged 18 years and older who had cataract surgery &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: Refer to the original measure documentation for administrative codes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Patients with significant ocular conditions impacting the visual outcome of surgery &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exceptions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;None&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3507" OrdBy="430" ID="597" Name="Exclusions/Exceptions" Type="picklist-choice-4">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="59" OrdBy="440" ID="600" Name="Numerator Inclusions/Exclusions" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Patients who had best-corrected visual acuity of 20/40 or better (distance or near) achieved within 90 days following cataract surgery&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: Refer to the original measure documentation for administrative codes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3061" OrdBy="450" ID="601" Name="Numerator Search Strategy" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Fixed time period or point in time" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3062" OrdBy="460" ID="602" Name="Data Source" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Electronic health/medical record" />
      <FieldValue Value="Registry data" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3065" OrdBy="470" ID="603" Name="Type of Health State" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Clinically Diagnosed Condition" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3066" OrdBy="480" ID="604" Name="Instruments Used and/or Associated with the Measure" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="605" OrdBy="490" Name="Computation of the Measure">
    <Field FieldID="3508" OrdBy="500" ID="606" Name="Measure Specifies Disaggregation" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Does not apply to this measure" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3067" OrdBy="520" ID="608" Name="Scoring" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Rate/Proportion" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3068" OrdBy="530" ID="609" Name="Interpretation of Score" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Desired value is a higher score" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3090" OrdBy="540" ID="610" Name="Allowance for Patient or Population Factors" Type="picklist-choice-3">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3070" OrdBy="560" ID="612" Name="Standard of Comparison" Type="picklist-choice-3">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="615" OrdBy="590" Name="Identifying Information">
    <Field FieldID="73" OrdBy="600" ID="616" Name="Original Title" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Measure #4: cataracts: 20/40 or better visual acuity within 90 days following cataract surgery.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="74" OrdBy="610" ID="617" Name="Measure Collection Name" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="AMA/PCPI Eye Care I and II Performance Measurement Set" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="16" OrdBy="650" ID="621" Name="Submitter" Type="orglist">
      <FieldValue Value="American Medical Association - Medical Specialty Society" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="17" OrdBy="660" ID="622" Name="Developer" Type="orglist-p">
      <FieldValue Value="American Academy of Ophthalmology - Medical Specialty Society" />
      <FieldValue Value="Physician Consortium for Performance Improvement® - Clinical Specialty Collaboration" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="79" OrdBy="670" ID="623" Name="Funding Source(s)" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="80" OrdBy="680" ID="624" Name="Composition of the Group that Developed the Measure" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Eye Care II Measure Development Work Group&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;*&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Work Group Members&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Paul P. Lee, MD, JD (&lt;em&gt;Co-chair&lt;/em&gt;) (ophthalmologist) &lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Jinnet B. Fowles, PhD (&lt;em&gt;Co-chair&lt;/em&gt;) (methodologist)&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Non-surgical Management Subgroup&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Richard L. Abbott, MD (ophthalmologist) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Lloyd P. Aiello, MD, PhD (ophthalmologist) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Murray Fingeret, OD (optometrist) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Andrea Gelzer, MD, MS, FACP (health plan) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Mathew MacCumber, MD (ophthalmologist) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Mildred M. G. Olivier, MD (ophthalmologist) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Marcus G. Piccolo, OD (optometrist) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Sam J. W. Romeo, MD, MBA (family practice) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Surgical Management Subgroup&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Priscilla P. Arnold, MD (ophthalmologist) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Andrea Gelzer, MD, MS, FACP (health plan) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Richard Hellman, MD, FACP, FACE (endocrinologist) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Leon W. Herndon, MD (ophthalmologist) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Jeffrey S. Karlik, MD (ophthalmologist) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;James L. Rosenzweig, MD, FACE (endocrinologist) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;John T. Thompson, MD (ophthalmologist) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Work Group Staff&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Centers for Medicare &amp;amp; Medicaid Services&lt;/em&gt;: Susan Nedza, MD, MBA, FACEP; Sylvia Publ, MBA, RHIA &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;American Academy of Ophthalmology&lt;/em&gt;: Flora Lum, MD &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Facilitators&lt;/em&gt;: Timothy F. Kresowik, MD; Rebecca A. Kresowik&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;National Committee for Quality Assurance&lt;/em&gt;: Donna Pillittere; Phil Renner, MBA&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;American Medical Association (AMA)-convened Physician Consortium for Performance Improvement&lt;sup&gt;&amp;reg;&lt;/sup&gt;(PCPI&lt;sup&gt;&amp;reg;&lt;/sup&gt;)&lt;/em&gt;: Karen S. Kmetik, PhD; Heidi Bossley, MSN, MBA; Stephen Havas, MD, MPH, MS &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;*The composition and affiliations of the work group members are listed as originally convened in 2006 and are not up to date.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="81" OrdBy="690" ID="625" Name="Financial Disclosures/Other Potential Conflicts of Interest" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Conflicts, if any, are disclosed in accordance with the Physician Consortium for Performance Improvement&amp;reg; conflict of interest policy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="82" OrdBy="700" ID="626" Name="Endorser" Type="orglist">
      <FieldValue Value="National Quality Forum - None" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3091" OrdBy="705" ID="696" Name="NQF Number" Type="plain-text">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3510" OrdBy="710" ID="627" Name="Date of Endorsement" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;2015 Nov 4&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3083" OrdBy="720" ID="628" Name="Measure Initiative(s)" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Physician Quality Reporting System" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="19" OrdBy="730" ID="629" Name="Adaptation" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This measure was not adapted from another source.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3086" OrdBy="740" ID="630" Name="Date of Most Current Version in NQMC" Type="date">
      <FieldValue Value="2015 Aug" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3511" OrdBy="750" ID="631" Name="Measure Maintenance" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3512" OrdBy="760" ID="632" Name="Date of Next Anticipated Revision" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="20" OrdBy="770" ID="633" Name="Measure Status" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the current release of the measure.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This measure updates a previous version: American Academy of Ophthalmology, Physician Consortium for Performance Improvement&amp;reg;, National Committee for Quality Assurance. Eye care physician performance measurement set. Chicago (IL): American Medical Association (AMA); 2010 Sep. 35 p.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="14" OrdBy="780" ID="634" Name="Measure Availability" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Source available from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ama-assn.org/ama/pub/physician-resources/physician-consortium-performance-improvement/pcpi-measures.page?&quot; title=&quot;AMA-PCPI Web site&quot;&gt;American Medical Association (AMA)-convened Physician Consortium for Performance Improvement&lt;sup&gt;&amp;reg;&lt;/sup&gt; Web site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For more information, contact AMA at 330 N. Wabash Avenue Suite 39300, Chicago, Ill. 60611; Phone: 312-800-621-8335; Fax: 312-464-5706; E-mail: &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:cqi@ama-assn.org&quot;&gt;cqi@ama-assn.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="87" OrdBy="800" ID="636" Name="NQMC Status" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This NQMC summary was completed by ECRI Institute on February 13, 2008. The information was verified by the measure developer on April 22, 2008.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This NQMC summary was retrofitted into the new template on June 3, 2011.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This NQMC summary was edited by ECRI Institute on April 27, 2012.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This NQMC summary was updated by ECRI Institute on December 3, 2015. The information was verified by the measure developer on January 7, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="88" OrdBy="810" ID="637" Name="Copyright Statement" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This NQMC summary is based on the original measure, which is subject to the measure developer's copyright restrictions. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Complete Physician Performance Measurement Sets (PPMS) are published by the American Medical Association, on behalf of the Physician Consortium for Performance Improvement. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For more information, contact the American Medical Association, Clinical Performance Evaluation, 330 N. Wabash Ave, Chicago, IL 60611. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="641" OrdBy="850" Name="Production">
    <Field FieldID="1" OrdBy="1366" ID="562" Name="Source(s)" Type="citation">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;American Medical Association-convened Physician Consortium for Performance Improvement® (PCPI®), American Academy of Ophthalmology. Eye care I and II performance measurement sets. Chicago (IL): American Medical Association (AMA); 2015 Aug. 55 p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="99999" OrdBy="99999" Name="Disclaimer">
    <Field FieldID="99999" OrdBy="99999" ID="99999" Name="NQMC Disclaimer" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;p&gt;The National Quality Measures Clearinghouse™ (NQMC) does not develop, produce, approve, or endorse the measures represented on this site.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;All measures summarized by NQMC and hosted on our site are produced under the auspices of medical specialty societies, relevant professional associations, public and private organizations, other government agencies, health care organizations or plans, individuals, and similar entities.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Measures represented on the NQMC Web site are submitted by measure developers, and are screened solely to determine that they meet the &lt;a href=&quot;/help-and-about/summaries/inclusion-criteria&quot;&gt;NQMC Inclusion Criteria&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;NQMC, AHRQ, and its contractor ECRI Institute make no warranties concerning the content or its reliability and/or validity of the quality measures and related materials represented on this site. Moreover, the views and opinions of developers or authors of measures represented on this site do not necessarily state or reflect those of NQMC, AHRQ, or its contractor, ECRI Institute, and inclusion or hosting of measures in NQMC may not be used for advertising or commercial endorsement purposes.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Readers with questions regarding measure content are directed to contact the measure developer.&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
</Version>