<Version>
  <xmlSource>This XML content was developed by AHRQ's contractor ECRI Institute for the National Quality Measures Clearinghouse (NQMC).</xmlSource>
  <Section SecID="560" OrdBy="10" Name="General">
    <Field FieldID="11" OrdBy="20" ID="561" Name="Title" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_title&quot;&gt;Heart failure in adults: percentage of patients with heart failure diagnosis and LVSD who at the last clinic visit met the following (if eligible): prescribed or were on ACEI/ARB, prescribed or were on beta-blocker therapy, and a non-smoker.&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="1" OrdBy="30" ID="562" Name="Source(s)" Type="citation">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Pinkerman C, Sander P, Breeding JE, Brink D, Curtis R, Hayes R, Ojha A, Pandita D, Raikar S, Setterlund L, Sule O, Turner A. Heart failure in adults. Bloomington (MN): Institute for Clinical Systems Improvement (ICSI); 2013 Jul. 94 p.  [190 references]&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="563" OrdBy="40" Name="Measure Domain">
    <Field FieldID="3025" OrdBy="50" ID="564" Name="Primary Measure Domain" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Clinical Quality Measures: Process" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3026" OrdBy="60" ID="565" Name="Secondary Measure Domain" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Does not apply to this measure" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="566" OrdBy="70" Name="Brief Abstract">
    <Field FieldID="34" OrdBy="80" ID="567" Name="Description" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This measure is used to assess the percentage of patients age 18 years and older with heart failure diagnosis and left ventricular systolic dysfunction (LVSD) who at the last clinic visit met the following (if eligible): prescribed or were on angiotensin-converting enzyme inhibitor (ACEI)/angiotensin receptor blocker (ARB), prescribed or were on beta-blocker therapy, and a non-smoker. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="21" OrdBy="90" ID="568" Name="Rationale" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The priority aim addressed by this measure is to increase the rate of heart failure patients age 18 years and older who receive optimum evidence-based pharmacologic treatment.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Heart failure is a major health problem in the United States (U.S.), and the incidence of the disease is increasing. The overall estimated 2004 prevalence of heart failure in adults age 20 and older in the U.S. was 5.2 million, with it being equally distributed among men and women.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The cornerstone of treatment of systolic dysfunction is the use of beta-blockers and angiotensin-converting enzyme (ACE) inhibitors. Certain beta-blocking medications have been shown to improve clinical symptoms and ventricular function in patients with systolic dysfunction. Beta-blockers decrease hospitalizations and mortality, and have objective beneficial effect on measures of exercise duration.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;ACE inhibitors prolong life in patients with heart failure symptoms and ejection fraction (EF) less than 35% and reduce symptom development in asymptomatic patients with EF less than 35%. There is also a mortality benefit in the use of ACE inhibitors in patients with recent myocardial infarction and asymptomatic EF less than 40%. ACE inhibitors slow disease progression, improve exercise capacity and decrease hospitalizations and mortality. Angiotensin receptor blockers (ARBs) are recommended for patients intolerant of ACE inhibitors.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3500" OrdBy="100" ID="569" Name="Evidence for Rationale" Type="citation">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Andersson B, Hamm C, Persson S, Wikstrom G, Sinagra G, Hjalmarson A, Waagstein F. Improved exercise hemodynamic status in dilated cardiomyopathy after beta-adrenergic blockade treatment. J Am Coll Cardiol. 1994 May;23(6):1397-404. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=8176099&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Bristow MR, Gilbert EM, Abraham WT, Adams KF, Fowler MB, Hershberger RE, Kubo SH, Narahara KA, Ingersoll H, Krueger S, Young S, Shusterman N. Carvedilol produces dose-related improvements in left ventricular function and survival in subjects with chronic heart failure. MOCHA Investigators. Circulation. 1996 Dec 1;94(11):2807-16. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=8941106&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Comparative effects of therapy with captopril and digoxin in patients with mild to moderate heart failure. The Captopril-Digoxin Multicenter Research Group. JAMA. 1988 Jan 22-29;259(4):539-44. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=2447297&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;CONSENSUS Trial Study Group. Effects of enalapril on mortality in severe congestive heart failure. Results of the Cooperative North Scandinavian Enalapril Survival Study (CONSENSUS). N Engl J Med. 1987 Jun 4;316(23):1429-35. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=2883575&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Effect of enalapril on mortality and the development of heart failure in asymptomatic patients with reduced left ventricular ejection fractions. The SOLVD Investigators. N Engl J Med. 1992 Sep 3;327(10):685-91. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=1463530&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Effect of metoprolol CR/XL in chronic heart failure: Metoprolol CR/XL Randomised Intervention Trial in Congestive Heart Failure (MERIT-HF). Lancet. 1999 Jun 12;353(9169):2001-7. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=10376614&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Hunt SA, Abraham WT, Chin MH, Feldman AM, Francis GS, Ganiats TG, Jessup M, Konstam MA, Mancini DM, Michl K, Oates JA, Rahko PS, Silver MA, Stevenson LW, Yancy CW, American College of Cardiology Foundation, American Heart Association. 2009 focused update incorporated into the ACC/AHA 2005 guidelines for the diagnosis and management of heart failure in adults [trunc]. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2009 Apr 14;53(15):e1-e90. [810 references] &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=19358937&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey 1999 to 2004 [NHANES] Data 1999-2004. [internet]. Hyattsville (MD): National Center for Health Statistics; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Packer M, Bristow MR, Cohn JN, Colucci WS, Fowler MB, Gilbert EM, Shusterman NH. The effect of carvedilol on morbidity and mortality in patients with chronic heart failure. U.S. Carvedilol Heart Failure Study Group. N Engl J Med. 1996 May 23;334(21):1349-55. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=8614419&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Packer M, Coats AJ, Fowler MB, Katus HA, Krum H, Mohacsi P, Rouleau JL, Tendera M, Castaigne A, Roecker EB, Schultz MK, DeMets DL. Effect of carvedilol on survival in severe chronic heart failure. N Engl J Med. 2001 May 31;344(22):1651-8. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=11386263&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Packer M, Fowler MB, Roecker EB, Coats AJ, Katus HA, Krum H, Mohacsi P, Rouleau JL, Tendera M, Staiger C, Holcslaw TL, Amann-Zalan I, DeMets DL. Effect of carvedilol on the morbidity of patients with severe chronic heart failure: results of the carvedilol prospective randomized cumulative survival (COPERNICUS) study. Circulation. 2002 Oct 22;106(17):2194-9. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=12390947&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Packer M, Poole-Wilson PA, Armstrong PW, Cleland JG, Horowitz JD, Massie BM, Ryden L, Thygesen K, Uretsky BF. Comparative effects of low and high doses of the angiotensin-converting enzyme inhibitor, lisinopril, on morbidity and mortality in chronic heart failure. ATLAS Study Group. Circulation. 1999 Dec 7;100(23):2312-8. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=10587334&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Pfeffer MA, Braunwald E, Moye LA, Basta L, Brown EJ Jr, Cuddy TE, Davis BR, Geltman EM, Goldman S, Flaker GC, et al. Effect of captopril on mortality and morbidity in patients with left ventricular dysfunction after myocardial infarction. Results of the survival and ventricular enlargement trial. The SAVE Investigators. N Engl J Med. 1992 Sep 3;327(10):669-77. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=1386652&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Pinkerman C, Sander P, Breeding JE, Brink D, Curtis R, Hayes R, Ojha A, Pandita D, Raikar S, Setterlund L, Sule O, Turner A. Heart failure in adults. Bloomington (MN): Institute for Clinical Systems Improvement (ICSI); 2013 Jul. 94 p.  [190 references]&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Poole-Wilson PA, Swedberg K, Cleland JG, Di Lenarda A, Hanrath P, Komajda M, Lubsen J, Lutiger B, Metra M, Remme WJ, Torp-Pedersen C, Scherhag A, Skene A. Comparison of carvedilol and metoprolol on clinical outcomes in patients with chronic heart failure in the Carvedilol Or Metoprolol European Trial (COMET): randomised controlled trial. Lancet. 2003 Jul 5;362(9377):7-13. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=12853193&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Roger VL, Weston SA, Redfield MM, Hellermann-Homan JP, Killian J, Yawn BP, Jacobsen SJ. Trends in heart failure incidence and survival in a community-based population. JAMA. 2004 Jul 21;292(3):344-50. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=15265849&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;SOLVD Investigators. Effect of enalapril on survival in patients with reduced left ventricular ejection fractions and congestive heart failure. N Engl J Med. 1991 Aug 1;325(5):293-302. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=2057034&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;The Cardiac Insufficiency Bisoprolol Study II (CIBIS-II): a randomised trial. Lancet. 1999 Jan 2;353(9146):9-13. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=10023943&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3022" OrdBy="110" ID="570" Name="Primary Health Components" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Heart failure; left ventricular systolic dysfunction (LVSD); angiotensin-converting enzyme inhibitor (ACEI); angiotensin receptor blocker (ARB); beta-blocker; smoking status&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="23" OrdBy="120" ID="571" Name="Denominator Description" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Number of patients age 18 years and older with a diagnosis of heart failure and left ventricular systolic dysfunction (LVSD) (see the related &quot;Denominator Inclusions/Exclusions&quot; field)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="24" OrdBy="130" ID="572" Name="Numerator Description" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Number of patients 18 years and older with a diagnosis of heart failure and left ventricular systolic dysfunction (LVSD) who were prescribed or were taking angiotensin-converting enzyme inhibitor (ACEI)/angiotensin receptor blocker (ARB), beta-blocker therapy and a non-smoker&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="573" OrdBy="140" Name="Evidence Supporting the Measure">
    <Field FieldID="3027" OrdBy="150" ID="574" Name="Type of Evidence Supporting the Criterion of Quality for the Measure" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="A clinical practice guideline or other peer-reviewed synthesis of the clinical research evidence" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3501" OrdBy="160" ID="575" Name="Additional Information Supporting Need for the Measure" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;In age 20 to 39, the incidence of heart failure is 0.3% of the population in men and 0.2% of the population in women. In the ages 40s and 50s, the incidence is 2% in men and 1.5% in women. In the 60 to 79 age group, the incidence is 7.2% in men and 5.2% in women. However, once reaching age 80, the incidence of heart failure is higher in women, with 11.6% of men and 12.4% of women. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Seventy-five percent of heart failure cases have antecedent hypertension in that the lifetime risk for heart failure doubles for people with blood pressure greater than 160/90 versus those with blood pressure less than 140/90. A community-based cohort study conducted in Olmsted County, Minnesota, showed that the incidence of heart failure (International Classification of Diseases, Ninth Revision [ICD9]-428) has not declined during the past two decades, but survival after onset has increased overall, with less improvement among women and elderly persons.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3502" OrdBy="170" ID="576" Name="Evidence for Additional Information Supporting Need for the Measure" Type="citation">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey 1999 to 2004 [NHANES] Data 1999-2004. [internet]. Hyattsville (MD): National Center for Health Statistics; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Pinkerman C, Sander P, Breeding JE, Brink D, Curtis R, Hayes R, Ojha A, Pandita D, Raikar S, Setterlund L, Sule O, Turner A. Heart failure in adults. Bloomington (MN): Institute for Clinical Systems Improvement (ICSI); 2013 Jul. 94 p.  [190 references]&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Roger VL, Weston SA, Redfield MM, Hellermann-Homan JP, Killian J, Yawn BP, Jacobsen SJ. Trends in heart failure incidence and survival in a community-based population. JAMA. 2004 Jul 21;292(3):344-50. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=15265849&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3072" OrdBy="180" ID="577" Name="Extent of Measure Testing" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="37" OrdBy="200" ID="579" Name="National Guideline Clearinghouse Link" Type="xref">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.guideline.gov/content.aspx?id=47030&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Heart failure in adults.&lt;/a&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="580" OrdBy="210" Name="State of Use of the Measure">
    <Field FieldID="3029" OrdBy="220" ID="581" Name="State of Use" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Current routine use" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3030" OrdBy="230" ID="582" Name="Current Use" Type="picklist-choice-3">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="583" OrdBy="240" Name="Application of the Measure in its Current Use">
    <Field FieldID="3031" OrdBy="250" ID="584" Name="Measurement Setting" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="Ambulatory/Office-based Care" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3032" OrdBy="260" ID="585" Name="Professionals Involved in Delivery of Health Services" Type="picklist-choice-3">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3033" OrdBy="270" ID="586" Name="Least Aggregated Level of Services Delivery Addressed" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Clinical Practice or Public Health Sites" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3505" OrdBy="280" ID="587" Name="Statement of Acceptable Minimum Sample Size" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Unspecified" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="41" OrdBy="290" ID="588" Name="Target Population Age" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Age greater than or equal to 18 years&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="42" OrdBy="300" ID="589" Name="Target Population Gender" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Either male or female" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="660" OrdBy="310" Name="National Strategy for Quality Improvement in Health Care">
    <Field FieldID="3522" OrdBy="320" ID="661" Name="National Quality Strategy Aim" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Better Care&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3525" OrdBy="330" ID="662" Name="National Quality Strategy Priority" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Prevention and Treatment of Leading Causes of Mortality&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="590" OrdBy="340" Name="Institute of Medicine (IOM) National Health Care Quality Report Categories">
    <Field FieldID="3163" OrdBy="350" ID="591" Name="IOM Care Need" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="Living with Illness" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3164" OrdBy="360" ID="592" Name="IOM Domain" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="Effectiveness" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="593" OrdBy="370" Name="Data Collection for the Measure">
    <Field FieldID="3506" OrdBy="380" ID="594" Name="Case Finding Period" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The time frame pertaining to data collection is quarterly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3054" OrdBy="390" ID="595" Name="Denominator Sampling Frame" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Patients associated with provider" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3057" OrdBy="400" ID="598" Name="Denominator (Index) Event or Characteristic" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="Clinical Condition" />
      <FieldValue Value="Encounter" />
      <FieldValue Value="Patient/Individual (Consumer) Characteristic" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3058" OrdBy="410" ID="599" Name="Denominator Time Window" Type="picklist-choice-3">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="55" OrdBy="420" ID="596" Name="Denominator Inclusions/Exclusions" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Number of patients age 18 years and older with a diagnosis of heart failure* and left ventricular systolic dysfunction (LVSD)**&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data Collection&lt;/strong&gt;: Query electronic medical records (EMR) for clinic visits within the last 12 months for patients age 18 years and older with heart failure diagnosis and LVSD. Determine if patients meet any exclusion criteria. For patients who meet exclusion criteria, exclude them from the analysis.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;*International Classification of Diseases, Ninth Revision (ICD-9) codes: 428.0, 428.1, 428.20, 428.21, 428.22, 428.23, 428.40, 428.41, 428.42, 428.43, 428.9. (Refer to the table &quot;Descriptions of ICD-9 Codes&quot; in the original measure documentation for code descriptions.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;**LVSD is defined quantitatively as left ventricular ejection fraction less than 40%, and qualitatively as moderately or severely depressed left ventricular systolic function.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Patients less than 18 years of age &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Patients with potential contraindications or other reasons for the provider to not prescribe an angiotensin-converting enzyme inhibitor (ACEI)/angiotensin receptor blocker (ARB) and/or beta-blocker (refer to the original measure documentation for a complete list) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Patients transferred to another care system &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Patients with devices &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Deceased patients &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3507" OrdBy="430" ID="597" Name="Exclusions/Exceptions" Type="picklist-choice-4">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="59" OrdBy="440" ID="600" Name="Numerator Inclusions/Exclusions" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Number of patients 18 years and older with a diagnosis of heart failure and left ventricular systolic dysfunction (LVSD) who were prescribed or were taking angiotensin-converting enzyme inhibitor (ACEI)/angiotensin receptor blocker (ARB), beta-blocker therapy and a non-smoker&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3061" OrdBy="450" ID="601" Name="Numerator Search Strategy" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Encounter" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3062" OrdBy="460" ID="602" Name="Data Source" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Administrative clinical data" />
      <FieldValue Value="Electronic health/medical record" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3065" OrdBy="470" ID="603" Name="Type of Health State" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Does not apply to this measure" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3066" OrdBy="480" ID="604" Name="Instruments Used and/or Associated with the Measure" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="605" OrdBy="490" Name="Computation of the Measure">
    <Field FieldID="3508" OrdBy="500" ID="606" Name="Measure Specifies Disaggregation" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Does not apply to this measure" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3067" OrdBy="520" ID="608" Name="Scoring" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Rate/Proportion" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3068" OrdBy="530" ID="609" Name="Interpretation of Score" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Desired value is a higher score" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3090" OrdBy="540" ID="610" Name="Allowance for Patient or Population Factors" Type="picklist-choice-3">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3070" OrdBy="560" ID="612" Name="Standard of Comparison" Type="picklist-choice-3">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="615" OrdBy="590" Name="Identifying Information">
    <Field FieldID="73" OrdBy="600" ID="616" Name="Original Title" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Percentage of patients with heart failure diagnosis and LVSD who at the last clinic visit met the following (if eligible): prescribed or were on ACEI/ARB, prescribed or were on beta-blocker therapy, and a non-smoker. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="74" OrdBy="610" ID="617" Name="Measure Collection Name" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="Heart Failure in Adults" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="16" OrdBy="650" ID="621" Name="Submitter" Type="orglist">
      <FieldValue Value="Institute for Clinical Systems Improvement - Nonprofit Organization" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="17" OrdBy="660" ID="622" Name="Developer" Type="orglist-p">
      <FieldValue Value="Institute for Clinical Systems Improvement - Nonprofit Organization" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="79" OrdBy="670" ID="623" Name="Funding Source(s)" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Institute for Clinical Systems Improvement's (ICSI's) work is funded by the annual dues of the member medical groups and five sponsoring health plans in Minnesota and Wisconsin.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="80" OrdBy="680" ID="624" Name="Composition of the Group that Developed the Measure" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Work Group Members&lt;/em&gt;: Charles Pinkerman, MD (&lt;em&gt;Work Group Leader&lt;/em&gt;) (Park Nicollet Health Services) (Cardiology); Paul Sander, MD (&lt;em&gt;Work Group Leader&lt;/em&gt;) (North Memorial Health Care) (Cardiology); Joshua E. Breeding, PharmD, BCPS (Fairview Health Services) (Pharmacist); Shama Raikar, MD (HealthPartners Medical Group and Regions Hospital) (Internal Medicine); Oghomwen Sule, MD (Howard Young Medical Center) (Internal Medicine); Ashok Ojha, MD (Hutchinson Medical Center) (Internal Medicine); Rochelle Curtis, PA (Park Nicollet Health Services) (Cardiology); Deepti Pandita, MD (Park Nicollet Health Services) (Internal Medicine); Angela Turner, PA-C (Park Nicollet Health Services) (Cardiology); Darin Brink, MD (University of Minnesota Physicians) (Family Medicine); Rochelle Hayes, BS (Institute for Clinical Systems Improvement) (Systems Improvement Coordinator); Linda Setterlund, MA, CPHQ (Institute for Clinical Systems Improvement) (Clinical Systems Improvement Facilitator)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="81" OrdBy="690" ID="625" Name="Financial Disclosures/Other Potential Conflicts of Interest" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Institute for Clinical Systems Improvement (ICSI) has long had a policy of transparency in declaring potential conflicting and competing interests of all individuals who participate in the development, revision and approval of ICSI guidelines and protocols. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 2010, the ICSI Conflict of Interest Review Committee was established by the Board of Directors to review all disclosures and make recommendations to the board when steps should be taken to mitigate potential conflicts of interest, including recommendations regarding removal of work group members. This committee has adopted the Institute of Medicine Conflict of Interest standards as outlined in the report Clinical Practice Guidelines We Can Trust (2011). &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Where there are work group members with identified potential conflicts, these are disclosed and discussed at the initial work group meeting. These members are expected to recuse themselves from related discussions or authorship of related recommendations, as directed by the Conflict of Interest committee or requested by the work group.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The complete ICSI policy regarding Conflicts of Interest is available at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.icsi.org/_asset/fwsfmi/coi_policyletter.pdf&quot; title=&quot;ICSI Web site&quot;&gt;ICSI Web site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclosure of Potential Conflicts of Interest&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Joshua E. Breeding, PharmD, BCPS (Work Group Member)&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Pharmacy, Fairview Health Services &lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;National, Regional, Local Committee Affiliations: None &lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Guideline Related Activities: None &lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Research Grants: None &lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Financial/Non-Financial Conflicts of Interest: None &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Darin Brink, MD (Work Group Member) &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Family Medicine, University of Minnesota Physicians &lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;National, Regional, Local Committee Affiliations: None &lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Guideline Related Activities: Colorectal Cancer Screening Guideline Work Group &lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Research Grants: None &lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Financial/Non-Financial Conflicts of Interest: None &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rochelle Curtis, PA (Work Group Member)&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Cardiology, Park Nicollet Health Services &lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;National, Regional, Local Committee Affiliations: None &lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Guideline Related Activities: None &lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Research Grants: None &lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Financial/Non-Financial Conflicts of Interest: None &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ashok Ojha, MD (Work Group Member) &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Internal Medicine, Hutchinson Medical Center &lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;National, Regional, Local Committee Affiliations: Minneapolis Heart Institute &lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Guideline Related Activities: None &lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Research Grants: None &lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Financial/Non-Financial Conflicts of Interest: None &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deepti Pandita, MD (Work Group Member)&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Internal Medicine, Park Nicollet Health Services &lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;National, Regional, Local Committee Affiliations: None &lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Guideline Related Activities: Breast Cancer Treatment Guideline Work Group &lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Research Grants: None &lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Financial/Non-Financial Conflicts of Interest: None &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Charles Pinkerman, MD (Work Group Leader) &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Cardiology, Park Nicollet Health Services &lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;National, Regional, Local Committee Affiliations: None &lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Guideline Related Activities: None &lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Research Grants: None &lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Financial/Non-Financial Conflicts of Interest: None &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shama Raikar, MD (Work Group Member)&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Internal Medicine, HealthPartners Medical Group and Regions Hospital &lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;National, Regional, Local Committee Affiliations: None &lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Guideline Related Activities: Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease &lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Research Grants: None &lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Financial/Non-Financial Conflicts of Interest: None &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Paul Sander, MD (Work Group Leader)&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Cardiology, North Memorial Health Care &lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;National, Regional, Local Committee Affiliations: None &lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Guideline Related Activities: None &lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Research Grants: None &lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Financial/Non-Financial Conflicts of Interest: None &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Oghomwen Sule, MD (Work Group Member) &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Internal Medicine, Howard Young Medical Center &lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;National, Regional, Local Committee Affiliations: None &lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Guideline Related Activities: Diagnosis and Initial Treatment of Stroke &lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Research Grants: None &lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Financial/Non-Financial Conflicts of Interest: None &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Angela Turner, PA-C (Work Group Member)&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Cardiology, Park Nicollet Health Services &lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;National, Regional, Local Committee Affiliations: None &lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Guideline Related Activities: None &lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Research Grants: None &lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Financial/Non-Financial Conflicts of Interest: None&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="19" OrdBy="730" ID="629" Name="Adaptation" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This measure was not adapted from another source.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3086" OrdBy="740" ID="630" Name="Date of Most Current Version in NQMC" Type="date">
      <FieldValue Value="2013 Jul" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3511" OrdBy="750" ID="631" Name="Measure Maintenance" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Scientific documents are revised every 12 to 24 months as indicated by changes in clinical practice and literature.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3512" OrdBy="760" ID="632" Name="Date of Next Anticipated Revision" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The next scheduled revision will occur within 24 months.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="20" OrdBy="770" ID="633" Name="Measure Status" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the current release of the measure.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This measure updates a previous version: Institute for Clinical Systems Improvement (ICSI). Heart failure in adults. Bloomington (MN): Institute for Clinical Systems Improvement (ICSI); 2011 Aug. 110 p. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The measure developer reaffirmed the currency of this measure in January 2016.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="14" OrdBy="780" ID="634" Name="Measure Availability" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Source available for purchase from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.icsi.org/guidelines__more/purchase_guidelines/&quot; title=&quot;ICSI Web site&quot;&gt;Institute for Clinical Systems Improvement (ICSI) Web site&lt;/a&gt;. Also available to ICSI members for free at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.icsi.org/guidelines__more/member_access/&quot; title=&quot;ICSI Web site&quot;&gt;ICSI Web site&lt;/a&gt; and to Minnesota health care organizations free by request at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.icsi.org/guidelines__more/minnesota_nonmember_access/&quot; title=&quot;ICSI Web site&quot;&gt;ICSI Web site&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For more information, contact ICSI at 8009 34th Avenue South, Suite 1200, Bloomington, MN 55425; Phone: 952-814-7060; Fax: 952-858-9675; Web site: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.icsi.org&quot; title=&quot;ICSI Web site&quot;&gt;www.icsi.org&lt;/a&gt;; E-mail: &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:icsi.info@icsi.org&quot;&gt;icsi.info@icsi.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="87" OrdBy="800" ID="636" Name="NQMC Status" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This NQMC summary was completed by ECRI on November 29, 2006. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This NQMC summary was updated by ECRI Institute on December 16, 2007 and on July 1, 2010. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This NQMC summary was retrofitted into the new template on July 25, 2011. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This NQMC summary was updated by ECRI Institute on October 16, 2012 and again on October 14, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The information was reaffirmed by the measure developer on January 13, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="88" OrdBy="810" ID="637" Name="Copyright Statement" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This NQMC summary (abstracted Institute for Clinical Systems Improvement [ICSI] Measure) is based on the original measure, which is subject to the measure developer's copyright restrictions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The abstracted ICSI Measures contained in this Web site may be downloaded by any individual or organization. If the abstracted ICSI Measures are downloaded by an individual, the individual may not distribute copies to third parties.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If the abstracted ICSI Measures are downloaded by an organization, copies may be distributed to the organization's employees but may not be distributed outside of the organization without the prior written consent of the Institute for Clinical Systems Improvement, Inc.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;All other copyright rights in the abstracted ICSI Measures are reserved by the Institute for Clinical Systems Improvement, Inc. The Institute for Clinical Systems Improvement, Inc. assumes no liability for any adaptations or revisions or modifications made to the abstracts of the ICSI Measures.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="641" OrdBy="850" Name="Production">
    <Field FieldID="1" OrdBy="1366" ID="562" Name="Source(s)" Type="citation">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Pinkerman C, Sander P, Breeding JE, Brink D, Curtis R, Hayes R, Ojha A, Pandita D, Raikar S, Setterlund L, Sule O, Turner A. Heart failure in adults. Bloomington (MN): Institute for Clinical Systems Improvement (ICSI); 2013 Jul. 94 p.  [190 references]&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="99999" OrdBy="99999" Name="Disclaimer">
    <Field FieldID="99999" OrdBy="99999" ID="99999" Name="NQMC Disclaimer" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;p&gt;The National Quality Measures Clearinghouse™ (NQMC) does not develop, produce, approve, or endorse the measures represented on this site.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;All measures summarized by NQMC and hosted on our site are produced under the auspices of medical specialty societies, relevant professional associations, public and private organizations, other government agencies, health care organizations or plans, individuals, and similar entities.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Measures represented on the NQMC Web site are submitted by measure developers, and are screened solely to determine that they meet the &lt;a href=&quot;/help-and-about/summaries/inclusion-criteria&quot;&gt;NQMC Inclusion Criteria&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;NQMC, AHRQ, and its contractor ECRI Institute make no warranties concerning the content or its reliability and/or validity of the quality measures and related materials represented on this site. Moreover, the views and opinions of developers or authors of measures represented on this site do not necessarily state or reflect those of NQMC, AHRQ, or its contractor, ECRI Institute, and inclusion or hosting of measures in NQMC may not be used for advertising or commercial endorsement purposes.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Readers with questions regarding measure content are directed to contact the measure developer.&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
</Version>