<Version>
  <xmlSource>This XML content was developed by AHRQ's contractor ECRI Institute for the National Quality Measures Clearinghouse (NQMC).</xmlSource>
  <Section SecID="560" OrdBy="10" Name="General">
    <Field FieldID="11" OrdBy="20" ID="561" Name="Title" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_title&quot;&gt;Acute myocardial infarction (AMI): hospital-level, risk-standardized payment associated with a 30-day episode of care for AMI.&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="1" OrdBy="30" ID="562" Name="Source(s)" Type="citation">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Yale New Haven Health Services Corporation (YNHHSC), Center for Outcomes Research and Evaluation (CORE). 2017 measure updates and specifications report: hospital-level risk-standardized payment measures. Baltimore (MD): Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS); 2017 Mar. 94 p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="563" OrdBy="40" Name="Measure Domain">
    <Field FieldID="3025" OrdBy="50" ID="564" Name="Primary Measure Domain" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Related Health Care Delivery Measures: Cost" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3026" OrdBy="60" ID="565" Name="Secondary Measure Domain" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Does not apply to this measure" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="566" OrdBy="70" Name="Brief Abstract">
    <Field FieldID="34" OrdBy="80" ID="567" Name="Description" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This measure estimates a hospital-level risk-standardized payment (RSP) for an acute myocardial infarction (AMI) episode of care starting with inpatient admission to a short term acute-care hospital and extending 30 days post-admission for Medicare Fee-for-Service (FFS) patients discharged from the hospital with a principal discharge diagnosis of AMI.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Centers for Medicare &amp;amp; Medicaid Services (CMS) annually reports the measure for individuals who are 65 years and older and are Medicare Fee-for-Service (FFS) beneficiaries hospitalized in non-federal short-term acute care hospitals (including Indian Health Services hospitals) and critical access hospitals.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="21" OrdBy="90" ID="568" Name="Rationale" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Medicare spending is estimated to have been $525.0 billion in 2010 with annual growth rates projected to be 6.3% for 2013 through 2020 due to both an increase in the Medicare population as well as Medicare spending on each beneficiary (Ash &amp;amp; Byrne-Logan, 1998). Further projections anticipate an exhaustion of Medicare's Hospital Insurance Trust Fund (Part A) by 2024 (Medicare Payment Advisory Commission [MedPAC], 2012). The growth in spending is unsustainable and highlights the need to understand the value of care Medicare buys with every dollar spent. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Given the urgency of the Medicare Hospital Insurance Trust Fund and the fact that Medicare pays for 40% to 50% of hospitalizations nationally (Centers for Disease Control and Prevention [CDC], 2012), hospital costs are a natural venue in which to deconstruct payments for Medicare patients. Yet payments to hospitals are difficult to interpret in isolation. Some high-payment hospitals may have better clinical outcomes when compared with low-payment hospitals; other-high payment hospitals may not. For this reason, the value of hospital care is more clearly assessed when pairing hospital payments with hospital quality. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A measure of payments for Medicare patients to hospitals that is aligned with current quality of care measures will facilitate profiling hospital value (payments and quality). The Centers for Medicare &amp;amp; Medicaid Services (CMS) developed a measure of payments for Medicare patients that reflects differences in the management of care for patients with acute myocardial infarction (AMI) both during hospitalization and immediately post-discharge. AMI is a condition with substantial variation in costs of care and for which there are well-established publicly reported quality measures, and is therefore an ideal condition for assessing relative value for an episode of care that begins with an acute hospitalization. By focusing on one specific condition, value assessments may provide actionable feedback to hospitals and incentivize targeted improvements in care.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3500" OrdBy="100" ID="569" Name="Evidence for Rationale" Type="citation">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Ash AS, Byrne-Logan S. How well do models work? Predicting health care costs. Alexandria (VA): American Statistical Association; 1998. 8 p.  [4 references]&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC). National Hospital Discharge Survey. [internet]. Atlanta (GA): Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC); [accessed 2012 Aug 07]. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Medicare Payment Advisory Commission (MedPAC). Report to the Congress: Medicare payment policy. Washington (DC): Medicare Payment Advisory Commission (MedPAC); 2012 Mar. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Yale New Haven Health Services Corporation (YNHHSC), Center for Outcomes Research &amp; Evaluation (CORE). Hospital-level, risk-standardized payment associated with a 30-day episode of care for AMI (version 1.0): 2012 measure methodology report. Baltimore (MD): Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS); 2012 Sep. 71 p.  [19 references]&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3022" OrdBy="110" ID="570" Name="Primary Health Components" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Acute myocardial infarction (AMI); 30-day episode of care payment&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="23" OrdBy="120" ID="571" Name="Denominator Description" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The measure cohort includes acute inpatient admissions for Medicare Fee-for-Service (FFS) beneficiaries aged 65 years or older discharged from non-federal acute care hospitals and critical access hospitals, with a principal discharge diagnosis of acute myocardial infarction (AMI).&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The risk-standardized payment (RSP) is calculated as the ratio of the &quot;predicted&quot; payment to the &quot;expected&quot; payment at a given hospital, multiplied by the national mean payment. For each hospital, the denominator is the payment expected based on the nation and the specific hospital's case mix.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;See the related &quot;Denominator Inclusions/Exclusions&quot; field.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: This outcome measure does not have a traditional numerator and denominator like a core process measure; thus, this field is used to define the measure cohort.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;See the &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.qualitynet.org/dcs/ContentServer?c=Page&amp;amp;pagename=QnetPublic%2FPage%2FQnetTier4&amp;amp;cid=1228774267858&quot; title=&quot;QualityNet Web site&quot;&gt;2017 Measures Updates and Specifications Report: Hospital-level Risk-standardized Payment Measures&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; for more details.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="24" OrdBy="130" ID="572" Name="Numerator Description" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The measure reports total payments associated with an episode of care for acute myocardial infarction (AMI).&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The risk-standardized payment (RSP) is calculated as the ratio of the &quot;predicted&quot; payment to the &quot;expected&quot; payment at a given hospital, multiplied by the national mean payment. For each hospital, the numerator of the ratio is the payment predicted based on the specific hospital and its observed case mix.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;See the related &quot;Numerator Inclusions/Exclusions&quot; field.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: This outcome measure does not have a traditional numerator and denominator like a core process measure; thus, this field is used to define the outcome.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;See the &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.qualitynet.org/dcs/ContentServer?c=Page&amp;amp;pagename=QnetPublic%2FPage%2FQnetTier4&amp;amp;cid=1228774267858&quot; title=&quot;QualityNet Web site&quot;&gt;2017 Measures Updates and Specifications Report: Hospital-level Risk-standardized Payment Measures&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; for more details.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="573" OrdBy="140" Name="Evidence Supporting the Measure">
    <Field FieldID="3027" OrdBy="150" ID="574" Name="Type of Evidence Supporting the Criterion of Quality for the Measure" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="One or more research studies published in a National Library of Medicine (NLM) indexed, peer-reviewed journal" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3501" OrdBy="160" ID="575" Name="Additional Information Supporting Need for the Measure" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Acute myocardial infarction (AMI) is a common condition in the elderly with substantial variability in payments due to different practice patterns. Quality measures for AMI such as 30-day AMI risk-standardized mortality rate (RSMR) are already publicly reported. In the context of its publicly reported quality measures, AMI is an ideal condition in which to assess payments for Medicare patients and relative hospital value. Therefore, we created a measure of payments for a 30-day episode of care for AMI that could be aligned with the Centers for Medicare &amp;amp; Medicaid's (CMS's) 30-day AMI mortality and readmission measures. This will allow CMS to assess the value of care provided for these episodes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A preliminary examination of the 30-day AMI risk-standardized mortality and risk-standardized payment measures showed high quality care (as measured by RSMR) at higher and lower relative costs. This finding illustrated that quality care can be provided at relative lower costs and that efficiencies of care can be optimized for AMI. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3502" OrdBy="170" ID="576" Name="Evidence for Additional Information Supporting Need for the Measure" Type="citation">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;DeBuhr J. (Research Associate II, Yale University Center for Outcomes Research and Evaluation (CORE), New Haven, CT). Personal communication. 2017 Dec 12. &amp;nbsp;1 p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3072" OrdBy="180" ID="577" Name="Extent of Measure Testing" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Assessment of Updated Models &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The acute myocardial infarction (AMI) payment measure estimates hospital-specific episode-of-care risk-standardized payment (RSPs) using a hierarchical generalized linear model. Refer to Section 2 in the original measure documentation for a summary of the measure methodology and model risk-adjustment variables. Refer to prior methodology and technical reports for further details.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Centers for Medicare &amp;amp; Medicaid Services (CMS) evaluated and validated the performance of the AMI model using July 2013 to June 2016 data for the 2017 reporting period. They also evaluated the stability of the risk-adjustment model over the three-year measurement period by examining the model variable frequencies, model coefficients, and the performance of the risk-adjustment model in each year.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;CMS assessed generalized linear model performance in terms of discriminant ability for each year of data and for the three-year combined period. Two summary statistics for assessing model performance were computed: the predictive ratio and a quasi-R&amp;sup2;. For a traditional linear model (that is, ordinary least squares regression), R&amp;sup2; is interpreted as the amount of variation in the observed outcome that is explained by the predictor variables (patient-level risk factors). Generalized linear models, however, do not output an R&amp;sup2; that is akin to the R&amp;sup2; of a traditional linear model. A &quot;quasi-R&amp;sup2;&quot; was produced by regressing the total payment outcome on the predicted outcome. Specifically, CMS regressed the total payment on the payment predicted by the patient-level risk factors.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The results of these analyses are presented in Section 4.2 of the original measure documentation. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AMI Payment 2017 Model Results&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Frequency of AMI Model Variables &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;CMS examined the change in the frequencies of clinical and demographic variables. Frequencies of model variables were stable over the measurement period. There were no notable changes (greater than 2% absolute change) in the frequencies. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;AMI Model Parameters and Performance &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Table 4.2.2 in the original measure documentation shows the hierarchical generalized linear regression model variable coefficients by individual year and for the combined three-year dataset. Table 4.2.3 in the original measure documentation shows the risk-adjusted payment ratios and 95% confidence intervals for the AMI payment model by individual year and for the combined three-year dataset. The quasi-R&amp;sup2; for the AMI payment model was 0.08, suggesting that approximately 8% of the variation in payment can be explained by patient-level risk factors. This quasi-R&amp;sup2; is in line with R&amp;sup2;s from other patient-level risk-adjustment models for healthcare payment (Pope et al., 2011).&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Overall, the variable effect sizes were relatively constant across years. In addition, model performance was stable over the three-year time period; the quasi-R&amp;sup2; and predictive ratios remained similar to the model used for 2016 public reporting.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Refer to the original measure documentation for additional information. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3007" OrdBy="190" ID="578" Name="Evidence for Extent of Measure Testing" Type="citation">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Pope G, Kautter J, Ingber M, Freeman S, Sekar R, Newhard C. Evaluation of the CMS-HCC risk adjustment model: final report. Research Triangle Park (NC): RTI International; 2011 Mar. 119 p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Yale New Haven Health Services Corporation (YNHHSC), Center for Outcomes Research and Evaluation (CORE). 2017 measure updates and specifications report: hospital-level risk-standardized payment measures. Baltimore (MD): Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS); 2017 Mar. 94 p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="580" OrdBy="210" Name="State of Use of the Measure">
    <Field FieldID="3029" OrdBy="220" ID="581" Name="State of Use" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Current routine use" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3030" OrdBy="230" ID="582" Name="Current Use" Type="picklist-choice-3">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="583" OrdBy="240" Name="Application of the Measure in its Current Use">
    <Field FieldID="3031" OrdBy="250" ID="584" Name="Measurement Setting" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="Hospital Inpatient" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3032" OrdBy="260" ID="585" Name="Professionals Involved in Delivery of Health Services" Type="picklist-choice-3">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3033" OrdBy="270" ID="586" Name="Least Aggregated Level of Services Delivery Addressed" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Single Health Care Delivery or Public Health Organizations" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3505" OrdBy="280" ID="587" Name="Statement of Acceptable Minimum Sample Size" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Specified" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="41" OrdBy="290" ID="588" Name="Target Population Age" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Age greater than or equal to 65 years&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="42" OrdBy="300" ID="589" Name="Target Population Gender" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Either male or female" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="660" OrdBy="310" Name="National Strategy for Quality Improvement in Health Care">
    <Field FieldID="3522" OrdBy="320" ID="661" Name="National Quality Strategy Aim" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Affordable Care&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3525" OrdBy="330" ID="662" Name="National Quality Strategy Priority" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="590" OrdBy="340" Name="Institute of Medicine (IOM) National Health Care Quality Report Categories">
    <Field FieldID="3163" OrdBy="350" ID="591" Name="IOM Care Need" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="Not within an IOM Care Need" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3164" OrdBy="360" ID="592" Name="IOM Domain" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="Not within an IOM Domain" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="593" OrdBy="370" Name="Data Collection for the Measure">
    <Field FieldID="3506" OrdBy="380" ID="594" Name="Case Finding Period" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Discharges July 1, 2013 through June 30, 2016&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3054" OrdBy="390" ID="595" Name="Denominator Sampling Frame" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Patients associated with provider" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3057" OrdBy="400" ID="598" Name="Denominator (Index) Event or Characteristic" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="Clinical Condition" />
      <FieldValue Value="Institutionalization" />
      <FieldValue Value="Patient/Individual (Consumer) Characteristic" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3058" OrdBy="410" ID="599" Name="Denominator Time Window" Type="picklist-choice-3">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="55" OrdBy="420" ID="596" Name="Denominator Inclusions/Exclusions" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;An &lt;em&gt;index admission&lt;/em&gt; is the hospitalization that begins the episode-of-care payment window and includes admissions for patients:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Having a principal discharge diagnosis of acute myocardial infarction (AMI)* &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Enrolled in Medicare Fee-for-Service (FFS) Part A and Part B for the 12 months prior to the date of the admission, and enrolled in Part A and Part B during the index admission &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Aged 65 or over &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Not transferred from another acute care facility &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;*International Classification of Diseases, Tenth Revision, Clinical Modification (ICD-10-CM) codes used to define the AMI cohort for discharges on or after October 1, 2015:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul class=&quot;Note&quot; style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;I21.01 ST elevation myocardial infarction (STEMI) involving left main coronary artery &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;I21.02 STEMI involving left anterior descending coronary artery &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;I21.09 STEMI involving other coronary artery of anterior wall &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;I21.11 STEMI involving right coronary artery &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;I21.19 STEMI involving other coronary artery of inferior wall &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;I21.21 STEMI involving left circumflex coronary artery &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;I21.29 STEMI involving other sites &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;I21.3 STEMI of unspecified site &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;I21.4 Non-ST elevation (NSTEMI) myocardial infarction &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: International Classification of Diseases, Ninth Revision (ICD-9) code lists for discharges prior to October 1, 2015 can be found in the &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.qualitynet.org/dcs/ContentServer?c=Page&amp;amp;pagename=QnetPublic%2FPage%2FQnetTier4&amp;amp;cid=1228774789978&quot; title=&quot;QualityNet Web site&quot;&gt;2016 Measures Updates and Specifications Report: Hospital-level Risk-standardized Payment Measures&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Discharged alive on the day of admission or the following day who were not transferred to another acute care facility &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Inconsistent or unknown patient vital status or other unreliable demographic (age and gender) data &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Incomplete administrative data in the 30 days following the start of the index admission if discharged alive &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Enrolled in the Medicare hospice program any time in the 12 months prior to the index admission, including the first day of the index admission &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Discharged against medical advice &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Transferred to a federal hospital &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Not matched to admission in the AMI mortality measure &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Missing index diagnosis-related group (DRG) weight where provider received no payment &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For patients with more than one eligible admission for AMI in a single year, only one index admission for that condition is randomly selected for inclusion in the cohort. Additional admissions within that year are excluded. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3507" OrdBy="430" ID="597" Name="Exclusions/Exceptions" Type="picklist-choice-4">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="59" OrdBy="440" ID="600" Name="Numerator Inclusions/Exclusions" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;The measure reports total payments associated with an episode of care for acute myocardial infarction (AMI). &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The measure captures payments for Medicare patients across multiple care settings, services, and supplies (that is, inpatient, outpatient, skilled nursing facility [SNF], home health, hospice, physician/clinical laboratory/ambulance services, durable medical equipment, prosthetics/orthotics, and supplies). &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The risk-standardized payment (RSP) is calculated as the ratio of the &quot;predicted&quot; payment to the &quot;expected&quot; payment at a given hospital, multiplied by the national mean payment. For each hospital, the numerator of the ratio is the payment predicted based on the specific hospital and its observed case mix.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: This outcome measure does not have a traditional numerator and denominator like a core process measure; thus, this field is used to define the outcome. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;See the &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.qualitynet.org/dcs/ContentServer?c=Page&amp;amp;pagename=QnetPublic%2FPage%2FQnetTier4&amp;amp;cid=1228774267858&quot; title=&quot;QualityNet Web site&quot;&gt;2017 Measures Updates and Specifications Report: Hospital-level Risk-standardized Payment Measures&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; for more details.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Payment adjustments unrelated to clinical care decisions are not considered in the measure outcome&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3061" OrdBy="450" ID="601" Name="Numerator Search Strategy" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Institutionalization" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3062" OrdBy="460" ID="602" Name="Data Source" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Administrative clinical data" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3065" OrdBy="470" ID="603" Name="Type of Health State" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Does not apply to this measure" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3066" OrdBy="480" ID="604" Name="Instruments Used and/or Associated with the Measure" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;None&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="605" OrdBy="490" Name="Computation of the Measure">
    <Field FieldID="3508" OrdBy="500" ID="606" Name="Measure Specifies Disaggregation" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Does not apply to this measure" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3067" OrdBy="520" ID="608" Name="Scoring" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Ratio" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3068" OrdBy="530" ID="609" Name="Interpretation of Score" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Does not apply to this measure (i.e., there is no pre-defined preference for the measure score)" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3090" OrdBy="540" ID="610" Name="Allowance for Patient or Population Factors" Type="picklist-choice-3">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3069" OrdBy="550" ID="611" Name="Description of Allowance for Patient or Population Factors" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Risk-Adjustment Variables &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In order to account for differences in case mix among hospitals, the measure adjusts for variables (for example, age, comorbid disease, and indicators of patient frailty) that are clinically relevant and have relationships with the outcome. For each patient, risk-adjustment variables are obtained from inpatient, outpatient, and physician Medicare administrative claims data extending 12 months prior to, and including, the index admission. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The measure adjusts for case mix differences among hospitals based on the clinical status of the patient at the time of the index admission. Accordingly, only comorbidities that convey information about the patient at that time or in the 12 months prior, and not complications that arise during the course of the hospitalization, are included in the risk adjustment. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The measure does not adjust for socioeconomic status (SES) because the association between SES and health outcomes can be due, in part, to differences in the quality of healthcare that groups of patients with varying SES receive. The intent is for the measure to adjust for patient demographic and clinical characteristics while illuminating important payment differences. As part of the National Quality Forum's (NQF's) endorsement process for this measure, the Centers for Medicare &amp;amp; Medicaid Services (CMS) completed analyses for the two-year Sociodemographic Trial Period. Although bivariate analyses found that the average total payments is higher for dual-eligible patients (for patients living in lower Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality [AHRQ] SES Index census block groups) and African-American patients compared with all other patients, analyses in the context of a multivariable model demonstrated that the effect size of these variables was small, and that the quasi-R&amp;sup2; values for the models are similar with and without the addition of these variables. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Refer to Appendix D in the original measure documentation for the list of comorbidity risk-adjustment variables and list of complications that are excluded from risk adjustment if they occur only during the index admission.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3070" OrdBy="560" ID="612" Name="Standard of Comparison" Type="picklist-choice-3">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="615" OrdBy="590" Name="Identifying Information">
    <Field FieldID="73" OrdBy="600" ID="616" Name="Original Title" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hospital-level RSP associated with a 30-day episode of care for AMI.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="74" OrdBy="610" ID="617" Name="Measure Collection Name" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="National Hospital Inpatient Quality Measures" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="75" OrdBy="620" ID="618" Name="Measure Set Name" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="Payment Measures" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="16" OrdBy="650" ID="621" Name="Submitter" Type="orglist">
      <FieldValue Value="Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services - Federal Government Agency [U.S.]" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="17" OrdBy="660" ID="622" Name="Developer" Type="orglist-p">
      <FieldValue Value="Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services - Federal Government Agency [U.S.]" />
      <FieldValue Value="Yale-New Haven Health Services Corporation/Center for Outcomes Research and Evaluation under contract to Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services - Academic Affiliated Research Institute" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="79" OrdBy="670" ID="623" Name="Funding Source(s)" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Centers for Medicare &amp;amp; Medicaid Services (CMS)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="80" OrdBy="680" ID="624" Name="Composition of the Group that Developed the Measure" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This measure was developed by a team of experts: &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Ann-Marie Audet, MD, Commonwealth Fund &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Peter Bach, MD, Memorial Sloan-Kettering Cancer Center &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Richard Bankowitz, MD, Premier Inc. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Donald Casey, MD, New York University Langone Medical Center &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Lesley Curtis, PhD, Duke University &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;David Dunn, MD, ZHealth LLC &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Terri Golash, MD, Aetna &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Vivian Ho, PhD, Rice University &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;David Hopkins, PhD, Pacific Business Group on Health &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Amanda Kowalski, PhD, Yale University &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Kavita Patel, MD, Brookings Institute &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Stephen Schmaltz, PhD, Joint Commission &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Nancy Kim, MD, PhD, Yale School of Medicine &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Lesli S. Ott, MA, MA, Yale New Haven Health Services Corporation/Center for Outcomes Research &amp;amp; Evaluation (YNHHSC/CORE) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Steven Spivack, MPH, YNHHSC/CORE &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Xiao Xu, MA, PhD, Yale School of Medicine &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Mark Volpe, BS, YNHHSC/CORE &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Alex Liu, BS, NHHSC/CORE &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Kanchana R. Bhat, MPH, YNHHSC/CORE &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Marissa Lee, MP., YNHHSC/CORE &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Carol Oladele, PhD, Yale School of Medicine &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Susannah M. Bernheim, MD, MHS, Yale School of Medicine &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Harlan M. Krumholz, MD, SM, Yale School of Medicine &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="81" OrdBy="690" ID="625" Name="Financial Disclosures/Other Potential Conflicts of Interest" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="82" OrdBy="700" ID="626" Name="Endorser" Type="orglist">
      <FieldValue Value="National Quality Forum - None" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3091" OrdBy="705" ID="696" Name="NQF Number" Type="plain-text">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3510" OrdBy="710" ID="627" Name="Date of Endorsement" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;2016 Nov 7&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3083" OrdBy="720" ID="628" Name="Measure Initiative(s)" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Hospital Compare" />
      <FieldValue Value="Hospital Inpatient Quality Reporting Program" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="19" OrdBy="730" ID="629" Name="Adaptation" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This measure was not adapted from another source.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3086" OrdBy="740" ID="630" Name="Date of Most Current Version in NQMC" Type="date">
      <FieldValue Value="2017 Mar" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3511" OrdBy="750" ID="631" Name="Measure Maintenance" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Annual&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3512" OrdBy="760" ID="632" Name="Date of Next Anticipated Revision" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;2018 Apr&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="20" OrdBy="770" ID="633" Name="Measure Status" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the current release of the measure.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This measure updates a previous version: Specifications manual for national hospital inpatient quality measures, version 5.0b. Centers for Medicare &amp;amp; Medicaid Services (CMS), The Joint Commission; Effective 2015 Oct 1. various p. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="14" OrdBy="780" ID="634" Name="Measure Availability" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Source available from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.qualitynet.org/dcs/ContentServer?c=Page&amp;amp;pagename=QnetPublic%2FPage%2FQnetTier4&amp;amp;cid=1228774267858&quot; title=&quot;QualityNet Web site&quot;&gt;QualityNet Web site&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Check the QualityNet Web site regularly for the most recent version of the specifications manual and for the applicable dates of discharge.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="15" OrdBy="790" ID="635" Name="Companion Documents" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following are available:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Hospital compare: a quality tool provided by Medicare. [internet]. Washington (DC): U.S. Department of Health and Human Services; [accessed 2017 Nov 10]. Available from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.medicare.gov/hospitalcompare/search.html?&quot; title=&quot;Medicare Web site&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Medicare Web site&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Yale New Haven Health Services Corporation (YNHHSC), Center for Outcomes Research and Evaluation (CORE). 2017 Medicare hospital quality chartbook. Baltimore (MD): Centers for Medicare &amp;amp; Medicaid Services (CMS); 2017. Available from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cms.gov/Medicare/Quality-Initiatives-Patient-Assessment-Instruments/HospitalQualityInits/OutcomeMeasures.html&quot; title=&quot;CMS Web site&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;CMS Web site&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Yale New Haven Health Services Corporation (YNHHSC), Center for Outcomes Research and Evaluation (CORE). 2017 payment measures updates and specifications report: supplemental ICD-10 code lists for use with claims for discharges on or after October 1, 2015. Baltimore (MD): Centers for Medicare &amp;amp; Medicaid Services (CMS); 2017. Available from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.qualitynet.org/dcs/ContentServer?c=Page&amp;amp;pagename=QnetPublic%2FPage%2FQnetTier4&amp;amp;cid=1228774267858&quot; title=&quot;QualityNet Web site&quot;&gt;QualityNet Web site&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="87" OrdBy="800" ID="636" Name="NQMC Status" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This NQMC summary was completed by ECRI Institute on December 4, 2014. The information was verified by the measure developer on January 21, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This NQMC summary was updated by ECRI Institute on August 7, 2015. The information was verified by the measure developer on September 23, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This NQMC summary was updated again by ECRI Institute on December 4, 2017. The information was verified by the measure developer on December 12, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="88" OrdBy="810" ID="637" Name="Copyright Statement" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;No copyright restrictions apply.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="641" OrdBy="850" Name="Production">
    <Field FieldID="1" OrdBy="1366" ID="562" Name="Source(s)" Type="citation">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Yale New Haven Health Services Corporation (YNHHSC), Center for Outcomes Research and Evaluation (CORE). 2017 measure updates and specifications report: hospital-level risk-standardized payment measures. Baltimore (MD): Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS); 2017 Mar. 94 p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="99999" OrdBy="99999" Name="Disclaimer">
    <Field FieldID="99999" OrdBy="99999" ID="99999" Name="NQMC Disclaimer" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;p&gt;The National Quality Measures Clearinghouse™ (NQMC) does not develop, produce, approve, or endorse the measures represented on this site.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;All measures summarized by NQMC and hosted on our site are produced under the auspices of medical specialty societies, relevant professional associations, public and private organizations, other government agencies, health care organizations or plans, individuals, and similar entities.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Measures represented on the NQMC Web site are submitted by measure developers, and are screened solely to determine that they meet the &lt;a href=&quot;/help-and-about/summaries/inclusion-criteria&quot;&gt;NQMC Inclusion Criteria&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;NQMC, AHRQ, and its contractor ECRI Institute make no warranties concerning the content or its reliability and/or validity of the quality measures and related materials represented on this site. Moreover, the views and opinions of developers or authors of measures represented on this site do not necessarily state or reflect those of NQMC, AHRQ, or its contractor, ECRI Institute, and inclusion or hosting of measures in NQMC may not be used for advertising or commercial endorsement purposes.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Readers with questions regarding measure content are directed to contact the measure developer.&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
</Version>