<Version>
  <xmlSource>This XML content was developed by AHRQ's contractor ECRI Institute for the National Quality Measures Clearinghouse (NQMC).</xmlSource>
  <Section SecID="560" OrdBy="10" Name="General">
    <Field FieldID="11" OrdBy="20" ID="561" Name="Title" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_title&quot;&gt;Hospital-based inpatient psychiatric services: the total number of hours that all patients admitted to a hospital-based inpatient psychiatric setting were maintained in physical restraint.&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="1" OrdBy="30" ID="562" Name="Source(s)" Type="citation">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Specifications manual for Joint Commission national quality measures, version 2016A. Oakbrook Terrace (IL): The Joint Commission; Effective 2016 Jul 1. various p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="563" OrdBy="40" Name="Measure Domain">
    <Field FieldID="3025" OrdBy="50" ID="564" Name="Primary Measure Domain" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Clinical Quality Measures: Process" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3026" OrdBy="60" ID="565" Name="Secondary Measure Domain" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Does not apply to this measure" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="566" OrdBy="70" Name="Brief Abstract">
    <Field FieldID="34" OrdBy="80" ID="567" Name="Description" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This measure is used to assess the total number of hours that all patients admitted to a hospital-based inpatient psychiatric setting were maintained in physical restraint.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This measure represents the overall rate. The following rates are also reported:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Children age 1 through 12 years &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Adolescent age 13 through 17 years &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Adult age 18 through 64 years &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Older adult age greater than or equal to 65 years &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="21" OrdBy="90" ID="568" Name="Rationale" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mental health providers that value and respect an individual's autonomy, independence and safety seek to avoid the use of dangerous or restrictive interventions at all times (Donat, 2003). The use of seclusion and restraint is limited to situations deemed to meet the threshold of imminent danger and when restraint and seclusion are used, such use is rigorously monitored and analyzed to prevent future use. Providers also seek to prevent violence or aggression from occurring in their treatment environments by focusing their attention on prevention activities that have a growing evidence base (Donat, 2003).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3500" OrdBy="100" ID="569" Name="Evidence for Rationale" Type="citation">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Donat DC. An analysis of successful efforts to reduce the use of seclusion and restraint at a public psychiatric hospital. Psychiatr Serv. 2003 Aug;54(8):1119-23. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=12883139&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Specifications manual for Joint Commission national quality measures, version 2016A. Oakbrook Terrace (IL): The Joint Commission; Effective 2016 Jul 1. various p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3022" OrdBy="110" ID="570" Name="Primary Health Components" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Psychiatric inpatient; physical restraint&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="23" OrdBy="120" ID="571" Name="Denominator Description" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Number of psychiatric inpatient days (see the related &quot;Denominator Inclusions/Exclusions&quot; field)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="24" OrdBy="130" ID="572" Name="Numerator Description" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The total number of hours that all psychiatric inpatients were maintained in physical restraint (see the related &quot;Numerator Inclusions/Exclusions&quot; field)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="573" OrdBy="140" Name="Evidence Supporting the Measure">
    <Field FieldID="3027" OrdBy="150" ID="574" Name="Type of Evidence Supporting the Criterion of Quality for the Measure" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="One or more research studies published in a National Library of Medicine (NLM) indexed, peer-reviewed journal" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3501" OrdBy="160" ID="575" Name="Additional Information Supporting Need for the Measure" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Restraint and seclusion are coercive high-risk interventions used in many psychiatric care settings in order to control aggressive and violent behaviors. The use of restraint and seclusion may result in adverse events including death and permanent loss of function for some patients, as well as staff injuries. According to the Joint Commission's sentinel event voluntary reporting database from 2004 through 2011, there have been 110 sentinel events related to physical restraint of a patient resulting in death or permanent loss of function. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;The rationale for restraint and seclusion use is not well understood and varies according to the organization's culture and perception on the most appropriate way to handle escalating behaviors. Restraint and seclusion use adversely impacts healthcare organizations, staff, and patients. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;According to Bergk et al. (2008), rates of seclusion and restraint use vary from 0% to 66%. Reports estimate 50 to 150 deaths per year in the U.S. due to improper monitoring and application. Even in cases where restraints have been applied correctly, fatal patient outcomes have occurred. Additionally, acute excited states resulting from restraint or seclusion have been associated with patient deaths. The use of restraint and seclusion creates significant risks for psychiatric patients. Among the most serious risks are: injury or death, retraumatization of patients with a trauma history, loss of dignity and psychological harm. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;In mental health, violence is considered endemic. The use of restraint and seclusion contributes to a cycle of workplace violence which may claim as much as 23% to 50% of staff time, account for 50% of staff injuries, increase the risk of injury to patients and staff by 60%, and increase the length of stay, potentially setting recovery back at least 6 months with each occurrence. Results from the National Crime Victimization Survey for 1993 to 1999 which was conducted by the Department of Justice showed the annual rate of nonfatal, job-related violent crime against psychiatrists and mental health professionals was 68.2 per 1,000 and 69.0 per 1,000 for mental health custodial workers as compared to 12.6 per 1,000 for work in all occupations. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;According to Cromwell et al. (2005), the daily cost of care increases with restraint and seclusion use and contributes to significant workforce turnover reportedly ranging from 18% to 62%, costing hundreds of thousands of dollars to several million dollars. The most significant day-to-day cost is the amount of staff time spent managing restraint and seclusion events. The full cost to an organization is unknown due to the lack of research. A time/motion/task analysis of restraint estimated the cost of one episode from $302 to $354, according to the number of restraint methods used (e.g., physical, mechanical, or medication). A 1-hour restraint involved 25 different activities and claimed nearly 12 hours of staff time to manage and process the event from beginning to end. Collectively, restraint use claimed more than 23% of staff time and $1.4 million in staff-related costs, which represented nearly 40% of the operating budget for the inpatient service studied. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Many hospitals and residential programs, serving different ages and populations, have successfully reduced their use and redirected existing resources to support additional staff training, implement prevention-oriented alternatives, and enhance the environment of care. Significant savings result from reduced staff turnover, hiring and replacement costs, sick time, and liability related costs. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3502" OrdBy="170" ID="576" Name="Evidence for Additional Information Supporting Need for the Measure" Type="citation">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Bergk J, Einsiedler B, Steinert T. Feasibility of randomized controlled trials on seclusion and mechanical restraint. Clin Trials. 2008;5(4):356-63. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=18697850&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Besemer D, Siler J, Vargas LA. Sanctuary longitudinal study: innovation, collaboration and frustration. In: Paper presented at the Alliance for Children and Families National Conference; Baltimore. 2008. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Cromwell J, Gage B, Drozd E, Maier J, Osber D, Evensen C, et al. Psychiatric inpatient routine cost analysis. Baltimore (MD): Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services; 2005. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Flood C, Bowers L, Parkin D. Estimating the costs of conflict and containment on adult acute inpatient psychiatric wards. Nurs Econ. 2008 Sep-Oct;26(5):325-330, 324. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=18979699&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Florida TaxWatch. Florida State Hospital-Chattahoochee wins award for reduced patient seclusion and restraint. Adaptable achievements from the 2007 Prudential Financial Davis Productivity Awards competition. [internet]. 2008&amp;nbsp;[accessed 2012 Mar 13]. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Friedman RA. Violence and mental illness--how strong is the link. N Engl J Med. 2006 Nov 16;355(20):2064-6. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=17108340&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;General Accounting Office (GAO). Extent of risk from improper restraint or seclusion is unknown. (GAO/T-HEHS-00-26). Washington (DC): United States General Accounting Office; 1999. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;General Accounting Office (GAO). Mental health: improper restraint or seclusion use places people at risk. (GAO/HES-99-176). Washington (DC): United States General Accounting Office; 1999. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Haimowitz S, Urff J, Huckshorn KA. Restraint and seclusion: a risk management guide. Alexandria (VA): National Association of State Mental Health Program Directors; 2006. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Huckshorn KA. Re-designing state mental health policy to prevent the use of seclusion and restraint. Admin Policy Ment Health. 2006 Jul;33(4):482-91. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=16244812&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Institute of Psychiatry (IOP). The recognition, prevention and therapeutic management of violence in mental healthcare, UKCC. [internet]. London (UK): United Kingdom Central Council; 2002&amp;nbsp;[accessed 2012 Mar 13]. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Lebel J, Goldstein R. The economic cost of using restraint and the value added by restraint reduction or elimination. Psychiatr Serv. 2005 Sep;56(9):1109-14. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=16148326&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;National Association of State Mental Health Program Directors (NASMHPD). Position statement on seclusion and restraint. Alexandria (VA): National Association of State Mental Health Program Directors (NASMHPD); 1999. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Paxton D. Creating and supporting coercion-free and violence-free treatment environments: The Village Network and the Knox County Children's Resource Center restraint reduction effort. Paper presentation. Columbus (OH): Ohio Association of Child Caring Agencies Learning Community Conference; 2009. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Richter D, Whittington R, editor(s). Violence in mental health settings: Causes, consequences, management. New York: Springer Science+Business Media, LLC; 2006. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Short R, Sherman ME, Raia J, Bumgardner C, Chambers A, Lofton V. Safety guidelines for injury-free management of psychiatric inpatients in precrisis and crisis situations. Psychiatr Serv. 2008 Dec;59(12):1376-8. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=19033162&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration. The business case for preventing and reducing restraint and seclusion use. HHS Publication No. (SMA) 11-4632). Rockville (MD): Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration; 2011. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;The Joint Commission. Sentinel event data - root causes by event type. [internet]. 2011&amp;nbsp;[accessed 2012 Mar 20]. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3072" OrdBy="180" ID="577" Name="Extent of Measure Testing" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Alpha testing was conducted during May and June 2006 at approximately 40 volunteer test sites to assess feasibility and data collection effort. A set of measures was recommended by the Technical Advisory Panel (TAP) to comprise the final test set addressing the domains of Assessment, Patient Safety and Continuity/Transitions of Care.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Specification Manual for National Hospital Inpatient Quality Measures Hospital-Based Inpatient Psychiatric Services Test Set was finalized in September 2006. In late 2006 a total of 196 hospitals volunteered to participate in the Hospital-Based Inpatient Psychiatric Services (HBIPS) pilot test. Data collection for the test set began with January 1, 2007 discharges and continued throughout December 31, 2007.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;During the first quarter of the pilot test, a subset of 39 hospitals was randomly selected to collect and transmit monthly hospital clinical data (HCD) to help assess data quality and data reliability. The data quality study continued with data collection and transmission for the 12 months of 2007. Feedback on data quality was provided to each performance measurement systems vendor submitting HCD.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The final phase of testing consisted of site visits to a sample of participating pilot hospitals to assess the reliability of data abstracted and reported by those hospitals. Reliability test site visits were conducted at 18 randomly selected pilot hospitals. Selection of the test sites was based on multiple characteristics, including hospital demographics, populations served, bed size and type of facility.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;All of the HBIPS measures have undergone a rigorous process of public comment, alpha testing and broad-scale pilot testing and are recognized by the field as important indicators of hospital-based inpatient psychiatric care. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3007" OrdBy="190" ID="578" Name="Evidence for Extent of Measure Testing" Type="citation">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Domzalski K. (Associate Project Director, Division of Healthcare Quality Evaluation, Department of Quality Measurement. The Joint Commission. Oakbrook Terrace, IL). Personal communication. 2010 Nov 16. &amp;nbsp;1 p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="580" OrdBy="210" Name="State of Use of the Measure">
    <Field FieldID="3029" OrdBy="220" ID="581" Name="State of Use" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Current routine use" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3030" OrdBy="230" ID="582" Name="Current Use" Type="picklist-choice-3">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="583" OrdBy="240" Name="Application of the Measure in its Current Use">
    <Field FieldID="3031" OrdBy="250" ID="584" Name="Measurement Setting" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="Hospital Inpatient" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3032" OrdBy="260" ID="585" Name="Professionals Involved in Delivery of Health Services" Type="picklist-choice-3">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3033" OrdBy="270" ID="586" Name="Least Aggregated Level of Services Delivery Addressed" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Single Health Care Delivery or Public Health Organizations" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3505" OrdBy="280" ID="587" Name="Statement of Acceptable Minimum Sample Size" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Does not apply to this measure" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="41" OrdBy="290" ID="588" Name="Target Population Age" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;All patients age one year and older&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="42" OrdBy="300" ID="589" Name="Target Population Gender" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Either male or female" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="660" OrdBy="310" Name="National Strategy for Quality Improvement in Health Care">
    <Field FieldID="3522" OrdBy="320" ID="661" Name="National Quality Strategy Aim" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Better Care&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3525" OrdBy="330" ID="662" Name="National Quality Strategy Priority" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Making Care Safer&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="590" OrdBy="340" Name="Institute of Medicine (IOM) National Health Care Quality Report Categories">
    <Field FieldID="3163" OrdBy="350" ID="591" Name="IOM Care Need" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="Getting Better" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3164" OrdBy="360" ID="592" Name="IOM Domain" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="Safety" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="593" OrdBy="370" Name="Data Collection for the Measure">
    <Field FieldID="3506" OrdBy="380" ID="594" Name="Case Finding Period" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Discharges July 1 through December 31&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3054" OrdBy="390" ID="595" Name="Denominator Sampling Frame" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Patients associated with provider" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3057" OrdBy="400" ID="598" Name="Denominator (Index) Event or Characteristic" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="Clinical Condition" />
      <FieldValue Value="Institutionalization" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3058" OrdBy="410" ID="599" Name="Denominator Time Window" Type="picklist-choice-3">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="55" OrdBy="420" ID="596" Name="Denominator Inclusions/Exclusions" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Number of psychiatric inpatient days&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Total leave days&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3507" OrdBy="430" ID="597" Name="Exclusions/Exceptions" Type="picklist-choice-4">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="59" OrdBy="440" ID="600" Name="Numerator Inclusions/Exclusions" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;The total number of hours that all psychiatric inpatients were maintained in physical restraint&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Include patients for whom at least one physical restraint event is reported during the month.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;None&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3061" OrdBy="450" ID="601" Name="Numerator Search Strategy" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Institutionalization" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3062" OrdBy="460" ID="602" Name="Data Source" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Administrative clinical data" />
      <FieldValue Value="Paper medical record" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3065" OrdBy="470" ID="603" Name="Type of Health State" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Does not apply to this measure" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3066" OrdBy="480" ID="604" Name="Instruments Used and/or Associated with the Measure" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Hospital-Based Inpatient Psychiatric Services (HBIPS) Initial Patient Population Algorithm Flowchart &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;HBIPS-2: Hours of Physical Restraint Use Flowchart &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="605" OrdBy="490" Name="Computation of the Measure">
    <Field FieldID="3508" OrdBy="500" ID="606" Name="Measure Specifies Disaggregation" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Measure is disaggregated into categories based on different definitions of the denominator and/or numerator" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3509" OrdBy="510" ID="607" Name="Basis for Disaggregation" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This measure is disaggregated according to the following age groups:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Children age 1 through 12 years &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Adolescent age 13 through 17 years &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Adult age 18 through 64 years &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Older adult age greater than or equal to 65 years &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data Reported As&lt;/strong&gt;: Aggregate rate generated from count data reported as a ratio.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3067" OrdBy="520" ID="608" Name="Scoring" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Ratio" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3068" OrdBy="530" ID="609" Name="Interpretation of Score" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Desired value is a lower score" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3090" OrdBy="540" ID="610" Name="Allowance for Patient or Population Factors" Type="picklist-choice-3">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3070" OrdBy="560" ID="612" Name="Standard of Comparison" Type="picklist-choice-3">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="615" OrdBy="590" Name="Identifying Information">
    <Field FieldID="73" OrdBy="600" ID="616" Name="Original Title" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;HBIPS-2: Hours of physical restraint use.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="74" OrdBy="610" ID="617" Name="Measure Collection Name" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="National Quality Core Measures" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="75" OrdBy="620" ID="618" Name="Measure Set Name" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="Hospital-Based Inpatient Psychiatric Services" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="16" OrdBy="650" ID="621" Name="Submitter" Type="orglist">
      <FieldValue Value="The Joint Commission - Health Care Accreditation Organization" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="17" OrdBy="660" ID="622" Name="Developer" Type="orglist-p">
      <FieldValue Value="The Joint Commission - Health Care Accreditation Organization" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="79" OrdBy="670" ID="623" Name="Funding Source(s)" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;All external funding for measure development has been received and used in full compliance with The Joint Commission's Corporate Sponsorship policies, which are available upon written request to The Joint Commission.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="80" OrdBy="680" ID="624" Name="Composition of the Group that Developed the Measure" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The composition of the group that developed the measure is available at: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jointcommission.org/assets/1/6/HBIPS%20TAP%20Members.pdf&quot; title=&quot;The Joint Commission Web site&quot;&gt;http://www.jointcommission.org/assets/1/6/HBIPS%20TAP%20Members.pdf&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="81" OrdBy="690" ID="625" Name="Financial Disclosures/Other Potential Conflicts of Interest" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Expert panel members have made full disclosure of relevant financial and conflict of interest information in accordance with the Joint Commission's Conflict of Interest policies, copies of which are available upon written request to The Joint Commission.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="82" OrdBy="700" ID="626" Name="Endorser" Type="orglist">
      <FieldValue Value="National Quality Forum - None" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3091" OrdBy="705" ID="696" Name="NQF Number" Type="plain-text">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3510" OrdBy="710" ID="627" Name="Date of Endorsement" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;2016 May 12&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3083" OrdBy="720" ID="628" Name="Measure Initiative(s)" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Inpatient Psychiatric Facility Quality Reporting Program" />
      <FieldValue Value="Quality Check®" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="19" OrdBy="730" ID="629" Name="Adaptation" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This measure was not adapted from another source.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3086" OrdBy="740" ID="630" Name="Date of Most Current Version in NQMC" Type="date">
      <FieldValue Value="2016 Jul" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3511" OrdBy="750" ID="631" Name="Measure Maintenance" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every six months&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3512" OrdBy="760" ID="632" Name="Date of Next Anticipated Revision" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;2017 Jan&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="20" OrdBy="770" ID="633" Name="Measure Status" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the current release of the measure. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This measure updates a previous version: Specifications manual for Joint Commission national quality core measures, version 2015B. Oakbrook Terrace (IL): The Joint Commission; Effective 2015 Oct 1. 327 p. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="14" OrdBy="780" ID="634" Name="Measure Availability" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Source available from &lt;a href=&quot;http://manual.jointcommission.org/bin/view/Manual/WebHome&quot; title=&quot;The Joint Commission Web site&quot;&gt;The Joint Commission Web site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For more information, contact The Joint Commission at One Renaissance Blvd., Oakbrook Terrace, IL 60181; Phone: 630-792-5800; Fax: 630-792-5005; Web site: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jointcommission.org&quot; title=&quot;The Joint Commission Web site&quot;&gt;www.jointcommission.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="87" OrdBy="800" ID="636" Name="NQMC Status" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This NQMC summary was completed by The Joint Commission on May 30, 2008 and reviewed accordingly by ECRI Institute on July 7, 2008.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This NQMC summary was updated by ECRI Institute on February 24, 2009. The information was verified by the measure developer on April 27, 2009.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This NQMC summary was completed by The Joint Commission on August 27, 2009 and reviewed accordingly by ECRI Institute on February 5, 2010.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This NQMC summary was completed by The Joint Commission on November 16, 2010 and reviewed accordingly by ECRI Institute on March 30, 2011.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This NQMC summary was retrofitted into the new template on June 30, 2011.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This NQMC summary was completed by The Joint Commission on June 10, 2013 and reviewed accordingly by ECRI Institute on October 30, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This NQMC summary was completed by The Joint Commission on June 27, 2014 and reviewed accordingly by ECRI Institute on September 19, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This NQMC summary was completed by The Joint Commission on July 21, 2015 and reviewed accordingly by ECRI Institute on September 21, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This NQMC summary was updated again by ECRI Institute on June 14, 2016. The information was verified by the measure developer on June 29, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="88" OrdBy="810" ID="637" Name="Copyright Statement" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Specifications Manual for Joint Commission National Quality Core Measures [Version 2016A, July 2016] is periodically updated by The Joint Commission. Users of the Specifications Manual for Joint Commission National Quality Core Measures must update their software and associated documentation based on the published manual production timelines.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="641" OrdBy="850" Name="Production">
    <Field FieldID="1" OrdBy="1366" ID="562" Name="Source(s)" Type="citation">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Specifications manual for Joint Commission national quality measures, version 2016A. Oakbrook Terrace (IL): The Joint Commission; Effective 2016 Jul 1. various p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="99999" OrdBy="99999" Name="Disclaimer">
    <Field FieldID="99999" OrdBy="99999" ID="99999" Name="NQMC Disclaimer" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;p&gt;The National Quality Measures Clearinghouse™ (NQMC) does not develop, produce, approve, or endorse the measures represented on this site.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;All measures summarized by NQMC and hosted on our site are produced under the auspices of medical specialty societies, relevant professional associations, public and private organizations, other government agencies, health care organizations or plans, individuals, and similar entities.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Measures represented on the NQMC Web site are submitted by measure developers, and are screened solely to determine that they meet the &lt;a href=&quot;/help-and-about/summaries/inclusion-criteria&quot;&gt;NQMC Inclusion Criteria&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;NQMC, AHRQ, and its contractor ECRI Institute make no warranties concerning the content or its reliability and/or validity of the quality measures and related materials represented on this site. Moreover, the views and opinions of developers or authors of measures represented on this site do not necessarily state or reflect those of NQMC, AHRQ, or its contractor, ECRI Institute, and inclusion or hosting of measures in NQMC may not be used for advertising or commercial endorsement purposes.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Readers with questions regarding measure content are directed to contact the measure developer.&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
</Version>