<Version>
  <xmlSource>This XML content was developed by AHRQ's contractor ECRI Institute for the National Quality Measures Clearinghouse (NQMC).</xmlSource>
  <Section SecID="560" OrdBy="10" Name="General">
    <Field FieldID="11" OrdBy="20" ID="561" Name="Title" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_title&quot;&gt;Availability of services: does the state report specific CAHPS results regarding whether parents of Medicaid-enrolled children get specialty care appointments for their children when needed?&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="1" OrdBy="30" ID="562" Name="Source(s)" Type="citation">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Quality Measurement, Evaluation, Testing, Review and Implementation Consortium (Q-METRIC). Basic measure information: reporting of CAHPS data regarding availability of specialist care for children on Medicaid. Ann Arbor (MI): Quality Measurement, Evaluation, Testing, Review and Implementation Consortium (Q-METRIC); 2014 Sep. 34 p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="563" OrdBy="40" Name="Measure Domain">
    <Field FieldID="3025" OrdBy="50" ID="564" Name="Primary Measure Domain" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Population Health Quality Measures: Population Structure" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3026" OrdBy="60" ID="565" Name="Secondary Measure Domain" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Population Health Quality Measure: Population Access" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="566" OrdBy="70" Name="Brief Abstract">
    <Field FieldID="34" OrdBy="80" ID="567" Name="Description" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This measure is used to assess whether the state reports specific Consumer Assessment of Healthcare Providers and Systems (CAHPS) results regarding whether parents of Medicaid-enrolled children get specialty care appointments for their children when needed.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This measure uses data on parent perceptions of specialist availability for Medicaid-enrolled children collected via an individual question from CAHPS, specifically CAHPS Health Plan Survey &amp;ndash; Child Medicaid Survey. The specialist availability question is written as follows in the CAHPS surveys currently in use:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Indent&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Version 5.0: In the last 6 months, how often did you get appointments for your child to see a specialist as soon as he or she needed?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Indent&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Version 4.0: In the last 6 months, how often was it easy to get appointments for your child with specialists? &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul class=&quot;Note&quot; style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;The question is asked of parents who answer &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Yes&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to the CAHPS screener question regarding whether parents made specialist appointments for their children. &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;The term &quot;state&quot; implies other geographical entities, such as United States territories.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="21" OrdBy="90" ID="568" Name="Rationale" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Availability and Early and Periodic Screening, Diagnosis and Treatment (EPSDT) (the CAHPS Measure)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xA;Medicaid's EPSDT benefit provides the foundation for comprehensive and preventive health care services for all Medicaid-enrolled children under age 21 years. Health screenings are mandated by the EPSDT guidelines, under which states are required to arrange (directly or through referral) for corrective treatment as indicated by the screenings. Further, states must report the number of children referred for corrective treatment to the Centers for Medicare &amp;amp; Medicaid Services (CMS) (Medicaid.gov, 2014). Specialty care referrals from EPSDT health screenings must be made available and provided promptly in order for parents to make timely appointments for their children. The Consumer Assessment of Healthcare Providers and Systems (CAHPS) measure assesses whether parents are able to secure these appointments.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Value of Reporting Results on Availability of Specialist Care (the Q-METRIC Measure)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xA;This Quality Measurement, Evaluation, Testing, Review and Implementation Consortium (Q-METRIC) measure requires states to report CAHPS data regarding whether parents of Medicaid‐enrolled children get specialty care appointments for their children when needed. Reporting about parents' views on the availability of specialty care is presumed to foster improvement through two mechanisms (Werner &amp;amp; Asch, 2005).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First, by ensuring a consistent mechanism to generate data on specialist availability, Medicaid programs can track their progress toward improving availability for their beneficiaries. Second, if such information is reported in a forum accessible to the public, patients (parents) have additional information on which to compare health plans (when available), and stakeholders have a mechanism to compare availability across states and to track progress over time (Werner &amp;amp; Asch, 2005). &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Public reporting in the health care setting is defined as data, publicly available or available to a broad audience free of charge or at a nominal cost, about a health care structure, process, or outcome at any provider level (individual clinician, group, or organizations [e.g., hospitals, nursing facilities]) or at the health plan level (&quot;Public reporting,&quot; 2012). Public reporting is seen as a possible way to bridge the gap between current and improved levels of quality in the practice of health care (Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality [AHRQ], 2011). Both consumer‐driven and provider‐driven changes can improve the quality of care after the initiation of public reporting (Werner, Stuart, &amp;amp; Polsky, 2010). Likewise, a study of the effect that voluntary information disclosure had on quality of care in health maintenance markets showed a significant and positive effect on quality (Jung, 2010). Disclosing data collected as part of the Health Plan Employer Data and Information Set (HEDIS) led to a ~7% improvement in quality scores, though improvement was not universal across all quality measures (Jung, 2010). &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Public reporting has also been noted to have the potential for unintended and negative consequences (Werner &amp;amp; Asch, 2005). These largely derive from a scenario in which physicians or providers screen their patients to avoid those negative outcomes in their reported performance scores. As this measure relies on aggregate and anonymous reporting, it is not expected that these unintended negative consequences will occur.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3500" OrdBy="100" ID="569" Name="Evidence for Rationale" Type="citation">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ). Public reporting as a quality improvement strategy: a systematic review of the multiple pathways public reporting may influence quality of health care. Rockville (MD): Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ); 2011 Aug 17. 18 p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Jung K. The impact of information disclosure on quality of care in HMO markets. Int J Qual Health Care. 2010 Dec;22(6):461-8. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=20940251&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Medicaid.gov. Early and periodic screening, diagnosis and treatment. [internet]. Baltimore (MD): Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS); 2014 Jun 17&amp;nbsp;[accessed 2014 Jul 09]. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Public reporting as a quality improvement strategy. Closing the quality gap: Revisiting the state of the science. Evidence Report No. 208. (Prepared by the Oregon Evidence-Based Practice Center under Contract No. 290-2007-10057-I.) AHRQ Publication No. 12-E011-EF. Rockville (MD): Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ); 2012 Jul. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Quality Measurement, Evaluation, Testing, Review and Implementation Consortium (Q-METRIC). Basic measure information: reporting of CAHPS data regarding availability of specialist care for children on Medicaid. Ann Arbor (MI): Quality Measurement, Evaluation, Testing, Review and Implementation Consortium (Q-METRIC); 2014 Sep. 34 p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Werner R, Stuart E, Polsky D. Public reporting drove quality gains at nursing homes. Health Aff (Millwood). 2010 Sep;29(9):1706-13. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=20820030&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Werner RM, Asch DA. The unintended consequences of publicly reporting quality information. JAMA. 2005 Mar 9;293(10):1239-44. [62 references] &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=15755946&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3022" OrdBy="110" ID="570" Name="Primary Health Components" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Specialist care; children&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="23" OrdBy="120" ID="571" Name="Denominator Description" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The denominator is the individual state required to report the CAHPS Health Plan Survey &amp;ndash; Child Medicaid version, and therefore will always be one (1).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="24" OrdBy="130" ID="572" Name="Numerator Description" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;A numerator of one (1) demonstrates that a particular state publicly reports the results of the individual question on specialist availability among its Medicaid population. If the numerator is zero (0), the state does not publicly report the results. See the related &quot;Numerator Inclusions/Exclusions&quot; field.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="573" OrdBy="140" Name="Evidence Supporting the Measure">
    <Field FieldID="3027" OrdBy="150" ID="574" Name="Type of Evidence Supporting the Criterion of Quality for the Measure" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="A clinical practice guideline or other peer-reviewed synthesis of the clinical research evidence" />
      <FieldValue Value="A systematic review of the clinical research literature (e.g., Cochrane Review)" />
      <FieldValue Value="One or more research studies published in a National Library of Medicine (NLM) indexed, peer-reviewed journal" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3501" OrdBy="160" ID="575" Name="Additional Information Supporting Need for the Measure" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Performance Gaps&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xA;Research shows a variety of issues related to specialist availability for Medicaid enrolled children:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Parents may have different expectations regarding their roles in setting up specialist appointments for a child (Stille et al., 2007; Clark et al., 2014). &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Physicians report varying degrees of success in their ability to refer Medicaid- and Children's Health Insurance Program (CHIP)-enrolled patients versus privately insured patients (United States Government Accountability Office, 2011). &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Timely and sufficient communication between the general pediatrician and the specialist can affect the degree of success in providing optimal care (Stille et al., 2006). &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Many states and regions have variable geographic distribution and shortages of specialists (Mayer, 2006). &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Research shows that consumers are beginning to seek out health care quality data. A report by the Kaiser Family Foundation (2004) noted that the number of consumers seeking such information increased from 27% in 2000 to 35% in 2004; moreover, 14% of consumers reported using quality information to choose health plans. However, the extent of public reporting varies by state.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Availability and Medicaid/CHIP&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xA;According to the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services (CMS), approximately 43 million children are currently covered by Medicaid/CHIP programs (Medicaid.gov, n.d.), suggesting that a significant proportion of these children at some point will be in a situation to require specialty care. A primary care provider for a Medicaid/CHIP enrolled child may refer the child to a specialist when the child has specialized health problems or treatment needs. Consumer Assessment of Healthcare Providers and Systems (CAHPS) survey data are focused on capturing the parent's success in obtaining the specialist appointment. The Quality Measurement, Evaluation, Testing, Review and Implementation Consortium (Q-METRIC) measure is focused on demonstrating whether states and programs make this information publicly available.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3502" OrdBy="170" ID="576" Name="Evidence for Additional Information Supporting Need for the Measure" Type="citation">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Clark SJ, Kauffman AD, Singer DC, Gebremariam A, Davis MM. Seeing specialists: Roles of parents and providers unclear. Ann Arbor (MI): University of Michigan; 2014 Jan. &amp;nbsp;(C.S. Mott Children’s Hospital National Poll on Children’s Health; no. 2).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Kaiser Family Foundation (KFF). Five years after IOM report on medical errors, nearly half of all consumers worry about the safety of their health care. [internet]. 2004 Nov 15&amp;nbsp;[accessed 2014 Jul 09]. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Mayer ML. Are we there yet? Distance to care and relative supply among pediatric medical subspecialties. Pediatrics. 2006 Dec;118(6):2313-21. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=17142513&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Medicaid.gov. Children. [internet]. Baltimore (MD) : Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS); [accessed 2014 Jul 08]. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Quality Measurement, Evaluation, Testing, Review and Implementation Consortium (Q-METRIC). Basic measure information: reporting of CAHPS data regarding availability of specialist care for children on Medicaid. Ann Arbor (MI): Quality Measurement, Evaluation, Testing, Review and Implementation Consortium (Q-METRIC); 2014 Sep. 34 p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Stille CJ, McLaughlin TJ, Primack WA, Mazor KM, Wasserman RC. Determinants and impact of generalist-specialist communication about pediatric outpatient referrals. Pediatrics. 2006 Oct;118(4):1341-9. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=17015522&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Stille CJ, Primack WA, McLaughlin TJ, Wasserman RC. Parents as information intermediaries between primary care and specialty physicians. Pediatrics. 2007 Dec;120(6):1238-46. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=18055672&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;United States Government Accountability Office (U.S. GAO). MEDICAID and CHIP: most physicians serve covered children but have difficulty referring them for specialty care. [internet]. United States Government Accountability Office (U.S. GAO); 2011 Jun&amp;nbsp;[accessed 2014 Jul 09]. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3072" OrdBy="180" ID="577" Name="Extent of Measure Testing" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reliability&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;Data and Methods&lt;/em&gt;. This measure has two aspects of reliability to consider: reliability of reporting the specific availability measure and reliability of the data collected.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first aspect, reliability of reporting the specific availability measure, has not been assessed. Reliability of reporting is expected to be high, as common threats to reliability identified by the National Quality Forum (2011) (specifically &quot;ambiguous measure specifications&quot; and &quot;small case volume or sample size&quot;) are not expected to be concerns.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The second aspect is the reliability of the underlying Consumer Assessment of Healthcare Providers and Systems (CAHPS) data. This measure is based on parents' responses to the CAHPS survey. CAHPS surveys have been extensively tested for reliability and have been consistently found to have high reliability (&amp;gt;0.70) (Dyer et al., 2012; Scholle et al., 2012). There may be some concern over using a single‐item question to assess the concept of availability. However, West et al. (2012) found that reliability of single‐item measures is relatively unaffected compared with multiple‐item measures of the same concept. Hays, Reise, &amp;amp; Calder&amp;oacute;n (2012) hypothesized that this may be due to the narrowness of the concept being measured, which would be consistent with the current measure's conceptual focus.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Validity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;Validity of CAHPS Questions&lt;/em&gt;. CAHPS is a well-established tool for obtaining patient reports of their health care experience and is accepted by a variety of stakeholder groups. The measurement question was only asked of parents who responded &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Yes&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; when asked if they had made a specialist appointment in the previous 6 months. CAHPS tests their surveys for reliability and validity, and notes that the survey results &quot;will be reliable and valid if (the survey) specifications are followed&quot; (Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality, 2012). Medicaid programs are likely to contract with approved CAHPS vendors who agree to adhere to CAHPS specifications, and thus their CAHPS results would be expected to maintain their validity. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Face Validity&lt;/em&gt;. The validity of this measure was also determined from face validity, the degree to which the measure construct characterizes the concept being assessed. The face validity of the CAHPS question on specialist availability was reviewed by a panel convened by the Quality Measurement, Evaluation, Testing, Review, and Implementation Consortium (Q-METRIC). The Q-METRIC expert panel included nationally recognized experts representing pediatrics, family medicine, psychiatry, dentistry, and two parent representatives. In addition, validity was considered by experts in state Medicaid program operations, Title V (Children's Special Health Care Services) program operations, health plan quality measurement, health informatics, and health care quality measurement. In total, the Q-METRIC Availability of Specialty Services panel included 13 experts, providing a comprehensive perspective on the availability of specialty services and the measurement of quality metrics for states and health plans.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Q-METRIC expert panel concluded that this measure has a high degree of face validity through a detailed review of concepts and metrics considered to be essential to the ability of parents to obtain appointments for children referred to specialty care and treatment. Concepts and draft measures were rated by this group for their relative importance. The measure was rated as follows: parent-reported-availability of specialty appointments received a score of 6.7 on a scale of 1 to 9, with 9 representing the highest possible ranking.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Q-METRIC expert panel had additional discussion about the data that would be reported out for this measure. Prior to deciding to use the CAHPS measure, this discussion included such topics as whether to report specialist availability for new patients or for any patient seeking to make specialist appointments; whether appointments should refer to urgent or non-urgent appointments; and, finally, the role that prior authorizations may have for Medicaid patients and the difficulty this may pose for data collection.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3007" OrdBy="190" ID="578" Name="Evidence for Extent of Measure Testing" Type="citation">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ). Established child health care quality measures: child health care quality toolbox. [internet]. Rockville (MD): Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ); 2012 Sep&amp;nbsp;[accessed 2014 Jul 24]. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Dyer N, Sorra JS, Smith SA, Cleary PD, Hays RD. Psychometric properties of the Consumer Assessment of Healthcare Providers and Systems (CAHPS®) Clinician and Group Adult Visit Survey. Med Care. 2012 Nov;50 Suppl:S28-34. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=23064274&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Hays RD, Reise S, Calderón JL. How much is lost in using single items?. J Gen Intern Med. 2012 Nov;27(11):1402-3. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=22878854&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;National Quality Forum (NQF). Guidance for measure testing and evaluating scientific acceptability of measure properties. 2011 Jan. 52 p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Quality Measurement, Evaluation, Testing, Review and Implementation Consortium (Q-METRIC). Basic measure information: reporting of CAHPS data regarding availability of specialist care for children on Medicaid. Ann Arbor (MI): Quality Measurement, Evaluation, Testing, Review and Implementation Consortium (Q-METRIC); 2014 Sep. 34 p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Scholle SH, Vuong O, Ding L, Fry S, Gallagher P, Brown JA, Hays RD, Cleary PD. Development of and field test results for the CAHPS PCMH Survey. Med Care. 2012 Nov;50 Suppl:S2-10. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=23064272&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;West CP, Dyrbye LN, Satele DV, Sloan JA, Shanafelt TD. Concurrent validity of single-item measures of emotional exhaustion and depersonalization in burnout assessment. J Gen Intern Med. 2012 Nov;27(11):1445-52. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=22362127&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="580" OrdBy="210" Name="State of Use of the Measure">
    <Field FieldID="3029" OrdBy="220" ID="581" Name="State of Use" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Current routine use" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3030" OrdBy="230" ID="582" Name="Current Use" Type="picklist-choice-3">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="583" OrdBy="240" Name="Application of the Measure in its Current Use">
    <Field FieldID="3031" OrdBy="250" ID="584" Name="Measurement Setting" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="Managed Care Plans" />
      <FieldValue Value="State/Provincial Public Health Programs" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3032" OrdBy="260" ID="585" Name="Professionals Involved in Delivery of Health Services" Type="picklist-choice-3">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3033" OrdBy="270" ID="586" Name="Least Aggregated Level of Services Delivery Addressed" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="State/Provincial" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3505" OrdBy="280" ID="587" Name="Statement of Acceptable Minimum Sample Size" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Does not apply to this measure" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="41" OrdBy="290" ID="588" Name="Target Population Age" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Does not apply to this measure&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="42" OrdBy="300" ID="589" Name="Target Population Gender" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Does not apply to this measure" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="700" OrdBy="304" Name="National Framework for Public Health Quality">
    <Field FieldID="4620" OrdBy="305" ID="701" Name="Public Health Aims for Quality" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Population-centered" />
      <FieldValue Value="Transparency" />
      <FieldValue Value="Vigilant" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="660" OrdBy="310" Name="National Strategy for Quality Improvement in Health Care">
    <Field FieldID="3522" OrdBy="320" ID="661" Name="National Quality Strategy Aim" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Healthy People/Healthy Communities&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3525" OrdBy="330" ID="662" Name="National Quality Strategy Priority" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="590" OrdBy="340" Name="Institute of Medicine (IOM) National Health Care Quality Report Categories">
    <Field FieldID="3163" OrdBy="350" ID="591" Name="IOM Care Need" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="Not within an IOM Care Need" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3164" OrdBy="360" ID="592" Name="IOM Domain" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="Not within an IOM Domain" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="593" OrdBy="370" Name="Data Collection for the Measure">
    <Field FieldID="3506" OrdBy="380" ID="594" Name="Case Finding Period" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3054" OrdBy="390" ID="595" Name="Denominator Sampling Frame" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Geographically defined" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3057" OrdBy="400" ID="598" Name="Denominator (Index) Event or Characteristic" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="Geographic Location" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3058" OrdBy="410" ID="599" Name="Denominator Time Window" Type="picklist-choice-3">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="55" OrdBy="420" ID="596" Name="Denominator Inclusions/Exclusions" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xA;The denominator is the individual state required to report the CAHPS Health Plan Survey &amp;ndash; Child Medicaid version, and therefore will always be one (1).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xA;None&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3507" OrdBy="430" ID="597" Name="Exclusions/Exceptions" Type="picklist-choice-4">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="59" OrdBy="440" ID="600" Name="Numerator Inclusions/Exclusions" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xA;A numerator of one (1) demonstrates that a particular state publicly reports the results of the individual question on specialist availability among its Medicaid population. If the numerator is zero (0), the state does not publicly report the results.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul class=&quot;Note&quot; style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;The specialist availability question is written as follows in the Consumer Assessment of Healthcare Providers and Systems (CAHPS) surveys currently in use:&#xA;    &lt;ul class=&quot;NoBullets&quot; style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Version 5.0: In the last 6 months, how often did you get appointments for your child to see a specialist as soon as he or she needed?&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Version 4.0: In the last 6 months, how often was it easy to get appointments for your child with specialists?&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Reporting of this CAHPS measure by a state program may take any form that clearly conveys the results of this question; it may be reported alone, or as one component of a broader array of parent-reported availability and access measures that include this specific specialist availability question. &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xA;None&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3061" OrdBy="450" ID="601" Name="Numerator Search Strategy" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Fixed time period or point in time" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3062" OrdBy="460" ID="602" Name="Data Source" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Patient/Individual survey" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3065" OrdBy="470" ID="603" Name="Type of Health State" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Does not apply to this measure" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3066" OrdBy="480" ID="604" Name="Instruments Used and/or Associated with the Measure" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;CAHPS Health Plan Survey (Child Medicaid Questionnaire)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="605" OrdBy="490" Name="Computation of the Measure">
    <Field FieldID="3508" OrdBy="500" ID="606" Name="Measure Specifies Disaggregation" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Does not apply to this measure" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3067" OrdBy="520" ID="608" Name="Scoring" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Dichotomous" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3068" OrdBy="530" ID="609" Name="Interpretation of Score" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Desired value is presence of a characteristic" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3090" OrdBy="540" ID="610" Name="Allowance for Patient or Population Factors" Type="picklist-choice-3">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3070" OrdBy="560" ID="612" Name="Standard of Comparison" Type="picklist-choice-3">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="615" OrdBy="590" Name="Identifying Information">
    <Field FieldID="73" OrdBy="600" ID="616" Name="Original Title" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reporting of CAHPS data regarding availability of specialist care for children on Medicaid.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="74" OrdBy="610" ID="617" Name="Measure Collection Name" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="Availability of Specialty Services Measures" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="16" OrdBy="650" ID="621" Name="Submitter" Type="orglist">
      <FieldValue Value="Quality Measurement, Evaluation, Testing, Review, and Implementation Consortium (Q-METRIC) - Academic Affiliated Research Institute" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="17" OrdBy="660" ID="622" Name="Developer" Type="orglist-p">
      <FieldValue Value="Quality Measurement, Evaluation, Testing, Review, and Implementation Consortium (Q-METRIC) - Academic Affiliated Research Institute" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="79" OrdBy="670" ID="623" Name="Funding Source(s)" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This work was funded by the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ) and the Centers for Medicare &amp;amp; Medicaid Services (CMS) under the Children's Health Insurance Program Reauthorization Act (CHIPRA) Pediatric Quality Measures Program Centers of Excellence grant number U18 HS020516.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="80" OrdBy="680" ID="624" Name="Composition of the Group that Developed the Measure" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Availability of Specialty Services Expert Panels&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Representative/Feasibility Panel&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;George Baker, MD, Retired, Co-Director, Office of Medical Affairs for Michigan Medicaid, Medical Director of Michigan's Title V program for Children and Youth with Special Health Care Needs, Michigan Department of Community Health, Lansing, MI &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Laura-Mae Baldwin, MD, MPH, Director of Research and Professor, Department of Family Medicine, University of Washington, Seattle, WA &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Patricia Barrett, MHSA, Vice President for Product Development, National Committee for Quality Assurance, Washington, DC &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Angie Davis, MA, Parent Representative, DeWitt, MI &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Lisa Huckleberry, Parent Representative, DeWitt, MI &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Renee Jenkins, MD, FAAP, Professor, Department of Pediatrics and Child Health, Howard University College of Medicine, Washington, DC &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;David Kelley, MD, MPA, Chief Medical Officer, Office of Medical Assistance Programs, Pennsylvania Department of Public Welfare, Harrisburg, PA &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Maureen Milligan, PhD, MPA, MA, Director, Texas Institute of Health Care Quality and Efficiency, Texas Health and Human Services Commission, Austin, TX &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Sue Moran, BSN, MPH, Director of the Bureau of Medicaid Program Operations and Quality Assurance, Michigan Department of Community Health, Lansing, MI &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;R. Gary Rozier, DDS, MPH, Director and Professor, Dental Public Health and Residency Training Program, Department of Health Policy and Management, University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, Chapel Hill, NC &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Aradhana (Bela) Sood, MD, MSHA, FAACAP, Professor and Chair, Division of Child and Adolescent Psychiatry, Medical Director, Virginia Treatment Center for Children, Virginia Commonwealth University, Richmond, VA &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Mark Wietecha, MS, MBA, President and CEO, Children's Hospital Association, Alexandria, VA &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Quality Measurement, Evaluation, Testing, Review, and Implementation Consortium (Q-METRIC) Investigators&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Sarah J. Clark, MPH, Associate Research Scientist, Department of Pediatrics, School of Medicine, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, MI &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Meredith P. Riebschleger, MD, MS, Clinical Lecturer, Department of Pediatrics and Communicable Diseases, Pediatric Rheumatology, School of Medicine, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, MI &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Gary L. Freed, MD, MPH, Professor of Pediatrics, School of Medicine and Professor of Health Management and Policy, School of Public Health, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, MI (principal investigator) &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Kevin J. Dombkowski, DrPH, MS, Research Associate Professor of Pediatrics, School of Medicine, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, MI &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="81" OrdBy="690" ID="625" Name="Financial Disclosures/Other Potential Conflicts of Interest" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="19" OrdBy="730" ID="629" Name="Adaptation" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This measure was not adapted from another source.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3086" OrdBy="740" ID="630" Name="Date of Most Current Version in NQMC" Type="date">
      <FieldValue Value="2014 Sep" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3511" OrdBy="750" ID="631" Name="Measure Maintenance" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3512" OrdBy="760" ID="632" Name="Date of Next Anticipated Revision" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="20" OrdBy="770" ID="633" Name="Measure Status" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the current release of the measure.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The measure developer reaffirmed the currency of this measure in January 2016. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="14" OrdBy="780" ID="634" Name="Measure Availability" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Source available from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://chear.org/sites/default/files/stories/pdfs/avail1_cahpsspecialty.pdf&quot; title=&quot;Q-METRIC Web site&quot;&gt;Quality Measurement, Evaluation, Testing, Review, and Implementation Consortium (Q-METRIC) Web site&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chear.org/qmetric&quot; title=&quot;Q-METRIC Web site&quot;&gt;Support documents&lt;/a&gt; are also available.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For more information, contact Q-METRIC at 300 North Ingalls Street, Room 6C08, SPC 5456, Ann Arbor, MI 48109-5456; Phone: 734-232-0657; Fax: 734-764-2599.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="87" OrdBy="800" ID="636" Name="NQMC Status" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This NQMC summary was completed by ECRI Institute on May 5, 2015. The information was verified by the measure developer on June 10, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The information was reaffirmed by the measure developer on January 7, 2016. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="88" OrdBy="810" ID="637" Name="Copyright Statement" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This NQMC summary is based on the original measure, which is subject to the measure developer's copyright restrictions. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Inform Quality Measurement, Evaluation, Testing, Review, and Implementation Consortium (Q-METRIC) if users implement the measures in their health care settings. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="641" OrdBy="850" Name="Production">
    <Field FieldID="1" OrdBy="1366" ID="562" Name="Source(s)" Type="citation">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Quality Measurement, Evaluation, Testing, Review and Implementation Consortium (Q-METRIC). Basic measure information: reporting of CAHPS data regarding availability of specialist care for children on Medicaid. Ann Arbor (MI): Quality Measurement, Evaluation, Testing, Review and Implementation Consortium (Q-METRIC); 2014 Sep. 34 p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="99999" OrdBy="99999" Name="Disclaimer">
    <Field FieldID="99999" OrdBy="99999" ID="99999" Name="NQMC Disclaimer" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;p&gt;The National Quality Measures Clearinghouse™ (NQMC) does not develop, produce, approve, or endorse the measures represented on this site.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;All measures summarized by NQMC and hosted on our site are produced under the auspices of medical specialty societies, relevant professional associations, public and private organizations, other government agencies, health care organizations or plans, individuals, and similar entities.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Measures represented on the NQMC Web site are submitted by measure developers, and are screened solely to determine that they meet the &lt;a href=&quot;/help-and-about/summaries/inclusion-criteria&quot;&gt;NQMC Inclusion Criteria&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;NQMC, AHRQ, and its contractor ECRI Institute make no warranties concerning the content or its reliability and/or validity of the quality measures and related materials represented on this site. Moreover, the views and opinions of developers or authors of measures represented on this site do not necessarily state or reflect those of NQMC, AHRQ, or its contractor, ECRI Institute, and inclusion or hosting of measures in NQMC may not be used for advertising or commercial endorsement purposes.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Readers with questions regarding measure content are directed to contact the measure developer.&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
</Version>