<Version>
  <xmlSource>This XML content was developed by AHRQ's contractor ECRI Institute for the National Quality Measures Clearinghouse (NQMC).</xmlSource>
  <Section SecID="560" OrdBy="10" Name="General">
    <Field FieldID="11" OrdBy="20" ID="561" Name="Title" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_title&quot;&gt;Abdominal aortic aneurysm (AAA) repair mortality: percentage of in-hospital deaths per 1,000 discharges with AAA repair, ages 18 years and older.&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="1" OrdBy="30" ID="562" Name="Source(s)" Type="citation">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;AHRQ QI research version 5.0. Inpatient quality indicator 11 technical specifications: abdominal aortic aneurysm (AAA) repair mortality rate. Rockville (MD): Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ); 2015 Mar. 3 p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;National Quality Forum measure information: abdominal aortic aneurysm (AAA) repair mortality rate (IQI 11). Washington (DC): National Quality Forum (NQF); 2014 Apr 1. 13 p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="563" OrdBy="40" Name="Measure Domain">
    <Field FieldID="3025" OrdBy="50" ID="564" Name="Primary Measure Domain" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Clinical Quality Measures: Outcome" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3026" OrdBy="60" ID="565" Name="Secondary Measure Domain" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Does not apply to this measure" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="566" OrdBy="70" Name="Brief Abstract">
    <Field FieldID="34" OrdBy="80" ID="567" Name="Description" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This measure is used to assess the percentage of in-hospital deaths per 1,000 discharges with abdominal aortic aneurysm (AAA) repair, ages 18 years and older. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The indicator is stratified into four groups by 1) type of AAA repair (open vs. endovascular) and 2) AAA rupture status. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cases are assigned to strata according to a hierarchy based on mortality, with cases being assigned to the stratum with the highest mortality for which the case qualifies. In the case of AAA Repair Mortality the current hierarchy is as follows: &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Strata hierarchy (listed from highest mortality to lowest mortality): &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ol style=&quot;list-style-type: decimal;&quot; start=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Stratum A (Open repair of ruptured AAA) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Stratum C (Endovascular repair of ruptured AAA) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Stratum B (Open repair of unruptured AAA) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Stratum D (Endovascular repair of unruptured AAA) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This measure summary represents the overall rate. See also the &quot;Basis for Disaggregation&quot; field.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="21" OrdBy="90" ID="568" Name="Rationale" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Abdominal aortic aneurysm (AAA) repair is a relatively rare procedure that requires proficiency with the use of complex equipment; and technical errors may lead to clinically significant complications, such as arrhythmias, acute myocardial infarction, colonic ischemia, and death. Better processes of care may reduce mortality for AAA repair, which represents better quality care.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3500" OrdBy="100" ID="569" Name="Evidence for Rationale" Type="citation">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;National Quality Forum measure information: abdominal aortic aneurysm (AAA) repair mortality rate (IQI 11). Washington (DC): National Quality Forum (NQF); 2014 Apr 1. 13 p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3022" OrdBy="110" ID="570" Name="Primary Health Components" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Abdominal aortic aneurysm (AAA); open or endovascular AAA repair; death&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="23" OrdBy="120" ID="571" Name="Denominator Description" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Discharges, for patients ages 18 years and older, with the following: &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Any-listed International Classification of Diseases, Ninth Revision, Clinical Modification (ICD-9-CM) diagnosis codes for ruptured abdominal aortic aneurysm (AAA) and any-listed ICD-9-CM procedure code for open AAA repair; or &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Any-listed ICD-9-CM diagnosis codes for unruptured AAA and any-listed ICD-9-CM procedure codes for open AAA repair; or &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Any-listed ICD-9-CM diagnosis codes for ruptured AAA and any-listed ICD-9-CM procedure codes for endovascular AAA repair; or &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Any-listed ICD-9-CM diagnosis codes for unruptured AAA and any-listed ICD-9-CM procedure codes for endovascular AAA repair &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;See the related &quot;Denominator Inclusions/Exclusions&quot; field.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="24" OrdBy="130" ID="572" Name="Numerator Description" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Number of deaths (DISP=20) among cases meeting the inclusion and exclusion rules for the denominator&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="573" OrdBy="140" Name="Evidence Supporting the Measure">
    <Field FieldID="3027" OrdBy="150" ID="574" Name="Type of Evidence Supporting the Criterion of Quality for the Measure" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="One or more research studies published in a National Library of Medicine (NLM) indexed, peer-reviewed journal" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3501" OrdBy="160" ID="575" Name="Additional Information Supporting Need for the Measure" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3072" OrdBy="180" ID="577" Name="Extent of Measure Testing" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reliability Testing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Data/Sample&lt;/em&gt;. Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ) 2007 State Inpatient Databases (SID) with 4,000 hospitals and 30 million adult discharges. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Analytic Method&lt;/em&gt;. Literature summary, expert panels and empirical analysis.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Testing Results&lt;/em&gt;. The relatively small number of abdominal aortic aneurysm (AAA) resections performed by each hospital suggests that mortality rates at the hospital level are likely to be unreliable. Empirical evidence shows that this indicator is precise, with a raw provider level mean of 21.5% and a substantial standard deviation of 26.8% (&quot;Healthcare Cost and Utilization Project [HCUP] Nationwide Inpatient Sample and State 88 Databases,&quot; n.d.). &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Relative to other indicators, a higher percentage of the variation occurs at the provider level, rather than the discharge level. The signal ratio (i.e., the proportion of the total variation across providers that is truly related to systematic differences in provider performance rather than random variation) is low, at 30.7%, indicating that some of the observed differences in provider performance.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The signal to noise ratio is the ratio of the between hospital variance (signal) to the within hospital variance (noise). The formula is signal / (signal + noise). The ratio itself is only a diagnostic for the degree of variance in the risk-adjusted rate systematically associated with the provider. Therefore, what matters is the magnitude of the variance in the &quot;smoothed&quot; rate (that is, the variance in the risk-adjusted rate after the application of the univariate shrinkage estimator based on the signal ratio). What the data demonstrate is systematic variation in the provider level rate of 2.6 to 7.6 per 100 from the 5th to 95th percentile after a signal ratio of 0.307 is applied as the shrinkage estimator (that is, after accounting for variation due to random factors). An additional technique applied to the indicator is the use of multivariate signal extraction (an extension of univariate shrinkage estimator) to increase effective sample size to the extent that individual measures are correlated (Staiger et. al., 2009).&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Validity Testing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Data/Sample&lt;/em&gt;. AHRQ 2007 SID with 4,000 hospitals and 30 million adult discharges.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Empirical evidence shows that AAA repair mortality is positively related to other post-procedural mortality measures, such as craniotomy (r=.28, p less than .0001) and coronary artery bypass graft (CABG) (r=.17, p less than .01) (&quot;HCUP Nationwide Inpatient Sample,&quot; n.d.).&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Veterans Integrated Service Networks (VISNs); and Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) versus non-VA (Nationwide Inpatient Sample) using VA inpatient data (2004 to 2007) (Pearce et al., 1999). &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A survey of hospital and system leaders (presidents/chief executive officers [CEOs]) that was conducted in the first six months of 2006 with a total of 562 respondents. Hospital-level data for these composite measures were produced by applying the Inpatient Quality Indicator (IQI) to the SID of the HCUP sponsored by AHRQ. The SID includes all-payer data on inpatient stays from virtually all community hospitals in each participating state (Rutledge et al., 1996).&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The developer used 100 percent national analytic files from the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services (CMS) for the calendar years 2003 through 2006. Medicare Provider Analysis and Review (MEDPAR) files, which contain hospital discharge abstracts for all fee-for-service acute care hospitalizations of all U.S. Medicare recipients, were used to create our main analytical datasets. The Medicare denominator file was used to assess patient vital status at 30 days. Using appropriate procedure codes from the International Classification of Diseases, version 9 (ICD-9 codes), the developer identified all patients aged 65 to 99 undergoing elective AAA repair and pancreatectomy (Pilcher et al., 1980).&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Analytic Method&lt;/em&gt;. Literature summary, expert panels and empirical analysis &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;VA- and VISN-level IQI observed rates, risk-adjusted rates, and observed to expected ratios (O/Es). The developer examined the trends in VA- and VISN-level rates using weighted linear regression, variation in VISN-level O/Es, and compared VA to non-VA trends (Pearce et al., 1999).&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A t-test was used to determine the significance of differences in quality measures (Rutledge et al., 1996). &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The developer first estimated risk-adjusted hospital mortality rates during 2003 to 2004. Mortality was defined as death within 30 days of operation or before hospital discharge. Patient age, gender, race, urgency of operation, median ZIP-code income, and coexisting medical conditions was adjusted for. Using logistic regression, the expected number of deaths in each hospital was estimated and then divided the observed deaths by this expected number of deaths to obtain the ratio of observed to expected mortality (O/E ratio). The developer then multiplied the O/E ratio by the average mortality rate to obtain a risk-adjusted mortality rate for each hospital. Next a hierarchical modeling techniques was used to adjust these mortality estimates for reliability. Using random effects logistic regression models, empirical Bayes predictions of mortality for each hospital were generated (Pilcher et al., 1980).&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Testing Results&lt;/em&gt;. The correlation between hospital or physician characteristics and in-hospital mortality in most studies supports the validity of in-hospital mortality as a measure of quality (Pearce et al., 1999; Rutledge et al., 1996). Finally, excessive blood loss, which is a potentially preventable complication of surgery, has been identified as the most important predictor of mortality after elective AAA repair (Pilcher et al., 1980). Empirical evidence shows that AAA repair mortality is positively related to other post-procedural mortality measures, such as craniotomy (r=.28, p less than .0001) and CABG (r=.17, p less than .01). &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Refer to the original measure documentation for additional measure testing information.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3007" OrdBy="190" ID="578" Name="Evidence for Extent of Measure Testing" Type="citation">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Healthcare Cost and Utilization Project (HCUP) Nationwide Inpatient Sample and State 88 Databases. Rockville (MD): Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ); &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Healthcare Cost and Utilization Project (HCUP) Nationwide Inpatient Sample. Rockville (MD): Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ); &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;National Quality Forum measure information: abdominal aortic aneurysm (AAA) repair mortality rate (IQI 11). Washington (DC): National Quality Forum (NQF); 2014 Apr 1. 13 p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Pearce WH, Parker MA, Feinglass J, Ujiki M, Manheim LM. The importance of surgeon volume and training in outcomes for vascular surgical procedures. J Vasc Surg. 1999 May;29(5):768-76; discussion 777-8. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=10231626&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Pilcher DB, Davis JH, Ashikaga T, Bookwalter J, Butsch DW, Chase CR, Ellman BR, Vacek PM, Lord CF. Treatment of abdominal aortic aneurysm in an entire state over 7 1/2 years. Am J Surg. 1980 Apr;139(4):487-94. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=6892754&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Rutledge R, Oller DW, Meyer AA, Johnson GJ Jr. A statewide, population-based time-series analysis of the outcome of ruptured abdominal aortic aneurysm. Ann Surg. 1996 May;223(5):492-502; discussion 503-5. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=8651740&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Staiger DO, Dimick JB, Baser O, Fan Z, Birkmeyer JD. Empirically derived composite measures of surgical performance. Med Care. 2009 Feb;47(2):226-33. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=19169124&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="580" OrdBy="210" Name="State of Use of the Measure">
    <Field FieldID="3029" OrdBy="220" ID="581" Name="State of Use" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Current routine use" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3030" OrdBy="230" ID="582" Name="Current Use" Type="picklist-choice-3">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="583" OrdBy="240" Name="Application of the Measure in its Current Use">
    <Field FieldID="3031" OrdBy="250" ID="584" Name="Measurement Setting" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="Hospital Inpatient" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3032" OrdBy="260" ID="585" Name="Professionals Involved in Delivery of Health Services" Type="picklist-choice-3">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3033" OrdBy="270" ID="586" Name="Least Aggregated Level of Services Delivery Addressed" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Single Health Care Delivery or Public Health Organizations" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3505" OrdBy="280" ID="587" Name="Statement of Acceptable Minimum Sample Size" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Does not apply to this measure" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="41" OrdBy="290" ID="588" Name="Target Population Age" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Age greater than or equal to 18 years&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="42" OrdBy="300" ID="589" Name="Target Population Gender" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Either male or female" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="660" OrdBy="310" Name="National Strategy for Quality Improvement in Health Care">
    <Field FieldID="3522" OrdBy="320" ID="661" Name="National Quality Strategy Aim" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Better Care&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3525" OrdBy="330" ID="662" Name="National Quality Strategy Priority" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Making Care Safer&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Prevention and Treatment of Leading Causes of Mortality&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="590" OrdBy="340" Name="Institute of Medicine (IOM) National Health Care Quality Report Categories">
    <Field FieldID="3163" OrdBy="350" ID="591" Name="IOM Care Need" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="Getting Better" />
      <FieldValue Value="Living with Illness" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3164" OrdBy="360" ID="592" Name="IOM Domain" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="Effectiveness" />
      <FieldValue Value="Safety" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="593" OrdBy="370" Name="Data Collection for the Measure">
    <Field FieldID="3506" OrdBy="380" ID="594" Name="Case Finding Period" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Time window can be determined by user, but is generally a calendar year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3054" OrdBy="390" ID="595" Name="Denominator Sampling Frame" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Patients associated with provider" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3057" OrdBy="400" ID="598" Name="Denominator (Index) Event or Characteristic" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="Clinical Condition" />
      <FieldValue Value="Institutionalization" />
      <FieldValue Value="Patient/Individual (Consumer) Characteristic" />
      <FieldValue Value="Therapeutic Intervention" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3058" OrdBy="410" ID="599" Name="Denominator Time Window" Type="picklist-choice-3">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="55" OrdBy="420" ID="596" Name="Denominator Inclusions/Exclusions" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Discharges, for patients ages 18 years and older, with the following &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Any-listed International Classification of Diseases, Ninth Revision, Clinical Modification (ICD-9-CM) diagnosis codes for ruptured abdominal aortic aneurysm (AAA) and any-listed ICD-9-CM procedure code for open AAA repair; or &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Any-listed ICD-9-CM diagnosis codes for unruptured AAA and any-listed ICD-9-CM procedure codes for open AAA repair; or &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Any-listed ICD-9-CM diagnosis codes for ruptured AAA and any-listed ICD-9-CM procedure codes for endovascular AAA repair; or &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Any-listed ICD-9-CM diagnosis codes for unruptured AAA and any-listed ICD-9-CM procedure codes for endovascular AAA repair &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: Refer to the original measure documentation for ICD-9-CM codes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Exclude cases:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Transferring to another short-term hospital (DISP=2) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Major Diagnostic Categories (MDC) 14 (pregnancy, childbirth, and puerperium) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;With missing discharge disposition (DISP=missing), gender (SEX=missing), age (AGE=missing), quarter (DQTR=missing), year (YEAR=missing) or principal diagnosis (DX1=missing) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3507" OrdBy="430" ID="597" Name="Exclusions/Exceptions" Type="picklist-choice-4">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="59" OrdBy="440" ID="600" Name="Numerator Inclusions/Exclusions" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Number of deaths (DISP=20) among cases meeting the inclusion and exclusion rules for the denominator &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3061" OrdBy="450" ID="601" Name="Numerator Search Strategy" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Institutionalization" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3062" OrdBy="460" ID="602" Name="Data Source" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Administrative clinical data" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3065" OrdBy="470" ID="603" Name="Type of Health State" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Death" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3066" OrdBy="480" ID="604" Name="Instruments Used and/or Associated with the Measure" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="605" OrdBy="490" Name="Computation of the Measure">
    <Field FieldID="3508" OrdBy="500" ID="606" Name="Measure Specifies Disaggregation" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Measure is disaggregated into categories based on different definitions of the denominator and/or numerator" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3509" OrdBy="510" ID="607" Name="Basis for Disaggregation" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The indicator is stratified into four groups by 1) type of abdominal aortic aneurysm (AAA) repair (open vs. endovascular) and 2) AAA rupture status.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cases are assigned to strata according to a hierarchy based on mortality, with cases being assigned to the stratum with the highest mortality for which the case qualifies. In the case of AAA Repair Mortality, the current hierarchy is as follows: &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Strata hierarchy (listed from highest mortality to lowest mortality): &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ol style=&quot;list-style-type: decimal;&quot; start=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Stratum A (Open repair of ruptured AAA) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Stratum C (Endovascular repair of ruptured AAA) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Stratum B (Open repair of unruptured AAA) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Stratum D (Endovascular repair of unruptured AAA) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Numerator&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Stratum A (Open repair of ruptured AAA)&lt;/span&gt;: Number of deaths (DISP=20) among cases meeting the inclusion and exclusion rules for the denominator. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Stratum B (Open repair of unruptured AAA)&lt;/span&gt;: Number of deaths (DISP=20) among cases meeting the inclusion and exclusion rules for the denominator. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Stratum C (Endovascular repair of ruptured AAA)&lt;/span&gt;: Number of deaths (DISP=20) among cases meeting the inclusion and exclusion rules for the denominator. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Stratum D (Endovascular repair of unruptured AAA)&lt;/span&gt;: Number of deaths (DISP=20) among cases meeting the inclusion and exclusion rules for the denominator. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Denominator&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Stratum A (Open repair of ruptured AAA)&lt;/span&gt;: Discharges, for patients ages 18 years and older, with any-listed International Classification of Diseases, Ninth Revision, Clinical Modification (ICD-9-CM) diagnosis code for ruptured AAA and any-listed ICD-9-CM procedure code for open AAA repair. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Stratum B (Open repair of unruptured AAA)&lt;/span&gt;: Discharges, for patients ages 18 years and older, with any-listed ICD-9-CM diagnosis code for unruptured AAA and any-listed ICD-9-CM procedure code for open AAA repair. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Stratum C (Endovascular repair of ruptured AAA)&lt;/span&gt;: Discharges, for patients ages 18 years and older, with any-listed ICD-9-CM diagnosis code for ruptured AAA and any-listed ICD-9-CM procedure code for endovascular AAA repair. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Stratum D (Endovascular repair of unruptured AAA)&lt;/span&gt;: Discharges, for patients ages 18 years and older, with any-listed ICD-9-CM diagnosis code for unruptured AAA and any-listed ICD-9-CM procedure code for endovascular AAA repair. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3067" OrdBy="520" ID="608" Name="Scoring" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Rate/Proportion" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3068" OrdBy="530" ID="609" Name="Interpretation of Score" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Desired value is a lower score" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3090" OrdBy="540" ID="610" Name="Allowance for Patient or Population Factors" Type="picklist-choice-3">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3069" OrdBy="550" ID="611" Name="Description of Allowance for Patient or Population Factors" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The predicted value for each case is computed using a hierarchical model (logistic regression with hospital random effect) and covariates for gender, age in years (in 5-year age groups), All Patient Refined-Diagnosis Related Group (APR-DRG) and APR-DRG risk of-mortality subclass. The reference population used in the model is the universe of discharges for states that participate in the Healthcare Cost and Utilization Project (HCUP) State Inpatient Databases (SID) for the year 2008 (updated annually), a database consisting of 43 states and approximately 30 million adult discharges and 4,000 hospitals. The expected rate is computed as the sum of the predicted value for each case divided by the number of cases for the unit of analysis of interest (i.e., hospital). The risk adjusted rate is computed using indirect standardization as the observed rate divided by the expected rate, multiplied by the reference population rate. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Refer to the original measure documentation for the risk adjustment factors. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3070" OrdBy="560" ID="612" Name="Standard of Comparison" Type="picklist-choice-3">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="615" OrdBy="590" Name="Identifying Information">
    <Field FieldID="73" OrdBy="600" ID="616" Name="Original Title" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;IQI 11: abdominal aortic aneurysm (AAA) repair mortality rate.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="74" OrdBy="610" ID="617" Name="Measure Collection Name" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ) Quality Indicators" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="75" OrdBy="620" ID="618" Name="Measure Set Name" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="Inpatient Quality Indicators" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="16" OrdBy="650" ID="621" Name="Submitter" Type="orglist">
      <FieldValue Value="Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality - Federal Government Agency [U.S.]" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="17" OrdBy="660" ID="622" Name="Developer" Type="orglist-p">
      <FieldValue Value="Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality - Federal Government Agency [U.S.]" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="79" OrdBy="670" ID="623" Name="Funding Source(s)" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="80" OrdBy="680" ID="624" Name="Composition of the Group that Developed the Measure" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ) Quality Indicator (QI) measures are developed by a team of clinical and measurement experts in collaboration with AHRQ. The AHRQ QIs are continually updated as a result of new research evidence and validation efforts, user feedback, guidance from the National Quality Forum (NQF), and general advances in the science of quality measurement. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="81" OrdBy="690" ID="625" Name="Financial Disclosures/Other Potential Conflicts of Interest" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;None&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="82" OrdBy="700" ID="626" Name="Endorser" Type="orglist">
      <FieldValue Value="National Quality Forum - None" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3091" OrdBy="705" ID="696" Name="NQF Number" Type="plain-text">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3510" OrdBy="710" ID="627" Name="Date of Endorsement" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;2015 Jan 5&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="19" OrdBy="730" ID="629" Name="Adaptation" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This measure was not adapted from another source.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3086" OrdBy="740" ID="630" Name="Date of Most Current Version in NQMC" Type="date">
      <FieldValue Value="2015 Mar" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3511" OrdBy="750" ID="631" Name="Measure Maintenance" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Measure is reviewed and updated on a yearly basis&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3512" OrdBy="760" ID="632" Name="Date of Next Anticipated Revision" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Spring 2016 (version 6.0, including International Classification of Diseases, Tenth Revision, Clinical Modification [ICD-10-CM] and International Classification of Diseases, Tenth Revision, Procedure Coding System [ICD-10-PCS] compatible software)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="20" OrdBy="770" ID="633" Name="Measure Status" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the current release of the measure. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This measure updates a previous version: AHRQ QI. Inpatient quality indicators #11: technical specifications. Abdominal aortic artery (AAA) repair mortality rate [version 4.4]. Rockville (MD): Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ); 2012 Mar. 1 p. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="14" OrdBy="780" ID="634" Name="Measure Availability" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Source available from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.qualityindicators.ahrq.gov/Downloads/Modules/IQI/V50/TechSpecs/IQI_11_Abdominal_Aortic_Aneurysm_(AAA)_Repair_Mortality_Rate.pdf&quot; title=&quot;AHRQ QI Web site&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ) Quality Indicators (QI) Web site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For more information, contact the AHRQ QI Support Team at E-mail: &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:QIsupport@ahrq.hhs.gov&quot;&gt;QIsupport@ahrq.hhs.gov&lt;/a&gt;; Phone: 301-427-1949.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="15" OrdBy="790" ID="635" Name="Companion Documents" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following are available:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;AHRQ quality indicators. Inpatient quality indicators (IQI) parameter estimates [version 5.0]. Rockville (MD): Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ); 2015 Mar. 42 p. This document is available from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.qualityindicators.ahrq.gov/Downloads/Modules/IQI/V50/Parameter_Estimates_IQI_50.pdf.pdf&quot; title=&quot;AHRQ QI Web site&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;AHRQ Quality Indicators Web site&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;AHRQ quality indicators. Inpatient quality indicators benchmark data tables [version 5.0]. Rockville (MD): Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ); 2015 Mar. 22 p. This document is available from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.qualityindicators.ahrq.gov/Downloads/Modules/IQI/V50/Version_50_Benchmark_Tables_IQI.pdf&quot; title=&quot;AHRQ QI Web site&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;AHRQ Quality Indicators Web site&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;AHRQ quality indicators. Inpatient quality indicators composite measure workgroup. Final report. Rockville (MD): Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ); 2008 Mar. various p. This document is available from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.qualityindicators.ahrq.gov/Downloads/Modules/IQI/IQI_Composite_Development.pdf&quot; title=&quot;AHRQ QI Web site&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;AHRQ Quality Indicators Web site&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;HCUPnet: a tool for identifying, tracking, and analyzing national hospital statistics. [Web site]. Rockville (MD): Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ); [accessed 2015 Sep 10]. HCUPnet is available from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://hcupnet.ahrq.gov/&quot; title=&quot;AHRQ Web site&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;AHRQ Web site&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="87" OrdBy="800" ID="636" Name="NQMC Status" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This NQMC summary was completed by ECRI on December 4, 2002. The information was verified by the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality on December 26, 2002. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This NQMC summary was updated by ECRI on April 7, 2004, August 19, 2004, and March 4, 2005. The information was verified by the measure developer on April 22, 2005. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This NQMC summary was updated by ECRI Institute on August 17, 2006, on May 29, 2007, on October 20, 2008 and on August 27, 2010. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This NQMC summary was reviewed and edited by ECRI Institute on July 13, 2011. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This NQMC summary was retrofitted into the new template on July 14, 2011. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This NQMC summary was updated by ECRI Institute on March 25, 2013 and again on December 9, 2015. The information was verified by the measure developer on February 16, 2016. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="88" OrdBy="810" ID="637" Name="Copyright Statement" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;No copyright restrictions apply.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="641" OrdBy="850" Name="Production">
    <Field FieldID="1" OrdBy="1366" ID="562" Name="Source(s)" Type="citation">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;AHRQ QI research version 5.0. Inpatient quality indicator 11 technical specifications: abdominal aortic aneurysm (AAA) repair mortality rate. Rockville (MD): Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ); 2015 Mar. 3 p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;National Quality Forum measure information: abdominal aortic aneurysm (AAA) repair mortality rate (IQI 11). Washington (DC): National Quality Forum (NQF); 2014 Apr 1. 13 p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="99999" OrdBy="99999" Name="Disclaimer">
    <Field FieldID="99999" OrdBy="99999" ID="99999" Name="NQMC Disclaimer" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;p&gt;The National Quality Measures Clearinghouse™ (NQMC) does not develop, produce, approve, or endorse the measures represented on this site.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;All measures summarized by NQMC and hosted on our site are produced under the auspices of medical specialty societies, relevant professional associations, public and private organizations, other government agencies, health care organizations or plans, individuals, and similar entities.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Measures represented on the NQMC Web site are submitted by measure developers, and are screened solely to determine that they meet the &lt;a href=&quot;/help-and-about/summaries/inclusion-criteria&quot;&gt;NQMC Inclusion Criteria&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;NQMC, AHRQ, and its contractor ECRI Institute make no warranties concerning the content or its reliability and/or validity of the quality measures and related materials represented on this site. Moreover, the views and opinions of developers or authors of measures represented on this site do not necessarily state or reflect those of NQMC, AHRQ, or its contractor, ECRI Institute, and inclusion or hosting of measures in NQMC may not be used for advertising or commercial endorsement purposes.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Readers with questions regarding measure content are directed to contact the measure developer.&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
</Version>