<Version>
  <xmlSource>This XML content was developed by AHRQ's contractor ECRI Institute for the National Quality Measures Clearinghouse (NQMC).</xmlSource>
  <Section SecID="560" OrdBy="10" Name="General">
    <Field FieldID="11" OrdBy="20" ID="561" Name="Title" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_title&quot;&gt;Sepsis: proportion of hospitals with a specific written protocol to identify and treat children with sepsis syndrome in the ED.&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="1" OrdBy="30" ID="562" Name="Source(s)" Type="citation">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Quality Measurement, Evaluation, Testing, Review, and Implementation Consortium (Q-METRIC). Basic measure information: protocol for identifying and treating children with sepsis syndrome in the emergency&#xD;&#xA;department. Ann Arbor (MI): Quality Measurement, Evaluation, Testing, Review, and Implementation Consortium; 2014 Aug. 42 p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="563" OrdBy="40" Name="Measure Domain">
    <Field FieldID="3025" OrdBy="50" ID="564" Name="Primary Measure Domain" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Clinical Quality Measures: Structure" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3026" OrdBy="60" ID="565" Name="Secondary Measure Domain" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Does not apply to this measure" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="566" OrdBy="70" Name="Brief Abstract">
    <Field FieldID="34" OrdBy="80" ID="567" Name="Description" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This measure is used to assess the proportion of hospitals with a specific written protocol to identify and treat children with sepsis syndrome in the emergency department (ED).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="21" OrdBy="90" ID="568" Name="Rationale" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sepsis is a potentially catastrophic condition that can escalate from infection to organ failure and death within hours. While mortality rates for pediatric sepsis have decreased over time, 4% to 10% of hospitalized children with sepsis in the United States die (Watson et al., 2003; Odetola, Gebremariam, &amp;amp; Freed, 2007). Also, annual hospital treatment costs are significant, at nearly $2 billion (Watson et al., 2003). Clinical practice parameters and clinical guidelines for the treatment of children with sepsis syndrome emphasize the critical importance of early recognition and aggressive treatment for all suspected cases (Dellinger et al., 2013; Carcillo et al., 2002). Improved survival has been associated with adherence to guidelines that emphasize time‐sensitive resuscitation of children with sepsis syndrome (Han et al., 2003). Whether a child presents to an academic medical center or to a community hospital, clinicians must be ready to rapidly deploy a set of time‐sensitive, goal‐directed, stepwise procedures to hinder or reverse the cascade of events in sepsis that lead to organ failure and death. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One fundamental element of timely and appropriate treatment is a sepsis management protocol. Based on clinical guidelines and research-driven data, instructions within the protocol provide a set of consistent steps to help clinicians in the emergency department (ED) recognize sepsis syndrome in pediatric patients and promptly initiate evidence-based interventions, such as fluid resuscitation and antibiotics, likely to hinder the occurrence of, or reverse progression to, septic shock. Protocols support immediate, consistent, and appropriate treatment, regardless of care setting. They also help institutions centralize resources for very sick patients, foster acceptable levels of competence for the skills necessary to provide successful treatment, and produce uniform data amenable to useful comparison and analysis (Dellinger et al., 2013; Rivers &amp;amp; Ahrens, 2008; Cruz et al., 2011; Larsen, Mecham, &amp;amp; Greenberg, 2011). Despite the clear value of such protocols, however, many hospitals lack them, undermining the ability of ED staff to quickly identify and effectively treat children with sepsis syndrome.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3500" OrdBy="100" ID="569" Name="Evidence for Rationale" Type="citation">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Carcillo JA, Fields AI. Clinical practice parameters for hemodynamic support of pediatric and neonatal patients in septic shock. Crit Care Med. 2002 Jun;30(6):1365-78. [162 references] &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=12072696&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Cruz AT, Perry AM, Williams EA, Graf JM, Wuestner ER, Patel B. Implementation of goal-directed therapy for children with suspected sepsis in the emergency department. Pediatrics. 2011 Mar;127(3):e758-66. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=21339277&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Dellinger RP, Levy MM, Rhodes A, Annane D, Gerlach H, Opal SM, Sevransky JE, Sprung CL, Douglas IS, Jaeschke R, Osborn TM, Nunnally ME, Townsend SR, Reinhart K, Kleinpell RM, Angus DC, Deutschman CS, Machado FR, Rubenfeld GD, Webb SA, Beale RJ, Vincent JL, Moreno R, Surviving Sepsis Campaign Guidelines Committee including the Pediatric Subgroup. Surviving sepsis campaign: international guidelines for management of severe sepsis and septic shock: 2012. Crit Care Med. 2013 Feb;41(2):580-637. [636 references] &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=23353941&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Han YY, Carcillo JA, Dragotta MA, Bills DM, Watson RS, Westerman ME, Orr RA. Early reversal of pediatric-neonatal septic shock by community physicians is associated with improved outcome. Pediatrics. 2003 Oct;112(4):793-9. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=14523168&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Larsen GY, Mecham N, Greenberg R. An emergency department septic shock protocol and care guideline for children initiated at triage. Pediatrics. 2011 Jun;127(6):e1585-92. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=21576304&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Odetola FO, Gebremariam A, Freed GL. Patient and hospital correlates of clinical outcomes and resource utilization in severe pediatric sepsis. Pediatrics. 2007 Mar;119(3):487-94. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=17332201&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Quality Measurement, Evaluation, Testing, Review, and Implementation Consortium (Q-METRIC). Basic measure information: protocol for identifying and treating children with sepsis syndrome in the emergency&#xD;&#xA;department. Ann Arbor (MI): Quality Measurement, Evaluation, Testing, Review, and Implementation Consortium; 2014 Aug. 42 p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Rivers EP, Ahrens T. Improving outcomes for severe sepsis and septic shock: tools for early identification of at-risk patients and treatment protocol implementation. Crit Care Clin. 2008 Jul;24(3 Suppl):S1-47. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=18634996&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Watson RS, Carcillo JA, Linde-Zwirble WT, Clermont G, Lidicker J, Angus DC. The epidemiology of severe sepsis in children in the United States. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2003 Mar 1;167(5):695-701. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=12433670&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3022" OrdBy="110" ID="570" Name="Primary Health Components" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sepsis syndrome; written protocol; emergency department (ED); identification; treatment; children&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="23" OrdBy="120" ID="571" Name="Denominator Description" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The eligible population for the denominator is all hospitals with an emergency department (ED).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="24" OrdBy="130" ID="572" Name="Numerator Description" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The numerator represents the number of hospitals with a specific written protocol to identify and treat children with sepsis syndrome in the emergency department (ED) (see the related &quot;Numerator Inclusions/Exclusions&quot; field).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="573" OrdBy="140" Name="Evidence Supporting the Measure">
    <Field FieldID="3027" OrdBy="150" ID="574" Name="Type of Evidence Supporting the Criterion of Quality for the Measure" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="A clinical practice guideline or other peer-reviewed synthesis of the clinical research evidence" />
      <FieldValue Value="A formal consensus procedure, involving experts in relevant clinical, methodological,  public health and organizational sciences" />
      <FieldValue Value="A systematic review of the clinical research literature (e.g., Cochrane Review)" />
      <FieldValue Value="One or more research studies published in a National Library of Medicine (NLM) indexed, peer-reviewed journal" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3501" OrdBy="160" ID="575" Name="Additional Information Supporting Need for the Measure" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sepsis Prevalence and Incidence&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xA;While sepsis-associated mortality in children has declined in recent years, from 97% in infants in 1966 to 9% in the early 1990s, it remains a major cause of morbidity and mortality among children (Watson et al., 2003). Incidence of pediatric sepsis was estimated in 1995 to be 0.56/1000 children, with the highest prevalence in infancy at 5.6/1000 children; boys had a higher incidence compared with girls (0.6 vs. 0.52 per 1000 children) (Watson et al., 2003). Sepsis prevalence tends to have two peaks during childhood, corresponding to significant periods of time in the maturity of the immune system: first, during the neonatal stage, with an incidence of 4.3 per 1000 and second, at 2 years of age (Watson et al., 2003). Odetola et al. (2007) reported another age‐specific peak in hospitalization rates: in 2003, children 15 to 19 years of age made up 18% of the pediatric population hospitalized nationally for sepsis.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mortality among hospitalized children with severe sepsis has been reported to be between 4% and 10% (Watson et al., 2003; Odetola, Gebremariam, &amp;amp; Freed, 2007). Mortality is strongly associated with multiple organ dysfunction syndrome, occurring in 7% of children with one failing organ, increasing to 53% in those with at least four failing organs (Watson et al., 2003). Comorbid illness is also associated with mortality from sepsis, with mortality rates of 8% in children with comorbid illness versus 2% among previously healthy children (Odetola, Gebremariam, &amp;amp; Freed, 2007). There are also reports of age‐specific differences in mortality from pediatric sepsis. Higher mortality rates among children over the age of 2 years may be attributable to the presence of chronic and severe underlying disease and to improved survival of immune‐compromised and immune‐suppressed children (Oliveira et al., 2008). Also, older pediatric patients have been sick longer than younger patients and may also have experienced more hospital admissions and treatments, such as transplantation or chemotherapy, making them more vulnerable to sepsis syndrome (Oliveira et al., 2008). &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sepsis Cost&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xA;Estimated annual total cost of pediatric sepsis in the United States is $1.97 billion (Watson et al., 2003). The average (mean) charge per hospitalization for sepsis is $47,126 (Odetola, Gebremariam, &amp;amp; Freed, 2007). Children who died from sepsis had total hospital charges that were 2.5-fold higher compared with those who survived. Higher charges were also associated with higher severity of illness. Longer length of stay for children hospitalized with sepsis was associated with multiple comorbidities, multiple organ dysfunction, and higher illness severity (Odetola, Gebremariam, &amp;amp; Freed, 2007).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Performance Gap&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xA;Despite the availability of evidence‐based guidelines for the care of children with sepsis, only a minority of children receive the standard of care. Process barriers are a common problem leading to delays in the recognition and treatment of pediatric shock (Cruz et al., 2011). They include varying levels of experience among emergency department (ED) staff performing initial evaluations, lack of adequate nursing staff for resource‐intensive patients, difficulty in obtaining frequent vital signs, lack of standardization of empiric antibiotics and diagnostic tests, lack of prioritization of medications, and barriers to patient flow through the hospital (Cruz et al., 2011). Similarly, Oliveria et al. (2008) suggested reasons for delay may include inaccuracy in assessing the severity of a child's state of shock, shortage of health care providers, fatigue among medical teams, and difficulty in establishing adequate intravascular access. Rivers and Ahrens (2008) describe several potential impediments to implementing a sepsis protocol, including professional barriers, such as lack (or variation) of expertise and resistance to change; institutional barriers, such as departmental competition and limited staff; and physical barriers, such as lack of equipment or space. They opined that identification of one or more knowledgeable leaders with the resources and authority needed to address such barriers is essential to successfully advocate for a sepsis protocol initiative and to promote an atmosphere of teamwork and quality care.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As severe sepsis and septic shock are time‐sensitive conditions that demand immediate care, the timing and location of treatment are important considerations. Treatment cannot start upon arrival at the intensive care unit (ICU); it must begin when patients present to the ED (Larsen, Mecham, &amp;amp; Greenberg, 2011). Early recognition and treatment of severe sepsis and septic shock right from presentation in the ED benefits all patients because it leads to more meticulous patient assessment (Larsen, Mecham, &amp;amp; Greenberg, 2011). Implementation of sepsis protocols before transfer to the ICU should greatly improve outcomes for patients with severe sepsis (Rivers &amp;amp; Ahrens, 2008).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Given the nature of ED care, patients may wait several hours before being evaluated by a physician. A sepsis protocol in the ED offers a process by which to identify patients at risk for septic shock who present at triage or whose course worsens while at they are in the ED. The goal of the protocol is earlier physician evaluation; it also helps provide nursing staff with guidelines to initiate timely care (Larsen, Mecham, &amp;amp; Greenberg, 2011).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Another possible performance barrier relates to hospital type and location. Many children live far from medical facilities that offer specialized pediatric care. For those presenting with septic shock to remote community hospitals, treatment efforts made by the physicians are crucial to their survival and should be prioritized. Delay in care while waiting to transfer patients to a more advanced pediatric medical facility is unwise (Han et al., 2003). Han et al. (2003), in a 9 year retrospective study, reported that 29% of infants and children who presented with septic shock at community hospitals and required transport to a larger medical center did not survive. In a separate report, Odetola et al. (2007) reported that pediatric patients with sepsis who were transferred incurred higher charges than those whose care did not entail transfer. The presence of an ED protocol at community hospitals that supports immediate treatment could be life-saving.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As clinical guidelines for the treatment of sepsis were developed at pediatric academic centers without accounting for use at community hospitals, barriers to their use may exist (Han et al., 2003). For example, some community physicians may lack specialized technical skills involved in managing severe sepsis or septic shock. Educational barriers regarding the guidelines themselves may curtail implementation, if physicians are unaware of, or lack support to execute, stepwise, goal‐directed interventions in a timely manner. However, most of the procedures detailed in current guidelines are easily within the scope of a community‐based practice (Han et al., 2003). Continued efforts to increase knowledge and comfort with sepsis guidelines among community physicians will likely improve outcomes. Odetola and colleagues (2007) also noted an urgent need for concerted clinical and educational efforts within the clinical care setting designed to limit the progression of sepsis severity, as multiple organ dysfunction portends poor outcomes including death.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;See the original measure documentation for additional evidence supporting the measure.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3502" OrdBy="170" ID="576" Name="Evidence for Additional Information Supporting Need for the Measure" Type="citation">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Cruz AT, Perry AM, Williams EA, Graf JM, Wuestner ER, Patel B. Implementation of goal-directed therapy for children with suspected sepsis in the emergency department. Pediatrics. 2011 Mar;127(3):e758-66. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=21339277&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Han YY, Carcillo JA, Dragotta MA, Bills DM, Watson RS, Westerman ME, Orr RA. Early reversal of pediatric-neonatal septic shock by community physicians is associated with improved outcome. Pediatrics. 2003 Oct;112(4):793-9. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=14523168&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Larsen GY, Mecham N, Greenberg R. An emergency department septic shock protocol and care guideline for children initiated at triage. Pediatrics. 2011 Jun;127(6):e1585-92. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=21576304&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Odetola FO, Gebremariam A, Freed GL. Patient and hospital correlates of clinical outcomes and resource utilization in severe pediatric sepsis. Pediatrics. 2007 Mar;119(3):487-94. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=17332201&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Oliveira CF, Nogueira de Sá FR, Oliveira DS, Gottschald AF, Moura JD, Shibata AR, Troster EJ, Vaz FA, Carcillo JA. Time- and fluid-sensitive resuscitation for hemodynamic support of children in septic shock: barriers to the implementation of the American College of Critical Care Medicine/Pediatric Advanced Life Support Guidelines in a pediatric intensive care unit in a developing world. Pediatr Emerg Care. 2008 Dec;24(12):810-5. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=19050666&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Quality Measurement, Evaluation, Testing, Review, and Implementation Consortium (Q-METRIC). Basic measure information: protocol for identifying and treating children with sepsis syndrome in the emergency&#xD;&#xA;department. Ann Arbor (MI): Quality Measurement, Evaluation, Testing, Review, and Implementation Consortium; 2014 Aug. 42 p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Rivers EP, Ahrens T. Improving outcomes for severe sepsis and septic shock: tools for early identification of at-risk patients and treatment protocol implementation. Crit Care Clin. 2008 Jul;24(3 Suppl):S1-47. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=18634996&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Watson RS, Carcillo JA, Linde-Zwirble WT, Clermont G, Lidicker J, Angus DC. The epidemiology of severe sepsis in children in the United States. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2003 Mar 1;167(5):695-701. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=12433670&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3072" OrdBy="180" ID="577" Name="Extent of Measure Testing" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reliability&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;Data and Methods&lt;/em&gt;. Testing data consisted of results from a telephone survey of nurse managers and physician directors at 50 randomly selected hospitals with emergency departments (EDs) in the states of Michigan and Ohio. Respondents were asked if their ED had a protocol for identifying and treating children with sepsis syndrome.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Validity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xA;The validity of this measure was determined from two perspectives: face validity and validity of the facility survey data.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Face Validity&lt;/em&gt;. The validity of this measure was determined from face validity, the degree to which the measure construct characterizes the concept being assessed. The face validity of this measure was established by a national panel of experts and a parent representative for families of children with sepsis syndrome convened by the Quality Measurement, Evaluation, Testing, Review, and Implementation Consortium (Q-METRIC). The Q-METRIC panel included nationally recognized experts in the identification and treatment of pediatric sepsis syndrome, representing neonatology, hematology/oncology, infectious diseases, emergency medicine, nursing, pediatric surgery, and pediatric intensive care. In addition, measure validity was considered by experts in state Medicaid program operations, health plan quality measurement, health informatics, and health care quality measurement. In total, the Q-METRIC sepsis panel included 15 experts, providing a comprehensive perspective on sepsis syndrome care and the measurement of quality metrics for states and health plans. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Q-METRIC expert panel concluded that this measure has a high degree of face validity through a detailed review of concepts and metrics considered to be essential to effective sepsis syndrome identification and treatment. Concepts and draft measures were rated by this group for their relative importance. This measure was highly rated, receiving an average score of 6.9 (with 9 as the highest possible score).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Validity of Abstracted Data&lt;/em&gt;. This measure was tested using facility survey data. Fifty hospitals were randomly selected in the states of Michigan and Ohio (Table 4 of the original measure documentation). After several calls (range of 1 to 6, based on response), 27 hospital ED nurse managers or physician directors responded. Eleven of the 27 (41%) reported having a written protocol for the identification and treatment of children who present to the ED with sepsis syndrome (Table 5 ​of the original measure documentation). Sixteen facilities (59%) indicated that they did not have a protocol.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Validity of the data obtained through the telephone survey was to be assessed through verification of the existence of a protocol. Sites indicating that they had a sepsis protocol were asked to submit this protocol to the study team. The team was interested in verifying the existence of a protocol, not assessing the content of the protocols. Of those respondents who indicated they had a protocol (n=11), only two protocols were received (18%) despite multiple messages to the respondents. Some protocols could not be sent because they were incorporated into the electronic health records in the hospitals.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3007" OrdBy="190" ID="578" Name="Evidence for Extent of Measure Testing" Type="citation">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Quality Measurement, Evaluation, Testing, Review, and Implementation Consortium (Q-METRIC). Basic measure information: protocol for identifying and treating children with sepsis syndrome in the emergency&#xD;&#xA;department. Ann Arbor (MI): Quality Measurement, Evaluation, Testing, Review, and Implementation Consortium; 2014 Aug. 42 p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="580" OrdBy="210" Name="State of Use of the Measure">
    <Field FieldID="3029" OrdBy="220" ID="581" Name="State of Use" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Current routine use" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3030" OrdBy="230" ID="582" Name="Current Use" Type="picklist-choice-3">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="583" OrdBy="240" Name="Application of the Measure in its Current Use">
    <Field FieldID="3031" OrdBy="250" ID="584" Name="Measurement Setting" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="Emergency Department" />
      <FieldValue Value="Hospital Outpatient" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3032" OrdBy="260" ID="585" Name="Professionals Involved in Delivery of Health Services" Type="picklist-choice-3">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3033" OrdBy="270" ID="586" Name="Least Aggregated Level of Services Delivery Addressed" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Single Health Care Delivery or Public Health Organizations" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3505" OrdBy="280" ID="587" Name="Statement of Acceptable Minimum Sample Size" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Does not apply to this measure" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="41" OrdBy="290" ID="588" Name="Target Population Age" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Does not apply to this measure&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="42" OrdBy="300" ID="589" Name="Target Population Gender" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Does not apply to this measure" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="660" OrdBy="310" Name="National Strategy for Quality Improvement in Health Care">
    <Field FieldID="3522" OrdBy="320" ID="661" Name="National Quality Strategy Aim" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Better Care&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3525" OrdBy="330" ID="662" Name="National Quality Strategy Priority" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="590" OrdBy="340" Name="Institute of Medicine (IOM) National Health Care Quality Report Categories">
    <Field FieldID="3163" OrdBy="350" ID="591" Name="IOM Care Need" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="Not within an IOM Care Need" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3164" OrdBy="360" ID="592" Name="IOM Domain" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="Not within an IOM Domain" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="593" OrdBy="370" Name="Data Collection for the Measure">
    <Field FieldID="3506" OrdBy="380" ID="594" Name="Case Finding Period" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3054" OrdBy="390" ID="595" Name="Denominator Sampling Frame" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Health care or public health organization" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3057" OrdBy="400" ID="598" Name="Denominator (Index) Event or Characteristic" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="Health Care/Public Health Organization Characteristic" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3058" OrdBy="410" ID="599" Name="Denominator Time Window" Type="picklist-choice-3">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="55" OrdBy="420" ID="596" Name="Denominator Inclusions/Exclusions" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xA;The eligible population for the denominator is all hospitals with an emergency department (ED).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xA;None&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3507" OrdBy="430" ID="597" Name="Exclusions/Exceptions" Type="picklist-choice-4">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="59" OrdBy="440" ID="600" Name="Numerator Inclusions/Exclusions" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;The numerator represents the number of hospitals with a specific written protocol to identify and treat children with sepsis syndrome in the emergency department (ED). &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul class=&quot;Note&quot; style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Written Protocol&lt;/em&gt;: A paper or electronic protocol with any mention of &quot;sepsis&quot; AND any mention of &quot;children&quot; or individuals younger than 19 years of age &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sepsis Syndrome&lt;/em&gt;: Sepsis, severe sepsis or septic shock (refer to Table 1 of the original measure documentation) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;International Classification of Diseases, Ninth Revision (ICD-9) codes to identify sepsis syndrome diagnoses are documented in Table 2 of the original measure documentation. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;None&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3061" OrdBy="450" ID="601" Name="Numerator Search Strategy" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Fixed time period or point in time" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3062" OrdBy="460" ID="602" Name="Data Source" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Health professional survey" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3065" OrdBy="470" ID="603" Name="Type of Health State" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Does not apply to this measure" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3066" OrdBy="480" ID="604" Name="Instruments Used and/or Associated with the Measure" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="605" OrdBy="490" Name="Computation of the Measure">
    <Field FieldID="3508" OrdBy="500" ID="606" Name="Measure Specifies Disaggregation" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Does not apply to this measure" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3067" OrdBy="520" ID="608" Name="Scoring" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Rate/Proportion" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3068" OrdBy="530" ID="609" Name="Interpretation of Score" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Desired value is a higher score" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3090" OrdBy="540" ID="610" Name="Allowance for Patient or Population Factors" Type="picklist-choice-3">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3070" OrdBy="560" ID="612" Name="Standard of Comparison" Type="picklist-choice-3">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="615" OrdBy="590" Name="Identifying Information">
    <Field FieldID="73" OrdBy="600" ID="616" Name="Original Title" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Protocol for identifying and treating children with sepsis syndrome in the emergency department.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="74" OrdBy="610" ID="617" Name="Measure Collection Name" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="Sepsis Measures" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="16" OrdBy="650" ID="621" Name="Submitter" Type="orglist">
      <FieldValue Value="Quality Measurement, Evaluation, Testing, Review, and Implementation Consortium (Q-METRIC) - Academic Affiliated Research Institute" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="17" OrdBy="660" ID="622" Name="Developer" Type="orglist-p">
      <FieldValue Value="Quality Measurement, Evaluation, Testing, Review, and Implementation Consortium (Q-METRIC) - Academic Affiliated Research Institute" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="79" OrdBy="670" ID="623" Name="Funding Source(s)" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This work was funded by the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ) and the Centers for Medicare &amp;amp; Medicaid Services (CMS) under the Children's Health Insurance Program Reauthorization Act (CHIPRA) Pediatric Quality Measures Program Centers of Excellence grant number U18 HS020516.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="80" OrdBy="680" ID="624" Name="Composition of the Group that Developed the Measure" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sepsis Expert Panels&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Representative Panel&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Marjorie Arca, MD, Associate Professor and Clinical Director, Pediatric Surgical Critical Care, Medical College of Wisconsin, Milwaukee, WI &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Joseph Carcillo, MD, Associate Professor, Department of Critical Care Medicine and Department of Pediatrics, University of Pittsburgh School of Medicine, Pittsburgh, PA &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Gretchen Cavanagh, RN, Registered Nurse, University of Michigan Health System, Ann Arbor, MI &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Shannon Hamet, MEd, Parent Representative, Flat Rock, MI &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;James O'Callaghan, MD, Clinical Assistant Professor, Department of Pediatrics, University of Washington School of Medicine, Seattle, WA &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Richard Polin, MD, Director, Division of Neonatology, Professor of Pediatrics, Attending Physician, Columbia University Medical Center, New York, NY &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Richard Saladino, MD, Chief of Pediatric Emergency Medicine, University of Pittsburgh School of Medicine, Pittsburgh, PA &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Samir Shah, MD, MSCE, Director and Research Director, Hospital Medicine, Associate Professor, Department of Pediatrics, Cincinnati Children's Hospital Medical Center, Cincinnati, OH &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Lillian Sung, MD, PhD, Associate Professor, University of Toronto, Scientist and Pediatric Oncologist, The Hospital for Sick Children, Toronto, Ontario &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Feasibility Panel&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Christine Gall, DrPHc, MS, RN, Director, Quality and Client Relations, Virtual PICU Systems, LLC, Milwaukee, WI &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Lakshmi Halasyamani, MD, Chief Medical Officer, Saint Joseph Mercy Health System, Ypsilanti, MI &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Kevin Johnson, MD, MS, Professor and Vice Chair of Biomedical Informatics, Vanderbilt University, Nashville, TN &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Sue Moran, BSN, MPH, Director of the Bureau of Medicaid Program Operations and Quality Assurance, Michigan Department of Community Health, Lansing, MI &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Joseph Singer, MD, Vice President Clinical Affairs, HealthCore, Inc., Wilmington, DE &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Marjorie Wilkins, CPC, CPC-H, CPAT, AHIMA, Approved International Classification of Diseases, Tenth Revision (ICD-10) Trainer, Altarum Institute, Alexandria, VA &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Quality Measurement, Evaluation, Testing, Review, and Implementation Consortium (Q-METRIC) Investigators&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Folafoluwa Olutobi Odetola, MD, MPH, Assistant Professor, Department of Pediatrics and Communicable Diseases, School of Medicine, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, MI &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Gary L. Freed, MD, MPH, Professor of Pediatrics, School of Medicine and Professor of Health Management and Policy, School of Public Health, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, MI (principal investigator) &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Kevin J. Dombkowski, DrPH, MS, Research Associate Professor of Pediatrics, School of Medicine, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, MI &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="81" OrdBy="690" ID="625" Name="Financial Disclosures/Other Potential Conflicts of Interest" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="19" OrdBy="730" ID="629" Name="Adaptation" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This measure was not adapted from another source.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3086" OrdBy="740" ID="630" Name="Date of Most Current Version in NQMC" Type="date">
      <FieldValue Value="2014 Aug" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3511" OrdBy="750" ID="631" Name="Measure Maintenance" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3512" OrdBy="760" ID="632" Name="Date of Next Anticipated Revision" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="20" OrdBy="770" ID="633" Name="Measure Status" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the current release of the measure.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The measure developer reaffirmed the currency of this measure in January 2016. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="14" OrdBy="780" ID="634" Name="Measure Availability" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Source available from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://chear.org/sites/default/files/stories/pdfs/sepsis1_edprotocol.pdf&quot; title=&quot;Q-METRIC Web site&quot;&gt;Quality Measurement, Evaluation, Testing, Review, and Implementation Consortium (Q-METRIC) Web site&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chear.org/qmetric&quot; title=&quot;Q-METRIC Web site&quot;&gt;Support documents&lt;/a&gt; are also available.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For more information, contact Q-METRIC at 300 North Ingalls Street, Room 6C08, SPC 5456, Ann Arbor, MI 48109-5456; Phone: 734-232-0657; Fax: 734-764-2599.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="87" OrdBy="800" ID="636" Name="NQMC Status" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This NQMC summary was completed by ECRI Institute on April 16, 2015. The information was verified by the measure developer on May 19, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The information was reaffirmed by the measure developer on January 7, 2016. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="88" OrdBy="810" ID="637" Name="Copyright Statement" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This NQMC summary is based on the original measure, which is subject to the measure developer's copyright restrictions. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Inform Quality Measurement, Evaluation, Testing, Review, and Implementation Consortium (Q-METRIC) if users implement the measures in their health care settings.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="641" OrdBy="850" Name="Production">
    <Field FieldID="1" OrdBy="1366" ID="562" Name="Source(s)" Type="citation">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Quality Measurement, Evaluation, Testing, Review, and Implementation Consortium (Q-METRIC). Basic measure information: protocol for identifying and treating children with sepsis syndrome in the emergency&#xD;&#xA;department. Ann Arbor (MI): Quality Measurement, Evaluation, Testing, Review, and Implementation Consortium; 2014 Aug. 42 p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="99999" OrdBy="99999" Name="Disclaimer">
    <Field FieldID="99999" OrdBy="99999" ID="99999" Name="NQMC Disclaimer" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;p&gt;The National Quality Measures Clearinghouse™ (NQMC) does not develop, produce, approve, or endorse the measures represented on this site.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;All measures summarized by NQMC and hosted on our site are produced under the auspices of medical specialty societies, relevant professional associations, public and private organizations, other government agencies, health care organizations or plans, individuals, and similar entities.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Measures represented on the NQMC Web site are submitted by measure developers, and are screened solely to determine that they meet the &lt;a href=&quot;/help-and-about/summaries/inclusion-criteria&quot;&gt;NQMC Inclusion Criteria&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;NQMC, AHRQ, and its contractor ECRI Institute make no warranties concerning the content or its reliability and/or validity of the quality measures and related materials represented on this site. Moreover, the views and opinions of developers or authors of measures represented on this site do not necessarily state or reflect those of NQMC, AHRQ, or its contractor, ECRI Institute, and inclusion or hosting of measures in NQMC may not be used for advertising or commercial endorsement purposes.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Readers with questions regarding measure content are directed to contact the measure developer.&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
</Version>