<Version>
  <xmlSource>This XML content was developed by AHRQ's contractor ECRI Institute for the National Quality Measures Clearinghouse (NQMC).</xmlSource>
  <Section SecID="560" OrdBy="10" Name="General">
    <Field FieldID="11" OrdBy="20" ID="561" Name="Title" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_title&quot;&gt;Pneumonia: hospital 30-day, all-cause, unplanned risk-standardized readmission rate (RSRR) following pneumonia hospitalization.&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="1" OrdBy="30" ID="562" Name="Source(s)" Type="citation">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Yale New Haven Health Services Corporation (YNHHSC), Center for Outcomes Research and Evaluation (CORE). 2017 condition-specific measures updates and specifications report: hospital-level 30-day risk-standardized readmission measures. Baltimore (MD): Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS); 2017 Mar. 112 p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="563" OrdBy="40" Name="Measure Domain">
    <Field FieldID="3025" OrdBy="50" ID="564" Name="Primary Measure Domain" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Related Health Care Delivery Measures: Use of Services" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3026" OrdBy="60" ID="565" Name="Secondary Measure Domain" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Does not apply to this measure" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="566" OrdBy="70" Name="Brief Abstract">
    <Field FieldID="34" OrdBy="80" ID="567" Name="Description" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This measure estimates a hospital-level 30-day risk-standardized readmission rate (RSRR) for patients discharged from the hospital with either a principal discharge diagnosis of pneumonia or a principle discharge diagnosis of sepsis with a secondary discharge diagnosis of pneumonia. The outcome is defined as unplanned readmission for any cause within 30 days of the discharge date for the index admission. A specified set of planned readmissions do not count as readmissions. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Centers for Medicare &amp;amp; Medicaid Services (CMS) annually reports the measure for individuals who are 65 years and older and are Medicare Fee-for-Service (FFS) beneficiaries hospitalized in non-federal short-term acute care hospitals (including Indian Health Services hospitals) and critical access hospitals.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="21" OrdBy="90" ID="568" Name="Rationale" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Readmission of patients who were recently discharged after hospitalization with pneumonia represents an important, expensive, and often preventable adverse outcome. The risk of readmission can be modified by the quality and type of care provided to these patients. Improving readmission rates is the joint responsibility of hospitals and clinicians. Measuring readmission will create incentives to invest in interventions to improve hospital care, better assess the readiness of patients for discharge, and facilitate transitions to outpatient status.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3500" OrdBy="100" ID="569" Name="Evidence for Rationale" Type="citation">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Yale University/Yale-New Haven Hospital-Center for Outcomes Research &amp; Evaluation (Yale-CORE). Hospital 30-day pneumonia readmission measure: methodology. Baltimore (MD): Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS); 2008 Jun 9. 49 p.  [22 references]&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3022" OrdBy="110" ID="570" Name="Primary Health Components" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pneumonia; 30-day readmission rate&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="23" OrdBy="120" ID="571" Name="Denominator Description" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The measure cohort consists of admissions for Medicare Fee-for-Service (FFS) beneficiaries aged 65 years and older and discharged from non-federal acute care hospitals and critical access hospitals, having a principal discharge diagnosis of pneumonia (including aspiration pneumonia) or a principal discharge diagnosis of sepsis (not including severe sepsis) that have a secondary discharge diagnosis of pneumonia (including aspiration pneumonia) coded as present on admission (POA) and no secondary diagnosis of severe sepsis coded as POA.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The risk-standardized readmission rate (RSRR) is calculated as the ratio of the number of &quot;predicted&quot; readmissions to the number of &quot;expected&quot; readmissions at a given hospital, multiplied by the national observed readmission rate. For each hospital, the denominator is the number of readmissions expected based on the nation's performance with that hospital's case-mix.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;See the related &quot;Denominator Inclusions/Exclusions&quot; field.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: This outcome measure does not have a traditional numerator and denominator like a core process measure; thus, this field is used to define the measure cohort.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;See the &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.qualitynet.org/dcs/ContentServer?c=Page&amp;amp;pagename=QnetPublic%2FPage%2FQnetTier4&amp;amp;cid=1219069855841&quot; title=&quot;QualityNet Web site&quot;&gt;2017 Condition-specific Measures Updates and Specifications Report: Hospital-level 30-day Risk-standardized Readmission Measures&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; for more details.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="24" OrdBy="130" ID="572" Name="Numerator Description" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The measure assesses unplanned readmissions to an acute care hospital, from any cause, within 30 days from the date of a discharge from an index pneumonia admission.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The risk-standardized readmission rate (RSRR) is calculated as the ratio of the number of &quot;predicted&quot; readmissions to the number of &quot;expected&quot; readmissions at a given hospital, multiplied by the national observed readmission rate. For each hospital, the numerator of the ratio is the number of readmissions within 30 days predicted based on the hospital's performance with its observed case-mix.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;See the related &quot;Numerator Inclusions/Exclusions&quot; field.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: This outcome measure does not have a traditional numerator and denominator like a core process measure; thus, this field is used to define the measure cohort.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;See the &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.qualitynet.org/dcs/ContentServer?c=Page&amp;amp;pagename=QnetPublic%2FPage%2FQnetTier4&amp;amp;cid=1219069855841&quot; title=&quot;QualityNet Web site&quot;&gt;2017 Condition-specific Measures Updates and Specifications Report: Hospital-level 30-day Risk-standardized Readmission Measures&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; for more details.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="573" OrdBy="140" Name="Evidence Supporting the Measure">
    <Field FieldID="3027" OrdBy="150" ID="574" Name="Type of Evidence Supporting the Criterion of Quality for the Measure" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="One or more research studies published in a National Library of Medicine (NLM) indexed, peer-reviewed journal" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3501" OrdBy="160" ID="575" Name="Additional Information Supporting Need for the Measure" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2007, the Medicare Payment Advisory Commission (MedPAC) (2007) called for hospital-specific public reporting of readmission rates, and identified pneumonia as a priority condition. In 2010, pneumonia is the principal discharge diagnosis for more than 1 million hospitalizations each year in the United States (Lindenauer et al., 2012; Centers for Disease Control and Prevention [CDC], 2017). From 2003 to 2004, approximately 20% of pneumonia patients were rehospitalized within thirty days, representing the second-highest proportion of all rehospitalizations at 6.3% (Jencks et al., 2009). Among patients 65 years [of age] or older in the United States, pneumonia is the second leading cause of hospitalization (Fry et al., 2005), and based on 2005 Medicare data, MedPAC estimated that about 8.9% of Medicare pneumonia admissions were followed by a readmission within 15 days, accounting for more than 74,000 admissions at a cost of $533 million. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pneumonia readmission is a costly event and represents an undesirable outcome of care from the patient's perspective, and highly disparate pneumonia readmission rates among hospitals suggest there is room for improvement (MedPAC, 2007; Lindenauer et al., 2010). Although many current hospital interventions are known to decrease the risk of readmission within 30 days of hospital discharge (Leppin et al., 2014), current process-based performance measures, cannot capture all the ways that care within the hospital might influence outcomes. Measurement of patient outcomes allows for a comprehensive view of quality of care that reflects complex aspects of care such as communication between providers and coordinated transitions to the outpatient environment. These aspects are critical to patient outcomes, and are more broad than what can be captured by individual process-of-care measures.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The pneumonia hospital-specific risk-standardized readmission rate (RSRR) measure is thus intended to inform quality-of-care improvement efforts, as individual process-based performance measures cannot encompass all the complex and critical aspects of care within a hospital that contribute to patient outcomes. As a result, many stakeholders, including patient organizations, are interested in outcomes measures that allow patients and providers to assess relative outcomes performance for hospitals (Bratzler, Nsa, &amp;amp; Houck, 2007).&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Numerous studies have demonstrated that appropriate (guideline recommended care), high-quality and timely treatment for pneumonia patients can reduce the risk of readmission within 30 days of hospital discharge (Leppin et al., 2014; Hansen et al., 2011). Recent evidence of declining readmission rates provides further support for the concept that care processes during and following hospitalization can affect a patient's risk of readmission (Lee et al., 2014). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3502" OrdBy="170" ID="576" Name="Evidence for Additional Information Supporting Need for the Measure" Type="citation">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Bratzler DW, Nsa W, Houck PM. Performance measures for pneumonia: are they valuable, and are process measures adequate?. Curr Opin Infect Dis. 2007 Apr;20(2):182-9. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=17496578 &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC). FastStats: pneumonia. [internet]. Atlanta (GA): Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC); 2017 Jan 20&amp;nbsp;[accessed 2017 Dec 01]. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Fry AM, Shay DK, Holman RC, Curns AT, Anderson LJ. Trends in hospitalizations for pneumonia among persons aged 65 years or older in  the United States, 1988-2002. JAMA. 2005 Dec 7;294(21):2712-9. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=16333006&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Hansen LO, Young RS, Hinami K, Leung A, Williams MV. Interventions to reduce 30-day rehospitalization: a systematic review. Ann Intern Med. 2011 Oct 18;155(8):520-8. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=22007045&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Jencks SF, Williams MV, Coleman EA. Rehospitalizations among patients in the Medicare fee-for-service program. N Engl J Med. 2009 Apr 2;360(14):1418-28. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=19339721&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Lee JS, Nsa W, Hausmann LR, Trivedi AN, Bratzler DW, Auden D, Mor MK, Baus K, Larbi FM, Fine MJ. Quality of care for elderly patients hospitalized for pneumonia in the United States, 2006 to 2010. JAMA Intern Med. 2014 Nov;174(11):1806-14. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=25201438 &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Leppin AL, Gionfriddo MR, Kessler M, Brito JP, Mair FS, Gallacher K, Wang Z, Erwin PJ, Sylvester T, Boehmer K, Ting HH, Murad MH, Shippee ND, Montori VM. Preventing 30-day hospital readmissions: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized trials. JAMA Intern Med. 2014 Jul;174(7):1095-107. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=24820131 &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Lindenauer PK, Bernheim SM, Grady JN, Lin Z, Wang Y, Wang Y, Merrill AR, Han LF, Rapp MT, Drye EE, Normand SL, Krumholz HM. The performance of US hospitals as reflected in risk-standardized 30-day mortality and readmission rates for Medicare beneficiaries with pneumonia. J Hosp Med. 2010 Jul-Aug;5(6):E12-8. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=20665626 &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Lindenauer PK, Lagu T, Shieh MS, Pekow PS, Rothberg MB. Association of diagnostic coding with trends in hospitalizations and mortality of patients with pneumonia, 2003-2009. JAMA. 2012 Apr 4;307(13):1405-13. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=22474204 &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Medicare Payment Advisory Commission (MedPAC). Report to the Congress: promoting greater efficiency in Medicare. Washington (DC): Medicare Payment Advisory Commission (MedPAC); 2007 Jun. 277 p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3072" OrdBy="180" ID="577" Name="Extent of Measure Testing" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Assessment of Updated Models&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The pneumonia readmission measure estimates hospital-specific 30-day all-cause risk-standardized readmission rates (RSRRs) using a hierarchical logistic regression model. Refer to Section 2 in the original measure documentation for a summary of the measure methodology and model risk-adjustment variables. Refer to prior methodology and technical reports for further details.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Centers for Medicare &amp;amp; Medicaid Services (CMS) evaluated and validated the performance of the models using July 2013 to June 2016 data for the 2017 reporting period. They also evaluated the stability of the risk-adjustment model over the three-year measurement period by examining the model variable frequencies, model coefficients, and the performance of the risk-adjustment model in each year.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;CMS assessed logistic regression model performance in terms of discriminant ability for each year of data and for the three-year combined period. They computed two summary statistics to assess model performance: the predictive ability and the area under the receiver operating characteristic (ROC) curve (c-statistic). CMS also computed between-hospital variance for each year of data and for the three-year combined period. If there were no systematic differences between hospitals, the between-hospital variance would be zero.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The results of these analyses are presented in Section 4.5 of the original measure documentation. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pneumonia Readmission 2017 Model Results&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Frequency of Pneumonia Model Variables&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;CMS examined the change in the frequencies of clinical and demographic variables. Frequencies of model variables were stable over the measurement period. The largest changes in the frequencies (those greater than 2% absolute change) include: &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Increases in Asthma (11.2% to 14.5%), Respiratory arrest; cardio-respiratory failure and shock (25.7% to 28.0%), Other psychiatric disorders (24.0% to 26.5%), and Septicemia, sepsis, systemic inflammatory response syndrome/shock (13.9% to 16.2%) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;A decrease in Iron deficiency or other/unspecified anemias and blood disease (60.7% to 58.5%) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pneumonia Model Parameters and Performance&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Table 4.5.2 in the original measure documentation shows hierarchical logistic regression model variable coefficients by individual year and for the combined three-year dataset. Table 4.5.3 in the original measure documentation shows the risk-adjusted odds ratios (ORs) and 95% confidence intervals for the pneumonia readmission model by individual year and for the combined three-year dataset. Overall, the variable effect sizes were relatively constant across years. In addition, model performance was stable over the three-year time period; the c-statistic increased slightly from 0.63 to 0.64.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Refer to the original measure documentation for additional information.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3007" OrdBy="190" ID="578" Name="Evidence for Extent of Measure Testing" Type="citation">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Yale New Haven Health Services Corporation (YNHHSC), Center for Outcomes Research and Evaluation (CORE). 2017 condition-specific measures updates and specifications report: hospital-level 30-day risk-standardized readmission measures. Baltimore (MD): Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS); 2017 Mar. 112 p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="580" OrdBy="210" Name="State of Use of the Measure">
    <Field FieldID="3029" OrdBy="220" ID="581" Name="State of Use" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Current routine use" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3030" OrdBy="230" ID="582" Name="Current Use" Type="picklist-choice-3">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="583" OrdBy="240" Name="Application of the Measure in its Current Use">
    <Field FieldID="3031" OrdBy="250" ID="584" Name="Measurement Setting" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="Hospital Inpatient" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3032" OrdBy="260" ID="585" Name="Professionals Involved in Delivery of Health Services" Type="picklist-choice-3">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3033" OrdBy="270" ID="586" Name="Least Aggregated Level of Services Delivery Addressed" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Single Health Care Delivery or Public Health Organizations" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3505" OrdBy="280" ID="587" Name="Statement of Acceptable Minimum Sample Size" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Does not apply to this measure" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="41" OrdBy="290" ID="588" Name="Target Population Age" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Age greater than or equal to 65 years&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="42" OrdBy="300" ID="589" Name="Target Population Gender" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Either male or female" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="660" OrdBy="310" Name="National Strategy for Quality Improvement in Health Care">
    <Field FieldID="3525" OrdBy="330" ID="662" Name="National Quality Strategy Priority" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="590" OrdBy="340" Name="Institute of Medicine (IOM) National Health Care Quality Report Categories">
    <Field FieldID="3163" OrdBy="350" ID="591" Name="IOM Care Need" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="Not within an IOM Care Need" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3164" OrdBy="360" ID="592" Name="IOM Domain" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="Not within an IOM Domain" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="593" OrdBy="370" Name="Data Collection for the Measure">
    <Field FieldID="3506" OrdBy="380" ID="594" Name="Case Finding Period" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Discharges July 1, 2013 through June 30, 2016&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3054" OrdBy="390" ID="595" Name="Denominator Sampling Frame" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Patients associated with provider" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3057" OrdBy="400" ID="598" Name="Denominator (Index) Event or Characteristic" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="Clinical Condition" />
      <FieldValue Value="Institutionalization" />
      <FieldValue Value="Patient/Individual (Consumer) Characteristic" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3058" OrdBy="410" ID="599" Name="Denominator Time Window" Type="picklist-choice-3">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="55" OrdBy="420" ID="596" Name="Denominator Inclusions/Exclusions" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;An &lt;em&gt;index admission&lt;/em&gt; is the hospitalization to which the readmission outcome is attributed and includes admissions for patients: &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Having a principal discharge diagnosis of:&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Pneumonia* (including aspiration pneumonia); or, &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Sepsis** (not including severe sepsis) with a secondary diagnosis of pneumonia (including aspiration pneumonia) coded as present on admission (POA) and no secondary diagnosis of severe sepsis coded as POA &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Enrolled in Medicare Fee-for-Service (FFS) Part A and Part B for the 12 months prior to the date of admission, and enrolled in Part A during the index admission &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Aged 65 or over &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Discharged alive from a non-federal short-term acute care hospital &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Not transferred to another acute care facility &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;*International Classification of Diseases, Tenth Revision, Clinical Modification (ICD-10-CM) codes used to define the pneumonia cohort for discharges on or after October 1, 2015:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul class=&quot;Note&quot; style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;A48.1 Legionnaires' disease &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;J10.00 Influenza due to other identified influenza virus with unspecified type of pneumonia &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;J10.01 Influenza due to other identified influenza virus with the same other identified influenza virus pneumonia &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;J10.08 Influenza due to other identified influenza virus with other specified pneumonia &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;J11.00 Influenza due to unidentified influenza virus with unspecified type of pneumonia &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;J11.08 Influenza due to unidentified influenza virus with specified pneumonia &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;J12.0 Adenoviral pneumonia &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;J12.1 Respiratory syncytial virus pneumonia &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;J12.2 Parainfluenza virus pneumonia &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;J12.3 Human metapneumovirus pneumonia &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;J12.81 Pneumonia due to SARS-associated coronavirus &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;J12.89 Other viral pneumonia &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;J12.9 Viral pneumonia, unspecified &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;J13 Pneumonia due to Streptococcus pneumoniae &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;J14 Pneumonia due to Hemophilus influenzae &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;J15.0 Pneumonia due to Klebsiella pneumoniae &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;J15.1 Pneumonia due to Pseudomonas &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;J15.20 Pneumonia due to staphylococcus, unspecified &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;J15.211 Pneumonia due to Methicillin susceptible Staphylococcus aureus &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;J15.212 Pneumonia due to Methicillin resistant Staphylococcus aureus &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;J15.29 Pneumonia due to other staphylococcus &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;J15.3 Pneumonia due to streptococcus, group B &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;J15.4 Pneumonia due to other streptococci &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;J15.5 Pneumonia due to Escherichia coli &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;J15.6 Pneumonia due to other aerobic Gram-negative bacteria &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;J15.7 Pneumonia due to Mycoplasma pneumoniae &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;J15.8 Pneumonia due to other specified bacteria &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;J15.9 Unspecified bacterial pneumonia &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;J16.0 Chlamydial pneumonia &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;J16.8 Pneumonia due to other specified infectious organisms &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;J18.0 Bronchopneumonia, unspecified organism &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;J18.1 Lobar pneumonia, unspecified organism &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;J18.8 Other pneumonia, unspecified organism &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;J18.9 Pneumonia, unspecified organism &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;J69.0 Pneumonitis due to inhalation of food and vomit &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;**Principal discharge diagnosis codes included in cohort if combined with a secondary diagnosis of pneumonia coded as POA AND no secondary diagnosis of severe sepsis (R65.20 Severe sepsis without septic shock or R65.21 Severe sepsis with septic shock) coded as POA is present:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul class=&quot;Note&quot; style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;A02.1 Salmonella sepsis &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;A22.7 Anthrax sepsis &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;A26.7 Erysipelothrix sepsis &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;A32.7 Listerial sepsis &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;A40.0 Sepsis due to streptococcus, group A &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;A40.1 Sepsis due to streptococcus, group B &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;A40.3 Sepsis due to Streptococcus pneumoniae &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;A40.8 Other streptococcal sepsis &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;A40.9 Streptococcal sepsis, unspecified &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;A41.01 Sepsis due to Methicillin susceptible Staphylococcus aureus &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;A41.02 Sepsis due to Methicillin resistant Staphylococcus aureus &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;A41.1 Sepsis due to other specified staphylococcus &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;A41.2 Sepsis due to unspecified staphylococcus &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;A41.3 Sepsis due to Hemophilus influenzae &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;A41.4 Sepsis due to anaerobes &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;A41.50 Gram-negative sepsis, unspecified &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;A41.51 Sepsis due to Escherichia coli (E. coli) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;A41.52 Sepsis due to Pseudomonas &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;A41.53 Sepsis due to Serratia &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;A41.59 Other Gram-negative sepsis &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;A41.81 Sepsis due to Enterococcus &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;A41.89 Other specified sepsis &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;A41.9 Sepsis, unspecified organism &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;A42.7 Actinomycotic sepsis &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;A54.86 Gonococcal sepsis &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;B37.7 Candidal sepsis &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: International Classification of Diseases, Ninth Revision (ICD-9) code lists for discharges prior to October 1, 2015 can be found in the &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.qualitynet.org/dcs/ContentServer?c=Page&amp;amp;pagename=QnetPublic%2FPage%2FQnetTier3&amp;amp;cid=1228774371008&quot; title=&quot;QualityNet Web site&quot;&gt;2016 Condition-specific Measures Updates and Specifications Report: Hospital-Level 30-Day Risk-Standardized Readmission Measures&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Without at least 30 days of post-discharge enrollment in Medicare FFS &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Discharged against medical advice &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Pneumonia admissions within 30 days of discharge from a prior pneumonia index admission &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3507" OrdBy="430" ID="597" Name="Exclusions/Exceptions" Type="picklist-choice-4">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="59" OrdBy="440" ID="600" Name="Numerator Inclusions/Exclusions" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;The measure assesses unplanned readmissions, from any cause, within 30 days from the date of discharge from an index pneumonia admission.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If a patient has more than one unplanned admission within 30 days of discharge from the index admission, only the first is considered a readmission. The measures assess a dichotomous yes or no outcome of whether each admitted patient has any unplanned readmission within 30 days. If the first readmission after discharge is planned, any subsequent unplanned readmission is not considered in the outcome for that index admission because the unplanned readmission could be related to care provided during the intervening planned readmission rather than during the index admission.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The risk-standardized readmission rate (RSRR) is calculated as the ratio of the number of &quot;predicted&quot; readmissions to the number of &quot;expected&quot; readmissions at a given hospital, multiplied by the national observed readmission rate. For each hospital, the numerator of the ratio is the number of readmissions within 30 days predicted based on the hospital's performance with its observed case-mix.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: This outcome measure does not have a traditional numerator and denominator like a core process measure; thus, this field is used to define the outcome.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;See the &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.qualitynet.org/dcs/ContentServer?c=Page&amp;amp;pagename=QnetPublic%2FPage%2FQnetTier4&amp;amp;cid=1219069855841&quot; title=&quot;QualityNet Web site&quot;&gt;2017 Condition-specific Measures Updates and Specifications Report: Hospital-level 30-day Risk-standardized Readmission Measures&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; for more details.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Admissions identified as planned by the planned readmissions algorithm are not counted as readmissions. The planned readmission algorithm is a set of criteria for classifying readmissions and planned among the general Medicare population using Medicare administrative claims data. The algorithm identified admissions that are typically planned and may occur within 30 days of discharge from the hospital. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The planned readmission algorithm has three fundamental principles: &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ol style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;A few specific, limited types of care are always considered planned (transplant surgery, maintenance chemotherapy/immunotherapy, rehabilitation); &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Otherwise, a planned readmission is defined as a non-acute readmission for a scheduled procedure; and &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Admissions for acute illness or for complications of care are never planned &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The planned readmission algorithm uses a flow chart and four tables of specific procedure categories and discharge diagnosis categories to classify readmissions as planned. The flow chart and tables are available in the &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.qualitynet.org/dcs/ContentServer?c=Page&amp;amp;pagename=QnetPublic%2FPage%2FQnetTier4&amp;amp;cid=1219069855841&quot; title=&quot;QualityNet Web site&quot;&gt;2017 Condition-specific Measures Updates and Specifications Report: Hospital-level 30-day Risk-standardized Readmission Measures&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3061" OrdBy="450" ID="601" Name="Numerator Search Strategy" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Institutionalization" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3062" OrdBy="460" ID="602" Name="Data Source" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Administrative clinical data" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3065" OrdBy="470" ID="603" Name="Type of Health State" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Proxy for Outcome" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3066" OrdBy="480" ID="604" Name="Instruments Used and/or Associated with the Measure" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Planned Readmission Algorithm Version 4.0 (ICD-10) Flowchart&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="605" OrdBy="490" Name="Computation of the Measure">
    <Field FieldID="3508" OrdBy="500" ID="606" Name="Measure Specifies Disaggregation" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Does not apply to this measure" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3067" OrdBy="520" ID="608" Name="Scoring" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Rate/Proportion" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3068" OrdBy="530" ID="609" Name="Interpretation of Score" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Desired value is a lower score" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3090" OrdBy="540" ID="610" Name="Allowance for Patient or Population Factors" Type="picklist-choice-3">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3069" OrdBy="550" ID="611" Name="Description of Allowance for Patient or Population Factors" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Risk-Adjustment Variables&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In order to account for differences in case mix among hospitals, the measure adjusts for variables (for example, age, comorbid diseases, and indicators of patient frailty) that are clinically relevant and have relationships with the outcome. For each patient, risk-adjustment variables are obtained from inpatient, outpatient, and physician Medicare administrative claims data extending 12 months prior to, and including, the index admission.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The measure adjusts for case mix differences among hospitals based on the clinical status of the patient at the time of the index admission. Accordingly, only comorbidities that convey information about the patient at that time or in the 12 months prior, and not complications that arise during the course of the hospitalization, are included in the risk adjustment.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The measure does not adjust for socioeconomic status (SES) because the association between SES and health outcomes can be due, in part, to differences in the quality of health care that groups of patients with varying SES receive. The intent is for the measures to adjust for patient demographic and clinical characteristics while illuminating important quality differences. As part of the National Quality Forum (NQF) endorsement process for this measure, the Centers for Medicare &amp;amp; Medicaid Services (CMS) completed analyses for the two-year Sociodemographic Trial Period. Although univariate analyses found that the patient-level observed (unadjusted) readmission rates are higher for dual-eligible patients (for patients living in lower Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality [AHRQ] SES Index census block groups) and African-American patients compared with all other patients, analyses in the context of a multivariable model demonstrated that the effect size of these variables was small, and that the c-statistics for the models are similar with and without the addition of these variables.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Refer to Appendix D of the original measure documentation for the list of comorbidity risk-adjustment variables and the list of complications that are excluded from risk adjustment if they occur only during the index admission.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3070" OrdBy="560" ID="612" Name="Standard of Comparison" Type="picklist-choice-3">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="615" OrdBy="590" Name="Identifying Information">
    <Field FieldID="73" OrdBy="600" ID="616" Name="Original Title" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hospital-level 30-day RSRR following pneumonia.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="74" OrdBy="610" ID="617" Name="Measure Collection Name" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="National Hospital Inpatient Quality Measures" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="75" OrdBy="620" ID="618" Name="Measure Set Name" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="Readmission Measures" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="16" OrdBy="650" ID="621" Name="Submitter" Type="orglist">
      <FieldValue Value="Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services - Federal Government Agency [U.S.]" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="17" OrdBy="660" ID="622" Name="Developer" Type="orglist-p">
      <FieldValue Value="Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services - Federal Government Agency [U.S.]" />
      <FieldValue Value="Yale-New Haven Health Services Corporation/Center for Outcomes Research and Evaluation under contract to Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services - Academic Affiliated Research Institute" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="79" OrdBy="670" ID="623" Name="Funding Source(s)" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="80" OrdBy="680" ID="624" Name="Composition of the Group that Developed the Measure" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This measure was developed by a team of experts: &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Harlan M. Krumholz, MD, SM, Yale School of Medicine &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Sharon-Lise T. Normand, PhD, Harvard Medical School, Department of Health Care Policy &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Patricia S. Keenan, PhD, MHS, Centers for Medicare &amp;amp; Medicaid Services (CMS) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Mayur M. Desai, PhD, MPH, Yale School of Public Health &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Zhenqiu Lin, PhD, Yale New Haven Health Services Corporation/Center for Outcomes Research &amp;amp; Evaluation (YNHHSC/CORE) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Elizabeth E. Drye, MD, SM, Yale School of Medicine &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Kanchana R. Bhat, MPH, YNHHSC/CORE &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Geoffrey C. Schreiner, BS, YNHHSC/CORE &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="81" OrdBy="690" ID="625" Name="Financial Disclosures/Other Potential Conflicts of Interest" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;None&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="82" OrdBy="700" ID="626" Name="Endorser" Type="orglist">
      <FieldValue Value="National Quality Forum - None" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3091" OrdBy="705" ID="696" Name="NQF Number" Type="plain-text">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3510" OrdBy="710" ID="627" Name="Date of Endorsement" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;2016 Dec 9&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3083" OrdBy="720" ID="628" Name="Measure Initiative(s)" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Hospital Compare" />
      <FieldValue Value="Hospital Inpatient Quality Reporting Program" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="19" OrdBy="730" ID="629" Name="Adaptation" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This measure was not adapted from another source.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3086" OrdBy="740" ID="630" Name="Date of Most Current Version in NQMC" Type="date">
      <FieldValue Value="2017 Mar" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3511" OrdBy="750" ID="631" Name="Measure Maintenance" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Annual&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3512" OrdBy="760" ID="632" Name="Date of Next Anticipated Revision" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;2018 Apr&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="20" OrdBy="770" ID="633" Name="Measure Status" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the current release of the measure.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This measure updates a previous version: Specifications manual for national hospital inpatient quality measures, version 5.0b. Centers for Medicare &amp;amp; Medicaid Services (CMS), The Joint Commission; Effective 2015 Oct 1. various p. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="14" OrdBy="780" ID="634" Name="Measure Availability" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Source available from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.qualitynet.org/dcs/ContentServer?c=Page&amp;amp;pagename=QnetPublic%2FPage%2FQnetTier4&amp;amp;cid=1219069855841&quot; title=&quot;QualityNet Web site&quot;&gt;QualityNet Web site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Check the QualityNet Web site regularly for the most recent version of the specifications manual and for the applicable dates of discharge.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="15" OrdBy="790" ID="635" Name="Companion Documents" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following are available:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Hospital compare: a quality tool provided by Medicare. [internet]. Washington (DC): U.S. Department of Health and Human Services; [accessed 2017 Oct 30]. Available from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.medicare.gov/hospitalcompare/search.html?&quot; title=&quot;Medicare Web site&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Medicare Web site&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Yale New Haven Health Services Corporation (YNHHSC), Center for Outcomes Research and Evaluation (CORE). 2017 Medicare hospital quality chartbook. Baltimore (MD): Centers for Medicare &amp;amp; Medicaid Services (CMS); 2017. Available from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cms.gov/Medicare/Quality-Initiatives-Patient-Assessment-Instruments/HospitalQualityInits/OutcomeMeasures.html&quot; title=&quot;Centers for Medicare &amp;amp; Medicaid Services (CMS) Web site&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Centers for Medicare &amp;amp; Medicaid Services (CMS) Web site&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Yale New Haven Health Services Corporation (YNHHSC), Center for Outcomes Research and Evaluation (CORE). 2017 condition-specific readmission measures updates and specifications report: supplemental ICD-10 code lists for use with claims for discharges on or after October 1, 2015. Baltimore (MD): Centers for Medicare &amp;amp; Medicaid Services (CMS); 2017. Available from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.qualitynet.org/dcs/ContentServer?c=Page&amp;amp;pagename=QnetPublic%2FPage%2FQnetTier4&amp;amp;cid=1219069855841&quot; title=&quot;QualityNet Web site&quot;&gt;QualityNet Web site&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="87" OrdBy="800" ID="636" Name="NQMC Status" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This NQMC summary was completed by ECRI Institute on June 23, 2009. The information was verified by the measure developer on December 29, 2009.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This NQMC summary was updated by ECRI Institute on November 8, 2010. The information was verified by the measure developer on December 17, 2010.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This NQMC summary was retrofitted into the new template on May 18, 2011.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This NQMC summary was updated by ECRI Institute on August 23, 2012. The information was verified by the measure developer on October 19, 2012.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This NQMC summary was updated by ECRI Institute on December 4, 2013. The information was verified by the measure developer on January 10, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This NQMC summary was updated by ECRI Institute on December 5, 2014. The information was verified by the measure developer on January 21, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This NQMC summary was updated by ECRI Institute on July 21, 2015. The information was verified by the measure developer on September 23, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This NQMC summary was updated again by ECRI Institute on November 13, 2017. The information was verified by the measure developer on December 12, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="88" OrdBy="810" ID="637" Name="Copyright Statement" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;No copyright restrictions apply.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="641" OrdBy="850" Name="Production">
    <Field FieldID="1" OrdBy="1366" ID="562" Name="Source(s)" Type="citation">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Yale New Haven Health Services Corporation (YNHHSC), Center for Outcomes Research and Evaluation (CORE). 2017 condition-specific measures updates and specifications report: hospital-level 30-day risk-standardized readmission measures. Baltimore (MD): Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS); 2017 Mar. 112 p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="99999" OrdBy="99999" Name="Disclaimer">
    <Field FieldID="99999" OrdBy="99999" ID="99999" Name="NQMC Disclaimer" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;p&gt;The National Quality Measures Clearinghouse™ (NQMC) does not develop, produce, approve, or endorse the measures represented on this site.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;All measures summarized by NQMC and hosted on our site are produced under the auspices of medical specialty societies, relevant professional associations, public and private organizations, other government agencies, health care organizations or plans, individuals, and similar entities.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Measures represented on the NQMC Web site are submitted by measure developers, and are screened solely to determine that they meet the &lt;a href=&quot;/help-and-about/summaries/inclusion-criteria&quot;&gt;NQMC Inclusion Criteria&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;NQMC, AHRQ, and its contractor ECRI Institute make no warranties concerning the content or its reliability and/or validity of the quality measures and related materials represented on this site. Moreover, the views and opinions of developers or authors of measures represented on this site do not necessarily state or reflect those of NQMC, AHRQ, or its contractor, ECRI Institute, and inclusion or hosting of measures in NQMC may not be used for advertising or commercial endorsement purposes.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Readers with questions regarding measure content are directed to contact the measure developer.&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
</Version>