<Version>
  <xmlSource>This XML content was developed by AHRQ's contractor ECRI Institute for the National Quality Measures Clearinghouse (NQMC).</xmlSource>
  <Section SecID="560" OrdBy="10" Name="General">
    <Field FieldID="11" OrdBy="20" ID="561" Name="Title" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_title&quot;&gt;Dehydration admission: percentage of admissions with a principal diagnosis of dehydration per 100,000 population, ages 18 years and older.&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="1" OrdBy="30" ID="562" Name="Source(s)" Type="citation">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;AHRQ QI research version 5.0. Prevention quality indicator 10 technical specifications: dehydration admission rate. Rockville (MD): Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ); 2015 Mar. 2 p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;National Quality Forum measure information: dehydration admission rate (PQI 10). Washington (DC): National Quality Forum (NQF); 2013 May. 36 p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="563" OrdBy="40" Name="Measure Domain">
    <Field FieldID="3025" OrdBy="50" ID="564" Name="Primary Measure Domain" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Related Population Health Measures: Population Use of Services" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3026" OrdBy="60" ID="565" Name="Secondary Measure Domain" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Does not apply to this measure" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="566" OrdBy="70" Name="Brief Abstract">
    <Field FieldID="34" OrdBy="80" ID="567" Name="Description" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This measure is used to assess the percentage of admissions with a principal diagnosis of dehydration per 100,000 population, ages 18 years and older.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="21" OrdBy="90" ID="568" Name="Rationale" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dehydration is a serious acute condition that occurs mostly in elderly patients and patients with other underlying illnesses. Dehydration for the most part can be treated in the outpatient setting. Dehydration is often preventable through attention and support for fluid intake, especially in patients at risk (Mentes, 2012; American Medical Directors Association [AMDA], 2009). Those at risk includes, but is not limited to, individuals with cognitive or psychiatric disorders, increased age, co-morbid illness requiring medications such as diuretics or laxatives, polypharmacy, diabetes, acute gastroenteritis, and living in areas with extreme heat (Wakefield et al., 2008; Jiang et al., 2010; Khalaj et al., 2010). Dehydration is treatable with oral rehydration therapy and/or intravenous (IV) fluids and by addressing the underlying cause (Mentes, 2012; AMDA, 2009). If left untreated, serious complications are possible, including acute kidney injury and mortality (Mentes, 2012; AMDA, 2009). Clinical interventions may prevent serious complications. Examples of such interventions include phone triage and education to promote oral rehydration (Mentes, 2012; Hazratjee et al., 2013) early detection of dehydration (AMDA, 2009), and providing rapid access to treatment for those at highest risk (Konrad et al., 2012). Community interventions include air conditioning for the elderly during intense heat waves (Ostro et al., 2010). &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dehydration can be prevented by increased surveillance of patients at risk in the outpatient setting along with early identification and intervention. Patients with poor access to primary care providers, may seek treatment later, have less access to telephone triage and health education to support home-based management, and may be more likely to seek emergency care.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This measure is an avoidable hospitalization/ambulatory care sensitive condition (ACSC) indicator. ACSC indicators are not measures of hospital quality, but rather measures of outpatient care and other healthcare not related to hospitalizations. The underlying premise for these indicators is that high access to high quality outpatient care may prevent hospital admissions (Billing et al., 1993; van Loenen et al., 2014). In the case of dehydration, such access to high quality care can prevent complications necessitating inpatient admission through encouraging hydration during high risk events, such as gastroenteritis infections, early detection of dehydration, particularly among those that are at high risk for dehydration, and early and effective interventions. These measures are of most interest to comprehensive health care delivery systems, such as some health maintenance organizations (HMOs), accountable care organizations (ACOs), or public health agencies. ACSC indicators correlate with each other and they may be used in conjunction as an overall examination of outpatient care and access to care at a regional level.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3500" OrdBy="100" ID="569" Name="Evidence for Rationale" Type="citation">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;American Medical Directors Association (AMDA). Dehydration and fluid maintenance in the long-term care setting. Columbia (MD): American Medical Directors Association (AMDA); 2009. 29 p.  [60 references]&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Billings J, Zeitel L, Lukomnik J, Carey TS, Blank AE, Newman L. Impact of socioeconomic status on hospital use in New York City. Health Aff (Millwood). 1993 Spring;12(1):162-73. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=8509018&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Hazratjee N, Agito M, Lopez R, Lashner B, Rizk MK. Hospital readmissions in patients with inflammatory bowel disease. Am J Gastroenterol. 2013 Jul;108(7):1024-32. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=23820989&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Jiang HJ, Wier LM, Potter DE, Burgess J. Hospitalizations for potentially preventable conditions among Medicare-Medicaid dual eligibles, 2008. Rockville (MD): Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality; 2010. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Khalaj B, Lloyd G, Sheppeard V, Dear K. The health impacts of heat waves in five regions of New South Wales, Australia: a case-only analysis. Int Arch Occup Environ Health. 2010 Oct;83(7):833-42. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=20464412&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Konrad D, Corrigan ML, Hamilton C, Steiger E, Kirby DF. Identification and early treatment of dehydration in home parenteral nutrition and home intravenous fluid patients prevents hospital admissions. Nutr Clin Pract. 2012 Dec;27(6):802-7. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=23069992&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Mentes JC. Managing oral hydration. In: Boltz M, Capezuti E, Fulmer T, Zwicker D, editor(s). Evidence-based geriatric nursing protocols for best practice. 4th ed. New York (NY): Springer Publishing Company; 2012. p. 419-38.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;National Quality Forum measure information: dehydration admission rate (PQI 10). Washington (DC): National Quality Forum (NQF); 2013 May. 36 p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Ostro B, Rauch S, Green R, Malig B, Basu R. The effects of temperature and use of air conditioning on hospitalizations. Am J Epidemiol. 2010 Nov 1;172(9):1053-61. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=20829270&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;van Loenen T, van den Berg MJ, Westert GP, Faber MJ. Organizational aspects of primary care related to avoidable hospitalization: a systematic review. 2014 Oct;31(5):502-16. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=25216664&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Wakefield BJ, Mentes J, Holman JE, Culp K. Risk factors and outcomes associated with hospital admission for dehydration. Rehabil Nurs. 2008 Nov-Dec;33(6):233-41. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=19024237&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3022" OrdBy="110" ID="570" Name="Primary Health Components" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dehydration; hyperosmolality; hypernatremia; gastroenteritis; acute kidney injury; ambulatory care sensitive condition (ACSC)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="23" OrdBy="120" ID="571" Name="Denominator Description" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Population ages 18 years and older in metropolitan area or county (see the related &quot;Denominator Inclusions/Exclusions&quot; field)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="24" OrdBy="130" ID="572" Name="Numerator Description" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Discharges, for patients ages 18 years and older, with either:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;A principal International Classification of Diseases, Ninth Revision, Clinical Modification (ICD-9-CM) diagnosis code for dehydration; or &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Any secondary ICD-9-CM diagnosis codes for dehydration and a principal ICD-9-CM diagnosis code for hyperosmolality and/or hypernatremia, gastroenteritis, or acute kidney injury &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;See the related &quot;Numerator Inclusions/Exclusions&quot; field.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="573" OrdBy="140" Name="Evidence Supporting the Measure">
    <Field FieldID="3027" OrdBy="150" ID="574" Name="Type of Evidence Supporting the Criterion of Quality for the Measure" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="A clinical practice guideline or other peer-reviewed synthesis of the clinical research evidence" />
      <FieldValue Value="A systematic review of the clinical research literature (e.g., Cochrane Review)" />
      <FieldValue Value="One or more research studies published in a National Library of Medicine (NLM) indexed, peer-reviewed journal" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3501" OrdBy="160" ID="575" Name="Additional Information Supporting Need for the Measure" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hospitalization rates for dehydration (Prevention Quality Indicator [PQI] 10) have been shown to be highest among blacks (1.3 times the rate among non-Hispanic whites in 2003) and lowest amongst Asians (Russo, Andrews, &amp;amp; Coffey, 2006). Use of Healthcare Cost and Utilization Project (HCUP) and State Inpatient Data (SID) data using the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ) PQI composite, demonstrated a decrease in the AHRQ PQI composite rate from 1,635 to 1,395 per 100,000 adults from 2001 to 2009 (Moy et al., 2013). Declines in potentially preventable hospitalization rates were observed across all income quartiles between these same years (years 2001 and 2009). In all years, rates of hospitalizations were higher among residents of neighborhoods in the three lower income quartiles compared with residents of neighborhoods in the highest income quartile (Moy et al., 2013). Income may be associated with access to care. In an earlier like study, when controlling for income there were no differences in race (Moy et al., 2011).&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dehydration is a common fluid and electrolyte disturbance in the adults, especially in the elderly. Dehydration is best treated by prevention. Once dehydration occurs, if not adequately treated, it can lead to hospitalization, renal failure, and or death. A common cause of dehydration in adults is gastroenteritis (Bresee et al., 2012; Hall et al., 2011). The most common cause of all forms of gastroenteritis in adults is the norovirus (Patel et al., 2008; Glass, Parashar, &amp;amp; Estes, 2009). It is estimated that noroviruses cause 23 million episodes of illness, 65,000 hospitalizations, and 300 deaths each year in the United States (Bresee et al, 2012; Hall et al., 2011; Patel et al., 2008; Glass, Parashar, &amp;amp; Estes, 2009; Glass et al., 1996; Parashar et al., 1998; Pang &amp;amp; Vesikari, 1999; Mead et al., 1999; Echeverria et al., 1983), with most fatalities occurring in elderly patients. Although norovirus typically causes disease epidemics (Glass et al., 1996; Pang &amp;amp; Vesikari, 1999; Echeverria et al., 1983), it is also a common cause of endemic diarrhea in community settings (Widdowson et al., 2004). Approximately 5 to 36 percent of outpatient visits for diarrhea are due to norovirus with similar percentages for patients hospitalized for gastroenteritis (Patel et al., 2008; Glass, Parashar, &amp;amp; Estes, 2009). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3502" OrdBy="170" ID="576" Name="Evidence for Additional Information Supporting Need for the Measure" Type="citation">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Bresee JS, Marcus R, Venezia RA, Keene WE, Morse D, Thanassi M, Brunett P, Bulens S, Beard RS, Dauphin LA, Slutsker L, Bopp C, Eberhard M, Hall A, Vinje J, Monroe SS, Glass RI, US Acute Gastroenteritis Etiology Study Team. The etiology of severe acute gastroenteritis among adults visiting emergency departments in the United States. J Infect Dis. 2012 May 1;205(9):1374-81. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=22454468&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Echeverria P, Blacklow NR, Cukor GG, Vibulbandhitkit S, Changchawalit S, Boonthai P. Rotavirus as a cause of severe gastroenteritis in adults. J Clin Microbiol. 1983 Sep;18(3):663-7. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=6313748&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Glass RI, Kilgore PE, Holman RC, Jin S, Smith JC, Woods PA, Clarke MJ, Ho MS, Gentsch JR. The epidemiology of rotavirus diarrhea in the United States: surveillance and estimates of disease burden. J Infect Dis. 1996 Sep;174 Suppl 1:S5-11. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=8752284&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Glass RI, Parashar UD, Estes MK. Norovirus gastroenteritis. N Engl J Med. 2009 Oct 29;361(18):1776-85. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=19864676&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Hall AJ, Rosenthal M, Gregoricus N, Greene SA, Ferguson J, Henao OL, Vinjé J, Lopman BA, Parashar UD, Widdowson MA. Incidence of acute gastroenteritis and role of norovirus, Georgia, USA, 2004-2005. Emerg Infect Dis. 2011 Aug;17(8):1381-8. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=21801613&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Mead PS, Slutsker L, Dietz V, McCaig LF, Bresee JS, Shapiro C, Griffin PM, Tauxe RV. Food-related illness and death in the United States. Emerg Infect Dis. 1999 Sep-Oct;5(5):607-25. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=10511517&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Moy E, Barrett M, Ho K, Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC). Potentially preventable hospitalizations - United States, 2004-2007. Morb Mortal Wkly Rep Surveill Summ. 2011 Jan 14;60 Suppl:80-3. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=21430628&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Moy E, Chang E, Barrett M, Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC). Potentially preventable hospitalizations - United States, 2001-2009. Morb Mortal Wkly Rep Surveill Summ. 2013 Nov 22;62 Suppl 3:139-43. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=24264504&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;National Quality Forum measure information: dehydration admission rate (PQI 10). Washington (DC): National Quality Forum (NQF); 2013 May. 36 p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Pang XL, Vesikari T. Human astrovirus-associated gastroenteritis in children under 2 years of age followed prospectively during a rotavirus vaccine trial. Acta Paediatr. 1999 May;88(5):532-6. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=10426176&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Parashar UD, Holman RC, Clarke MJ, Bresee JS, Glass RI. Hospitalizations associated with rotavirus diarrhea in the United States, 1993 through 1995: surveillance based on the new ICD-9-CM rotavirus-specific diagnostic code. J Infect Dis. 1998 Jan;177(1):13-7. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=9419164&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Patel MM, Widdowson MA, Glass RI, Akazawa K, Vinjé J, Parashar UD. Systematic literature review of role of noroviruses in sporadic gastroenteritis. Emerg Infect Dis. 2008 Aug;14(8):1224-31. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=18680645&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Russo CA, Andrews RM, Coffey RM. Racial and ethnic disparities in potentially preventable hospitalizations, 2003. Statistical Brief #10. 2006 Jul. In: Healthcare Cost and Utilization Project (HCUP) Statistical Briefs [internet]. Rockville (MD): Agency for Health Care Policy and Research; 2006 Feb.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Widdowson MA, Cramer EH, Hadley L, Bresee JS, Beard RS, Bulens SN, Charles M, Chege W, Isakbaeva E, Wright JG, Mintz E, Forney D, Massey J, Glass RI, Monroe SS. Outbreaks of acute gastroenteritis on cruise ships and on land: identification of a predominant circulating strain of norovirus--United States, 2002. J Infect Dis. 2004 Jul 1;190(1):27-36. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=15195240&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3072" OrdBy="180" ID="577" Name="Extent of Measure Testing" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reliability Testing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;The developer evaluated the reliability of risk-adjusted rates using a signal-to-noise ratio metric. The unit of analysis is the county. The noise measure is defined as the within-county variance, which is computed using a formula for the approximation for the variance of adjusted rates that is based on the observed and expected rates (see empirical methods document for details, or, for example Hosmer and Lemeshow [1995]). The signal measure is defined as the variance between counties. Signal-to-noise is computed for each county as [signal / (signal + noise)]. The overall signal-to-noise ratio is the weighted average of the county-specific signal-to-noise ratios where the weights are defined as [1/(signal + noise)^2]). The signal-to-noise ratio across deciles of county population size was evaluated. The overall reliability of the risk adjusted measure is high. More than 80% of counties had signal-to-noise ratios that exceeded a threshold reliability of 0.80. Reliability was lower in counties with smaller populations. The observed signal-to-noise ratios were below 0.80 in counties with populations less than about 2,300 persons. This finding implies that when rates are smoothed, the rates for counties with smaller populations will be shifted more toward the overall (national) population rate.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Overall, the risk-adjusted rate is strongly reliable. Based on a norm of a signal-to-noise ratio of 0.80, 80% of areas exceed the norm. Reliability is less than the norm in areas with population less than approximately 2,300 persons, meaning that the performance score is reliability adjusted closer to the shrinkage target in those areas.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Validity Testing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;The developer examined the complexity of the numerator cases from 2008 to 2012 using three metrics: 1) the percent of discharges with comorbidities can increase the risk of dehydration, 2) the mean number of comorbidities as defined by the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ) Comorbidity Index and 3) the mean age in years. The purpose of this analysis is to determine whether as rates of dehydration hospitalizations have decreased over time, the complexity of the remaining numerator cases has increased over time. Each of the three complexity metrics was calculated for each county in the State Inpatient Databases (SID); the distribution of the metrics across all counties is provided in Table 5 of the original measure documentation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;From 2008 to 2012, there was less than 10% change in the percent of cases with all comorbidities known to have higher risk for dehydration except renal failure which demonstrated a 10% decrease. However, the mean number of comorbidities across counties increased by 11%. The number of numerator observations with a behavioral health comorbidity increased by 22% but the total number remained low (mean of 0.21 in 2008 compared to 0.25 in 2012). Mean age remained unchanged. From this, we conclude that there is only modest evidence of increasing complexity in the numerator population during the period of decrease, suggesting that the decrease does not simply reflect the shifting of non-complex patients from hospital care to other settings.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Refer to the original measure documentation for additional measure testing information.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3007" OrdBy="190" ID="578" Name="Evidence for Extent of Measure Testing" Type="citation">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Hosmer DW, Lemeshow S. Confidence interval estimates of an index of quality performance based on logistic regression models. Stat Med. 1995 Oct 15;14(19):2161-72. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=8552894&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;National Quality Forum measure information: dehydration admission rate (PQI 10). Washington (DC): National Quality Forum (NQF); 2013 May. 36 p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="580" OrdBy="210" Name="State of Use of the Measure">
    <Field FieldID="3029" OrdBy="220" ID="581" Name="State of Use" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Current routine use" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3030" OrdBy="230" ID="582" Name="Current Use" Type="picklist-choice-3">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="583" OrdBy="240" Name="Application of the Measure in its Current Use">
    <Field FieldID="3031" OrdBy="250" ID="584" Name="Measurement Setting" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="Ambulatory/Office-based Care" />
      <FieldValue Value="Hospital Inpatient" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3032" OrdBy="260" ID="585" Name="Professionals Involved in Delivery of Health Services" Type="picklist-choice-3">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3033" OrdBy="270" ID="586" Name="Least Aggregated Level of Services Delivery Addressed" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Regional, County or City" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3505" OrdBy="280" ID="587" Name="Statement of Acceptable Minimum Sample Size" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Does not apply to this measure" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="41" OrdBy="290" ID="588" Name="Target Population Age" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Age greater than or equal to 18 years&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="42" OrdBy="300" ID="589" Name="Target Population Gender" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Either male or female" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="700" OrdBy="304" Name="National Framework for Public Health Quality">
    <Field FieldID="4620" OrdBy="305" ID="701" Name="Public Health Aims for Quality" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Population-centered" />
      <FieldValue Value="Risk Reducing" />
      <FieldValue Value="Vigilant" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="660" OrdBy="310" Name="National Strategy for Quality Improvement in Health Care">
    <Field FieldID="3525" OrdBy="330" ID="662" Name="National Quality Strategy Priority" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="590" OrdBy="340" Name="Institute of Medicine (IOM) National Health Care Quality Report Categories">
    <Field FieldID="3163" OrdBy="350" ID="591" Name="IOM Care Need" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="Not within an IOM Care Need" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3164" OrdBy="360" ID="592" Name="IOM Domain" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="Not within an IOM Domain" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="593" OrdBy="370" Name="Data Collection for the Measure">
    <Field FieldID="3506" OrdBy="380" ID="594" Name="Case Finding Period" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Users may specify a time period; but the time period is generally one year. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: The reference population rates and signal variance parameters assume a one-year time period.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3054" OrdBy="390" ID="595" Name="Denominator Sampling Frame" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Geographically defined" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3057" OrdBy="400" ID="598" Name="Denominator (Index) Event or Characteristic" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="Geographic Location" />
      <FieldValue Value="Patient/Individual (Consumer) Characteristic" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3058" OrdBy="410" ID="599" Name="Denominator Time Window" Type="picklist-choice-3">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="55" OrdBy="420" ID="596" Name="Denominator Inclusions/Exclusions" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Population ages 18 years and older in metropolitan area (MA) or county. Discharges in the numerator are assigned to the denominator based on the MA or county of the patient residence, not the MA or county of the hospital where the discharge occurred.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: The term MA was adopted by the United States (U.S.) Census in 1990 and referred collectively to metropolitan statistical areas (MSAs), consolidated metropolitan statistical areas (CMSAs), and primary metropolitan statistical areas (PMSAs). In addition, &quot;area&quot; could refer to either 1) Federal Information Processing Standard (FIPS) county, 2) modified FIPS county, 3) 1999 Office of Management and Budget (OMB) Metropolitan Statistical Area, or 4) 2003 OMB Metropolitan Statistical Area. Micropolitan Statistical Areas are not used in the Quality Indicator (QI) software.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3507" OrdBy="430" ID="597" Name="Exclusions/Exceptions" Type="picklist-choice-4">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="59" OrdBy="440" ID="600" Name="Numerator Inclusions/Exclusions" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Discharges, for patients ages 18 years and older, with either:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;A principal International Classification of Diseases, Ninth Revision, Clinical Modification (ICD-9-CM) diagnosis code for dehydration; or &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Any secondary ICD-9-CM diagnosis codes for dehydration and a principal ICD-9-CM diagnosis code for hyperosmolality and/or hypernatremia, gastroenteritis, or acute kidney injury &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul class=&quot;Note&quot; style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;By definition, discharges with a principal diagnosis of dehydration, hyperosmolality and/or hypernatremia, gastroenteritis, or acute kidney injury are precluded from an assignment of Major Diagnostic Categories (MDC) 14 by grouper software. Thus, obstetric discharges should not be considered in the Prevention Quality Indicator (PQI) rate, though the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ) Quality Indicators (QI&lt;sup&gt;TM&lt;/sup&gt;) software does not explicitly exclude obstetric cases. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Refer to the original measure documentation for ICD-9-CM codes. See also the &lt;em&gt;Prevention Quality Indicators Appendices&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Exclude cases:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Transfer from a hospital (different facility) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Transfer from a Skilled Nursing Facility (SNF) or Intermediate Care Facility (ICF) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Transfer from another health care facility &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;With any-listed ICD-9-CM diagnosis codes for chronic renal failure &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;With missing gender (SEX=missing), age (AGE=missing), quarter (DQTR=missing), year (YEAR=missing), principal diagnosis (DX1=missing), or county (PSTCO=missing) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3061" OrdBy="450" ID="601" Name="Numerator Search Strategy" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Institutionalization" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3062" OrdBy="460" ID="602" Name="Data Source" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Administrative clinical data" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3065" OrdBy="470" ID="603" Name="Type of Health State" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Proxy for Health State" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3066" OrdBy="480" ID="604" Name="Instruments Used and/or Associated with the Measure" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="605" OrdBy="490" Name="Computation of the Measure">
    <Field FieldID="3508" OrdBy="500" ID="606" Name="Measure Specifies Disaggregation" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Does not apply to this measure" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3067" OrdBy="520" ID="608" Name="Scoring" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Rate/Proportion" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3068" OrdBy="530" ID="609" Name="Interpretation of Score" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Does not apply to this measure (i.e., there is no pre-defined preference for the measure score)" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3090" OrdBy="540" ID="610" Name="Allowance for Patient or Population Factors" Type="picklist-choice-3">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3069" OrdBy="550" ID="611" Name="Description of Allowance for Patient or Population Factors" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The predicted value for each case is computed using a hierarchical model (logistic regression with area random effect) and covariates for gender and age (in 5-year age groups). Because they cannot individually observe the age and gender of each person in a counties population, the developer uses the age and gender distribution of the county to estimate the number of &quot;cases&quot; in each age gender group. The reference population used in the regression is the universe of discharges for states that participate in the Healthcare Cost and Utilization Project (HCUP) State Inpatient Data (SID) for the year 2010 (combined), a database consisting of 46 states and approximately 38 million adult discharges, and the United States (U.S.) Census data by county. The expected rate is computed as the sum of the predicted value for each case divided by the number of cases for the unit of analysis of interest (i.e., area). The risk adjusted rate is computed using indirect standardization as the observed rate divided by the expected rate, multiplied by the reference population rate.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Refer to the original measure documentation for the specific covariates for this measure.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3070" OrdBy="560" ID="612" Name="Standard of Comparison" Type="picklist-choice-3">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="615" OrdBy="590" Name="Identifying Information">
    <Field FieldID="73" OrdBy="600" ID="616" Name="Original Title" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;PQI 10: dehydration admission rate.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="74" OrdBy="610" ID="617" Name="Measure Collection Name" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ) Quality Indicators" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="75" OrdBy="620" ID="618" Name="Measure Set Name" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="Prevention Quality Indicators" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="16" OrdBy="650" ID="621" Name="Submitter" Type="orglist">
      <FieldValue Value="Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality - Federal Government Agency [U.S.]" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="17" OrdBy="660" ID="622" Name="Developer" Type="orglist-p">
      <FieldValue Value="Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality - Federal Government Agency [U.S.]" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="79" OrdBy="670" ID="623" Name="Funding Source(s)" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="80" OrdBy="680" ID="624" Name="Composition of the Group that Developed the Measure" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ) Quality Indicator (QI) measures are developed by a team of clinical and measurement experts in collaboration with AHRQ. The AHRQ QIs are continually updated as a result of new research evidence and validation efforts, user feedback, guidance from the National Quality Forum (NQF), and general advances in the science of quality measurement. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="81" OrdBy="690" ID="625" Name="Financial Disclosures/Other Potential Conflicts of Interest" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;None&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="82" OrdBy="700" ID="626" Name="Endorser" Type="orglist">
      <FieldValue Value="National Quality Forum - None" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3091" OrdBy="705" ID="696" Name="NQF Number" Type="plain-text">
      <FieldValue Value="not defined yet" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3510" OrdBy="710" ID="627" Name="Date of Endorsement" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;2015 Sep 2&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="19" OrdBy="730" ID="629" Name="Adaptation" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This measure was not adapted from another source.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3086" OrdBy="740" ID="630" Name="Date of Most Current Version in NQMC" Type="date">
      <FieldValue Value="2015 Mar" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3511" OrdBy="750" ID="631" Name="Measure Maintenance" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Measure is reviewed and updated on a yearly basis&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="3512" OrdBy="760" ID="632" Name="Date of Next Anticipated Revision" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Spring 2016 (version 6.0, including International Classification of Diseases, Tenth Revision, Clinical Modification [ICD-10-CM] and International Classification of Diseases, Tenth Revision, Procedure Coding System [ICD-10-PCS] compatible software)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="20" OrdBy="770" ID="633" Name="Measure Status" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the current release of the measure.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This measure updates previous versions: &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;AHRQ QI. Prevention quality indicators #10: technical specifications. Dehydration admission rate [version 4.4]. Rockville (MD): Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ); 2012 Mar. 2 p. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;AHRQ quality indicators. Prevention quality indicators: technical specifications [version 4.4]. Appendices. Rockville (MD): Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ); 2012 Mar. 6 p. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="14" OrdBy="780" ID="634" Name="Measure Availability" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Source available from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.qualityindicators.ahrq.gov/Downloads/Modules/PQI/V50/TechSpecs/PQI_10_Dehydration_Admission_Rate.pdf&quot; title=&quot;AHRQ QI Web site&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ) Quality Indicators (QI) Web site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For more information, contact the AHRQ QI Support Team at E-mail: &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:QIsupport@ahrq.hhs.gov&quot;&gt;QIsupport@ahrq.hhs.gov&lt;/a&gt;; Phone: 301-427-1949.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="15" OrdBy="790" ID="635" Name="Companion Documents" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following are available:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;AHRQ quality indicators. Prevention quality indicators (PQI) parameter estimates [version 5.0]. Rockville (MD): Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ); 2015 Mar. 21 p. This document is available from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.qualityindicators.ahrq.gov/Downloads/Modules/PQI/V50/Parameter_Estimates_PQI_50.pdf&quot; title=&quot;AHRQ QI Web site&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;AHRQ Quality Indicators Web site&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;AHRQ quality indicators. Prevention quality indicators benchmark data tables [version 5.0]. Rockville (MD): Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ); 2015 Mar. 9 p. This document is available from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.qualityindicators.ahrq.gov/Downloads/Modules/PQI/V50/Version_50_Benchmark_Tables_PQI.pdf&quot; title=&quot;AHRQ QI Web site&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;AHRQ Quality Indicators Web site&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;AHRQ quality indicators. Prevention quality indicators (PQI) composite measure workgroup. Final report. Rockville (MD): Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ); 2006 Apr 7. various p. This document is available from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.qualityindicators.ahrq.gov/Downloads/Modules/PQI/PQI_Composite_Development.pdf&quot; title=&quot;AHRQ QI Web site&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;AHRQ Quality Indicators Web site&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;HCUPnet: a tool for identifying, tracking, and analyzing national hospital statistics. [Web site]. Rockville (MD): Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ); [accessed 2015 Sep 10]. HCUPnet is available from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://hcupnet.ahrq.gov/&quot; title=&quot;AHRQ Web site&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;AHRQ Web site&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="87" OrdBy="800" ID="636" Name="NQMC Status" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This NQMC summary was completed by ECRI on December 19, 2002. The information was verified by the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality on January 9, 2003. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This NQMC summary was updated by ECRI Institute on April 6, 2004, February 18, 2005, February 27, 2006, June 15, 2007, November 26, 2008 and May 22, 2010. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This NQMC summary was reviewed and edited by ECRI Institute on May 16, 2011. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This NQMC summary was retrofitted into the new template on July 13, 2011. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This NQMC summary was updated by ECRI Institute on February 22, 2013 and again on December 1, 2015. The information was verified by the measure developer on January 19, 2016. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="88" OrdBy="810" ID="637" Name="Copyright Statement" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;No copyright restrictions apply.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="641" OrdBy="850" Name="Production">
    <Field FieldID="1" OrdBy="1366" ID="562" Name="Source(s)" Type="citation">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;AHRQ QI research version 5.0. Prevention quality indicator 10 technical specifications: dehydration admission rate. Rockville (MD): Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ); 2015 Mar. 2 p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;National Quality Forum measure information: dehydration admission rate (PQI 10). Washington (DC): National Quality Forum (NQF); 2013 May. 36 p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="99999" OrdBy="99999" Name="Disclaimer">
    <Field FieldID="99999" OrdBy="99999" ID="99999" Name="NQMC Disclaimer" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;p&gt;The National Quality Measures Clearinghouse™ (NQMC) does not develop, produce, approve, or endorse the measures represented on this site.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;All measures summarized by NQMC and hosted on our site are produced under the auspices of medical specialty societies, relevant professional associations, public and private organizations, other government agencies, health care organizations or plans, individuals, and similar entities.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Measures represented on the NQMC Web site are submitted by measure developers, and are screened solely to determine that they meet the &lt;a href=&quot;/help-and-about/summaries/inclusion-criteria&quot;&gt;NQMC Inclusion Criteria&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;NQMC, AHRQ, and its contractor ECRI Institute make no warranties concerning the content or its reliability and/or validity of the quality measures and related materials represented on this site. Moreover, the views and opinions of developers or authors of measures represented on this site do not necessarily state or reflect those of NQMC, AHRQ, or its contractor, ECRI Institute, and inclusion or hosting of measures in NQMC may not be used for advertising or commercial endorsement purposes.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Readers with questions regarding measure content are directed to contact the measure developer.&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
</Version>